<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Creative Commons Planet: Us, jurisdictions, and people</title>
	<link>http://planet.creativecommons.org/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Creative Commons Planet: Us, jurisdictions, and people - http://planet.creativecommons.org/</description>

<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Buy GiftTRAP California Edition, Donate to CC</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7886</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7886</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The good folks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gifttrap.com/&quot;&gt;GiftTRAP&lt;/a&gt; (who we recentlly featured &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7705&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) are running a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gifttrap.com/creative_commons_fund_raiser&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Fundraiser Holiday Promotion&lt;/a&gt;, where a purchase of “GiftTRAP California Edition” will result in $15 donated to CC, and a case of “GiftTRAP California Edition” (8 copies) will mean $100 donated.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A huge thanks is due to GiftTRAP for this awesome idea, which comes right in time for our &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;2007 fundraising campaign&lt;/a&gt;. We are on our way to reaching our goal, and every bit helps. Thanks GiftTRAP!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/with-scorers-cal.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 16:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Lawrence Lessig: 9 days till we're 5</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3468</guid>
	<link>http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/9_days_till_were_5.html</link>
	<description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2046561465_d5b03292de_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2046561465_d5b03292de_b.jpg&quot; height=&quot;341&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
By Tama Lever at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/tamaleaver/2046561465/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot; rel=&quot;license&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/80x15.png&quot; alt=&quot;Creative Commons License&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Tama's is the latest winning Flickr photo in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org/contest&quot;&gt;CC Flickr contest&lt;/a&gt;. It nicely captures my obsessive focus these next 9 days. 

We turn 5 on the 15th. We've got a long way to got to meet our target for the year. Ordinarily we'd have till the end  of the year. But this year, I want to meet the target by December 15. We've all been working insanely hard to pull this (and a list of amazing announcements) together. I want to be able to let the staff go back to life on December 16. And I want to have sometime to explain to my 4 year old just how reindeer fly. 

So please, if you haven't, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; us now. If you have, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;support&lt;/a&gt; us again. If you've got any really good dirt on someone, blackmail them now. And, as a special (if corrupt) bonus: If you donate $100 or more, I'll send a free DVD of my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/10/corruption_lecture_alpha_versi_1.html&quot;&gt;corruption lecture&lt;/a&gt;. Just send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:corrupt_lessig@pobox.com&quot;&gt;corrupt_lessig@pobox.com&lt;/a&gt; after you make your donation with an address, and off it will go.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 15:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Lawrence Lessig: the iCommons Auction</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3467</guid>
	<link>http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/the_icommons_auction_1.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://icommons.org/auction&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/auction_button_final.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;auction_button_final.jpg&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://iCommons.org&quot;&gt;iCommons&lt;/a&gt; is the group CC incubated and then have begun to spin out this year. Its aim is to build a common (but not CC owned) platform for digital freedom related issues (A2K, free software, open source software, free culture, free knowledge, activism, etc.). Its main annual event is a conference. The first year was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icommons.org/isummit05/&quot;&gt;Boston&lt;/a&gt;. The second, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icommons.org/isummit06/&quot;&gt;Brazil&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icommons.org/isummit07/&quot;&gt;Croatia&lt;/a&gt;. Next year &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icommons.org/isummit08/&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;.

iCommons is having an &lt;a href=&quot;http://icommons.org/auction&quot;&gt;auction&lt;/a&gt; to build support (and $$!, or actually €) for iCommons. Among the items auctioned is the (&lt;a href=&quot;http://cgi.ebay.com/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ViewItem&amp;amp;item=360003000531&quot;&gt;embarrassingly worn) black jacket I have worn&lt;/a&gt; while traveling about 500,000 miles over the last few years. Weird (but clean). Bid away!</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2007 14:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science Commons: What’s “open source knowledge management”?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://sciencecommons.org/weblog/archives/2007/12/05/whats-open-source-knowledge-management/</guid>
	<link>http://sciencecommons.org/weblog/archives/2007/12/05/whats-open-source-knowledge-management/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges we face at Science Commons is explaining what we do — and, much more important, why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, the core problem is translation; what makes sense to a computer scientist is gibberish to a life scientist, and vice versa. We want to connect with as many people as possible, both within the scientific community and beyond. To that end, we’ve decided to publish a series of posts to bring more clarity to the terms and phrases we use. To make sure these posts are truly useful, we’ll be asking for your feedback. Got questions? Criticism? A better definition of a term than the one we’re proposing? We hope you’ll &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dwentworth@creativecommons.org&quot; id=&quot;jk99&quot; title=&quot;Donna Wentworth @ SC&quot;&gt;send us an email&lt;/a&gt; or add your comments to the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up is a term we’ve been using to describe our &lt;a href=&quot;http://sciencecommons.org/projects/data/&quot; id=&quot;hkvx&quot; title=&quot;Neurocommons project&quot;&gt;Neurocommons project&lt;/a&gt;: “open source knowledge management.” This is a hybrid term that splices together concepts from the worlds of business and software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part, “open source,” is derived from “open source software.” Open source software is software that’s published with licensing to allow anyone to look under the hood at the underlying “source” code to see how it works. Any developer can copy the code and modify it — either to improve the original software, or build on it to create something brand new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Knowledge management,” or KM, is a term often used by businesses to describe the systems they have for organizing, accessing and using information — everything from the data in personnel files to the number of products on store shelves. One reason that it’s “knowledge” management rather than “information” management is that the word knowledge connotes &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; of information, not just its availability. Having the ability to use information is what makes it valuable. One classic example is Wal-Mart, which used real-time data about its inventory to realize tremendous, game-changing efficiency gains and cost-savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how is our Neurocommons project an “open source knowledge management” project? In a nutshell, Science Commons is developing all of the key elements for a free, web-enabled KM system for biological research that anyone can use, and anyone can build on. Right now, scientists don’t know “what’s on the shelf” — either in terms of research data or materials. They don’t have an easy way to sort through or make sense of the terabytes of data being produced in laboratories around the world. They certainly don’t have “one-click” access to materials like cell lines. We want to change that. Our goal isn’t (simply) to increase efficiency in the research cycle and magnify the impact of investments in research. Ultimately, we hope to speed the pace of discovery — unlocking the value of research so more people can benefit from the work scientists are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about the Neurocommons project, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://sciencecommons.org/projects/data/&quot; id=&quot;p_3b&quot; title=&quot;project page&quot;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dwentworth@creativecommons.org&quot; id=&quot;iba2&quot; title=&quot;Donna Wentworth @ SC&quot;&gt;send us an email&lt;/a&gt;. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 18:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Pix-Yu Great Example of Open Photo Sharing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7883</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7883</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Kudos to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pix-yu.com/&quot; title=&quot;Pix-Yu&quot;&gt;Pix-Yu&lt;/a&gt; for creating an engaging social networking site where users can easily share photo events. Pix-Yu supports Creative Commons licensing and is promoted as an “online virtual space in which users can share life experiences, events, journeys, holidays and meetings etc, by uploading an unlimited number of pictures.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; has been one of the most visible supporters of Creative Commons over the past few years, now displaying over &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/creativecommons/&quot; title=&quot;Flickr CC&quot;&gt;54 million CC-licensed photos&lt;/a&gt;. We’re always working to explore CC integration with both new and existing sites and services. While Flickr has just passed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wired.com/monkeybites/2007/11/flickr-two-bill.html&quot; title=&quot;Flickr passes 2 billion photos&quot;&gt;2 billion photo mark&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook claims to hold twice as many. It’d be fantastic to see important photo-sharing sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://picasa.google.com/&quot; title=&quot;Picasa&quot;&gt;Picasa&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://photobucket.com/&quot; title=&quot;Photobucket&quot;&gt;Photobucket&lt;/a&gt;, and others incorporate CC licensing. Together we can work towards a critical mass of open photography. Pix-Yu is a great example of a start-up networking site that is supporting user creativity by enabling open content sharing from the get-go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/contact/&quot; title=&quot;Contact Page&quot;&gt;Holler at us&lt;/a&gt; if you have a project we can help you integrate with CC licensing. Check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Web_Integration&quot; title=&quot;CC Web Integration&quot;&gt;web integration&lt;/a&gt; wiki page for a framework on setting up your media site with CC features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 18:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC China Mainland: Invitation to the Global CC Birthday Party and CC Salon in Beijing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://cn.creativecommons.org/index.php/2007/12/05/invitation-to-the-global-cc-birthday-party-and-cc-salon-in-beijing/</guid>
	<link>http://cn.creativecommons.org/index.php/2007/12/05/invitation-to-the-global-cc-birthday-party-and-cc-salon-in-beijing/</link>
		<category>cn</category>
	<description>知识共享（ＣＣ）沙龙暨环球生日会（北京）
活动公告
一、 活动主题：
知识共享组织（Creative Commons，简称ＣＣ）倡导对知识创造成果进行合法地分享与演绎，在传统的“所有权利保留”模式之外，提出了“部分权利保留”的灵活的著作权行使模式。知识共享组织通过向公众免费提供一系列独特的著作权许可协议（知识共享许可协议，简称CC协议），为知识创造成果提供一种合理灵活的保护与使用的方法。
知识共享（ＣＣ）主题沙龙作为一个交流平台，采取自由、开放的形式，本次沙龙活动主办方将邀请多位嘉宾及CC协议用户就CC协议等主题做相关的介绍或主题发言，同时大家可对主题发言进行评论、提问，共同探讨CC协议的发展与使用。
其后将举行知识共享（CC）环球生日会北京庆祝会，所有来宾将在愉快、轻松的气氛中共同庆祝CC协议发布5周年。
二、 活动主办方：
知识共享中国大陆项目
北京谋智网络
协办单位: 侃谱艺术俱乐部
三、日程安排：
1、知识共享沙龙　演讲嘉宾（以姓名拼音字母为序） 
曹   斐     艺术家
宫   力     谋智网络技术有限公司 董事长兼首席执行官
欧   宁     艺术家、策展人
王逢旦     中国开放教育协会 主席
许   晖     HIPIHI 虚拟世界 创始人兼首席执行官
赵   牧     SOHU网 博客频道负责人
2、CC生日会仪式
3、展示放映采用CC协议发布的艺术作品
4、自由交流
四、活动时间：2007年12月15日（周六）下午13：30－18：00
五、活动地点：侃谱艺术俱乐部  电话：65524945      朝阳区工体西路8号楼6层（工体南门）
六、媒体支持：SOHU搜狐网、新摄影网、今日艺术网 图说天下网 在艺术网
如您有意参加本次沙龙活动，请详细填写如下信息，于12月12日17：00前向zhuziphoto#yahoo.com.cn(#改成@)邮箱回传回执。以便我们为您预留座位！
知识共享（CC）沙龙暨环球生日会回执内容
本人有意参加本次沙龙活动，请预留座位！
姓名：     
单位：    
职务：
电话：    
电子邮件：
参加人数：
   
联系方式 
E-mail:zhuziphoto#yahoo.com.cn(#改成@)
联系人：朱捍东　

知识共享中国大陆项目  北京谋智网络</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 10:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Australia: CCau Birthday BBQ Bash</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://creativecommons.org.au/143 at http://creativecommons.org.au</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org.au/node/143</link>
		<category>au</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/bbqbash&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/images/bbqbash.jpg&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; hspace=&quot;10&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;photo: by Free-ers, under CC BY 2.0&lt;br /&gt;
http://www.flickr.com/photos/46357488@N00/380933738/&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 06:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: mayer + bettle: the sequel?!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-3029810488315553963</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/12/mayer-bettle-sequel.html</link>
	<description>There's word on the street is that the loveable CC duo Mayer and Bettle featured in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/animation_train&quot;&gt;CCau animation film&lt;/a&gt; are planning to hit the set on a new sequel to the much loved, much distributed film. Almost three years on and the pair feel it is time to update their message. The duo aren't saying much at this early stage, but Mayer did say, &quot;It's more of what you loved, but this time we're talking creator's rights.&quot;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&quot;Much has changed since we shot the first film,&quot; Mayer said, &quot;Which is why Bettle and I are getting back in front of the Camera.&quot; Tightening of the licences, expanded metadata, a dedicated &lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;education division&lt;/a&gt; and exploration into &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/CCPlus&quot;&gt;complimentary licensing options&lt;/a&gt; are just some of the key developments. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Bettle, who is still riding high on the success of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot; class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;The Best Song in the World&lt;/span&gt;, has been spending much of her time exploring different ways of using CC. &quot;With this new animation we want to help you, the creators out there, to understand the great potential of CC,&quot; she told CCau staff this morning. &quot;Give some, take some. That's what it's all about,&quot; she said, &quot;If you're taking from the commons, and you want to put it back, this new film will show you how.&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The first animation film, which has been republished 1000s of times, translated and subtitled and &lt;a href=&quot;http://revver.com/&quot;&gt;Revver&lt;/a&gt;ised to help fundraise for CC internationally, was a huge success.  Mayer and Bettle are enthusiastically joined by the original film team, CCau staffer &lt;a href=&quot;http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Elliott Bledsoe&lt;/a&gt;, animator &lt;a href=&quot;http://iusebiro.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Pete Foley&lt;/a&gt;, musician Chris Perren and actors Dash Kruck and Mem Rynne in the production of the sequel.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 05:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: cc birthday party by ccau</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-3822023774284084223</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/cc-birthday-party-by-ccau.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/cc5logo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/cc5logo.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand; width: 400px;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CC is turning 5 and they are encouraging people to host parties. America is having a &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7855&quot;&gt;party&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco that will include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;...announcements by Joi Ito and Lawrence Lessig, a live acoustic performance by Gilberto Gil, video remixing by Phi Phenomenon, and music provided by DJ Spooky.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you're over there, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/images/8/8c/Flier-general-final.pdf&quot;&gt;get along&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here in Australia, we're hosting a party for CC at my house!! We're leveraging our time zone advantage to kick off the 5th birthday celebrations for Creative Commons. And how? We're having a true blue Aussie breakfast BBQ (and some champagne too!) on Saturday December 15. So unless the newbies over at CC New Zealand host a midnight party we're the first!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Come along any time after 10am. We'll provide some BBQ treats, but bring some of your own. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jessica@creativecommons.org.au&quot;&gt;Jessica Coates&lt;/a&gt; for more details if you wanna come!&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 04:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Joi Ito: T.t.t.t.twitter...</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4728</guid>
	<link>http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/05/tttttwitter.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/twitterblock.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denied in Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to fire up my VPN…&lt;/p&gt;

		

		&lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/05/tttttwitter.html#comments&quot; title=&quot;Comment&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/05/tttttwitter.html#trackbacks&quot; title=&quot;Trackback&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 03:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Poland: CC Polska na konferencji o Open Access</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.pl/blog/2007/12/cc-polska-na-konferencji-o-open-access/</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.pl/blog/2007/12/cc-polska-na-konferencji-o-open-access/</link>
		<category>pl</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;W dniach 7-8 grudnia odbędzie się w Toruniu konferencja “Open Access. Internet w bibliotekach”, organizowana przez Stowarzyszenie Bibliotekarzy Polskich i projekt EBIB. W jej ramach będziemy opowiadać o wolnych licencjach oraz poprowadzimy warsztaty praktyczne dla bibliotekarzy. Więcej informacji na &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ebib.info/content/view/587/126/&quot;&gt;stronie EBIB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 23:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Free Speech TV: It’s Our Web</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7881</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7881</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freespeech.org/&quot;&gt;Free Speech TV&lt;/a&gt; just uploaded their new video, &lt;a href=&quot;http://freespeech.org/ourweb/&quot;&gt;“It’s Our Web”&lt;/a&gt;, choosing to release it under a CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/us/&quot;&gt;BY-NC-SA license&lt;/a&gt;. The video focuses on current changes happening online, contrasting the increased focus on opening up content with the threats that face this movement. From FSTV:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a truly pivotal time for the Internet, the most powerful and interactive medium humans have ever seen.   New commercial incursions by big online media enterprises including the widely distained “Facebook Beacon”, make explicit what new media giants have been doing quietly for some time; searching for new and evermore effective ways to sell our attention, our clicks and our private information to advertisers and marketers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 21:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: Plug-in CC per OpenOffice.org</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/601</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/601</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Come si può leggere nel &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/press-releases/entry/7820&quot;&gt;comunicato stampa ufficiale&lt;/a&gt;, Creative Commons ha creato un plug-in per Openoffice.org che permette di &quot;marcare&quot; i relativi documenti con le licenze CC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 10:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: “Teaching Music With Reason” Released Under CC-License</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7880</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7880</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propellerheads.se/&quot;&gt;Propellerhead Software&lt;/a&gt;, makers of electronic-music production tool Reason, have recently re-released their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.propellerheads.se/remote.cfm?sID=dynamo&amp;amp;nav=yes&amp;amp;menu=/products/education/index.cfm?fuseaction=display_menu&amp;amp;page=/products/education/index.cfm?fuseaction=get_article&amp;amp;article=tmwr_download&quot;&gt;“Teaching Music With Reason”&lt;/a&gt; lesson set under a CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/se/deed.en_US&quot;&gt;BY-NC license&lt;/a&gt;. Originally intended for educators teaching courses on electronic music at the high school and college level, “Teaching” was made for Reason 2.5 and provided, among other things, lessons, source material, and student booklets. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Reason is now at version 4, the book does have some inconsistencies with the program’s current UI. While this traditionally would be a hindrance, by re-releasing “Teaching” under a CC license, Propellherhead have created a document that can grow and change with the help of the Reason community, adding new value to an old tool. Motivated users of the program can augment the lesson plans, updating and adding information as they see fit. Similarly, if users simply wish to get a hold on some basic information for free, they can use the material and “massage” it to make sense for Reason 4.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 20:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Copyright Crash Course</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7878</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7878</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/picture-1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Copyright Crash Course&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/picture-1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Copyright Crash Course&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/picture-1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Copyright Crash Course&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/picture-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Copyright Crash Course&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The University of Texas maintains a useful &lt;a href=&quot;http://copyright.lib.utexas.edu/&quot;&gt;“Copyright Crash Course”&lt;/a&gt; through its library website. It’s a great resource, providing a clearinghouse of information on many topics such as ownership and management of copyrights, open access materials, fair use and orphan works, and copyright issues within libraries and universities. Of course, the site lays out the ways Creative Commons can help us build on others’ creative expression (and is itself licensed &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt;). A note from the authors on the ease of CC:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I only had to copy and paste a snippet of code I got from the Creative Commons Website into this document to make the license appear. The snippet does three things: it creates this cool little image, it links the reader directly to the Creative Commons site for more details about my license and it makes this document searchable by the Creative Commons search engines so that people who are looking for materials they can be sure they are free to use can easily find it. Very powerful stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 20:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: CC swag photo contest winner #3</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7877</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7877</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/glutnix/2079709803/&quot; title=&quot;Carpeted Commons by Glutnix, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2281/2079709803_445f2a3ea3_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carpeted Commons&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third winner of the 2007 CC Swag photo contest is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/people/glutnix/&quot;&gt;Glutnix&lt;/a&gt;! Congratulations!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are only 2 weeks left to participate. If you need new CC swag - check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org/store&quot;&gt;online store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org/donate&quot;&gt;donate&lt;/a&gt; to our 2007 annual fundraising campaign. Thanks to everyone who has participated so far!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 18:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: Wikipedia e Creative Commons ancora più vicini</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/599</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/599</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Secondo quanto annunciato da &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html&quot;&gt;varie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jamendo.com/index.php/2007/12/01/breaking-news-wikipedia-switches-to-creative-commons/&quot;&gt;fonti&lt;/a&gt;, la Wikimedia Foundation ha &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativecommons.it/href&quot;&gt;proposto&lt;/a&gt; una modifica alla &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl.html&quot;&gt;GNU Free Documentation License&lt;/a&gt; in modo che le opere sotto GFDL possano essere rilicenziati sotto CC Attribution-ShareAlike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 18:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Carolina Botero: Wikipedia: GFDL y CCBYSA ¡Compatibles!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=299</guid>
	<link>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=299</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://barrapunto.com/article.pl?sid=07/12/02/028227&amp;amp;from=rss&quot;&gt;Barrapunto&lt;/a&gt; trae el recuento de lo que Lessig anuncia en &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html&quot;&gt;su blog&lt;/a&gt; y que desde la &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt;Fundación Wikimedia explican&lt;/a&gt;: FSF ha acordado hacer los ajustes necesarios a la GFDL que permita hacer compatible esta licencia con la de Creative Commons AtribuciónCompartiIgual. Cuando esto se verifique será la comunidad de wikipedia la que deberá pronunciarse para que Wikipedia “&lt;strong&gt;relicencie&lt;/strong&gt;” con CCBYSA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El tema ha tenido un importante eco en la &lt;a href=&quot;http://planet.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;blogosfera de gente relacionada con Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, pero seguramente lo más interesante va a ser la discusión sobre el proceso de migración que se inicie en la comunidad de Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primer gran paso el que se hace en compatibilidad y un gran cambio si wikipedia relicencia, no? (gracias &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.eljeffto.com/&quot;&gt;Jeffrey&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 10:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Joi Ito: Wikipedia and Creative Commons move closer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4725</guid>
	<link>http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/wikipedia_and_creative_commons_move_closer.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;personquote&quot;&gt;Lessig Blog&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html&quot;&gt;Some important news from Wikipedia to understand clearly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you’ll see in this video, there has been important progress in making Wikipedia compatible with the world of &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; licensed work. But we should be very precise about this extremely good news: As Jimmy announces, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Foundation&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Foundation Board&lt;/a&gt; has agreed with a proposal made by the Free Software Foundation that will permit Wikipedia (and other such wikis) to relicense under a &lt;a href=&quot;http://http//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is very different from saying that Wikipedia has relicensed under a CC license. The decision whether to take advantage of this freedom granted by the FSF when the FSF grants it will be a decision the Wikipedia community will have to make. We are very hopeful that the community will ratify this move to compatible freedoms. And if they do, we are looking forward to an extraordinary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Wikimedia Foundation resolution &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My endless thanks to everyone who has helped make this possible, from Richard Stallman and the FSF board, to the important leaders within the Wikipedia community who say yet another legal obstacle to freedom that they could remove. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Thanks to everyone who has been working on it. This is a very significant step in improving interoperability and I think this is a great example of how we can all work together to benefit the free culture community. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right; font-size: 10px;&quot;&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.technorati.com/tag/Wikipedia&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

		

		&lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/wikipedia_and_creative_commons_move_closer.html#comments&quot; title=&quot;Comment&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/wikipedia_and_creative_commons_move_closer.html#trackbacks&quot; title=&quot;Trackback&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 09:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Joi Ito: Lawsuit against CC dismissed</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4724</guid>
	<link>http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/lawsuit_against_cc_dismissed.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;personquote&quot;&gt;Lessig Blog&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/from_the_whyagcfromcravathisgr.html&quot;&gt;From the Why-a-GC-from-Cravath-is-great Department: The lawsuit is over&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received this happy missive in the mail yesterday: The plaintiffs in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html&quot;&gt;lawsuit about Virgin using a CC-licensed photo&lt;/a&gt; have dismissed CC from the case. This is not a settlement. It is not the product of negotiation. It is the recognition by plaintiffs counsel that the laws of Texas and the United States give the plaintiffs no cause to sue Creative Commons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;This is great news. Congratulations to the whole team who worked on this including a number of volunteers from the community.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

		

		&lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/lawsuit_against_cc_dismissed.html#comments&quot; title=&quot;Comment&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/lawsuit_against_cc_dismissed.html#trackbacks&quot; title=&quot;Trackback&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 09:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mike Linksvayer: Steps toward better software and content</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/12/01/copyleft-pd/</guid>
	<link>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/12/01/copyleft-pd/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Wikimedia Foundation board has passed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt;resolution&lt;/a&gt; that is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7876&quot;&gt;step toward Wikipedia migrating to the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&lt;/a&gt;. I have an uninteresting interest in this due to working at Creative Commons (I do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; represent them on this blog), but as someone who wants to see free knowledge “win” and achieve &lt;a href=&quot;http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2006/12/10/peer-production-revolution/&quot;&gt;revolutionary&lt;/a&gt; impact, I declare this an important step forward. The current fragmentation of the universe of free content along the lines of legally incompatible but similar in spirit &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyleft&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;copyleft&lt;/a&gt; licenses delays and endangers the point at which that universe reaches critical mass — when any given project decides to use a copyleft license merely because then being able to include content from the free copyleft universe makes that decision make sense. This has worked fairly well in the software world with the GPL as &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; copyleft license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyleft was and is a great hack, and useful in many cases. But practically it is a major barrier to collaboration in some contexts and politically it is still based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/09/10/copyright-intervention/&quot;&gt;censorship&lt;/a&gt;. So I’m always extremely pleased by any expansion of the public domain. There could hardly be a more welcome expansion than &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_J._Bernstein&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Daniel J. Bernstein&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://lwn.net/Articles/260481/&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; of his code (most notably &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qmail&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;qmail&lt;/a&gt;) into the public domain. Most of the practical benefit (including his code in free software distributions) could have been achieved by released under any free software license, including the GPL. But politically, check out this &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-3147768955127254412&amp;amp;q=%22Bernstein+releases+code+to+public+domain%22&amp;amp;total=1&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;num=10&amp;amp;so=0&amp;amp;type=search&amp;amp;plindex=0&quot;&gt;two minute video&lt;/a&gt; of Bernstein pointing out some of the problems of copyright and announcing that his code is in the public domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernstein (usually referred to as ‘djb’) also recently doubled the reward for finding a security hole in qmail to US$1,000. I highly recommend his &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cr.yp.to/qmail/qmailsec-20071101.pdf&quot;&gt;Some thoughts on security after ten years of qmail 1.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, also available as something approximating &lt;a href=&quot;http://cr.yp.to/talks/2007.11.02/slides.pdf&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; (also see an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eros-os.org/pipermail/cap-talk/2007-November/thread.html#9202&quot;&gt;discussion of the paper on cap-talk&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 00:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Taiwan: 12/3 主機停機公告</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://creativecommons.org.tw/259 at http://creativecommons.org.tw</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org.tw/node/259</link>
		<category>tw</category>
	<description>由於主機位置搬遷，明天 (12/3 週一) 上午 9:30 起「創用 CC」的網站將停止服務六小時，特此公告。</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 23:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Netherlands: Creative Commons licenties voor Wikipedia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://creativecommons.nl/2007/12/02/creative-commons-licenties-op-wikipedia/</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.nl/2007/12/01/creative-commons-licenties-voor-wikipedia/</link>
		<category>nl</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;het board van de &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Foundation&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Foundation&lt;/a&gt; heeft gisteren een &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt; resolutie aangenomen&lt;/a&gt; die de weg vrijmaakt voor de migratie van &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikipedia.org/&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; (en de &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Our_projects&quot;&gt;andere projecten&lt;/a&gt; van de wikimedia foundation) van de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html&quot;&gt;GNU Free Documentation Licentie&lt;/a&gt; naar de &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/nl/deed.nl&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Naamsvermelding GelijkDelen Licentie&lt;/a&gt;. Dit is gisteren in San Francisco door Jimmy Wales, de oprichter van Wikipedia bekend gemaakt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&amp;lt; param name=&quot;wmode&quot; value=&quot;transparent&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In eerste instantie wordt door dit besluit van de wikimedia foundation de mogelijkheid geschept wikipedia (het grootste (en meeste succesvolle) open content project ter wereld) onder de CC-BY-SA licentie te herlicensieren. Voorafgaand aan een dergelijke migrate is echter nog een consultatie van de Wikipedia Community gepland. Het zal dus nog een tijd kunnen duren voordat wikipedia ook daadwerkelijk onder een Creative Commons licentie beschikbaar is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voor meer informatie zie ook &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html&quot;&gt;deze blog-post&lt;/a&gt; van Creative Commons oprichter Lawrence Lessig.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 21:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Progress on license interoperability with Wikipedia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7876</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7876</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;As announced last night by Jimmy Wales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.jamendo.com/index.php/2007/12/01/breaking-news-wikipedia-switches-to-creative-commons/&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;), the Wikimedia Foundation board has passed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt;resolution on licensing&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Foundation requests that the GNU Free Documentation License be modified in the fashion proposed by the FSF to allow migration by mass collaborative projects to the Creative Commons CC-BY-SA license;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon the announcement of that relicensing, the Foundation will initiate a process of community discussion and voting before making a final decision on relicensing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt;whole resolution&lt;/a&gt; and CC CEO Lawrence Lessig’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html&quot;&gt;explanation&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an extremely important step toward a world in which the free content world is not fractured by license incompatibility and thus is &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect&quot;&gt;stronger&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7840&quot;&gt;Previous post&lt;/a&gt; on license interoperability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 19:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Lawrence Lessig: Some important news from Wikipedia to understand clearly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3466</guid>
	<link>http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html</link>
	<description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

As you'll  see in this video, there has been important progress in making Wikipedia compatible with the world of &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; licensed work. But we should be very precise about this extremely good news: As Jimmy announces, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Foundation&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Foundation Board&lt;/a&gt; has agreed with a proposal made by the Free Software Foundation that will permit Wikipedia (and other such wikis) to relicense under a &lt;a href=&quot;http://http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license&lt;/a&gt;. 

That is very different from saying that Wikipedia has relicensed under a CC license. The decision whether to take advantage of this freedom granted by the FSF when the FSF grants it will be a decision the Wikipedia community will have to make. We are very hopeful that the community will ratify this move to compatible freedoms. And if they do, we are looking forward to an extraordinary celebration.

Read the Wikimedia Foundation resolution &lt;a href=&quot;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. 

My endless thanks to everyone who has helped make this possible, from Richard Stallman and the FSF board, to the important leaders within the Wikipedia community who say yet another legal obstacle to freedom that they could remove.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 18:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: La denuncia contro Creative Commons viene ritirata</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/598</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/598</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Come &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7680&quot;&gt;già riportato&lt;/a&gt;,  Creative Commons era stata denunciata in Texas per non aver adeguatamente &quot;informato&quot; un licenziante delle implicazioni della licenza CC scelta.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 16:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Carolina Botero: Claudio Ruiz en Bogotá, para SLUD y…</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=298</guid>
	<link>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=298</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Como en otras oportunidades que &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=88&quot;&gt;han venido amigos líderes &lt;/a&gt;de Creative Commons a Bogotá aprovechamos para que dejen acá sus conocimientos y opiniones, como siempre junto con nuestros amigos de la comunidad de Software Libre. Esta vez, estará acá la próxima semana Claudio Ruiz, si el blogger de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quemarlasnaves.net/&quot;&gt;QuemarLasNaves&lt;/a&gt;, y participará en &lt;a href=&quot;http://glud.udistrital.edu.co/slud6/&quot;&gt;la Sexta Semana Linux de la Universidad Distrital (SLUD VI)&lt;/a&gt; y lo aprovecharé, claro, para otras cositas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sexta Semana Linux &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les recomiendo todo el &lt;a href=&quot;http://glud.udistrital.edu.co/slud6/?q=node/19&quot;&gt;programa&lt;/a&gt; (aunque no está de más decir que yo estaré el lunes a las 11am) pero para los interesados en Creative Commons anoten las charlas de Claudio:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El martes&lt;br /&gt;
1:15 a 2:40 pm 	Qué y a quienes protege el derecho de autor: Una historia de intereses y desequilibrios - Claudio Ruíz (Chile) - Invitado Internacional&lt;br /&gt;
El jueves&lt;br /&gt;
1:25 a 2:50 pm 	Creative Commons como herramienta para el desarrollo - Claudio Ruíz (Chile) - Invitado Internacional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lugar: Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas&lt;br /&gt;
Facultad de Ingeniería&lt;br /&gt;
Auditorio Sabio Caldas&lt;br /&gt;
Carrera 8 N. 40-53&lt;br /&gt;
Bogotá, Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrada Libre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Derecho de autor y alternativas en la Universidad Nacional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adicionalmente estaremos participando en una sesión de capacitación para docentes que hace la Fundación Karisma: el tema es Derecho de Autor y problemáticas en el sector educativo y editorial y se organiza por y para LA DIRECCIÓN NACIONAL DE SERVICIOS ACADÉMICOS VIRUTALES, UNIBIBLOS y LA DIRECCIÓN NACIONAL DE BIBLIOTECAS de la Universidad Nacional, y además habrá ¡acceso libre y gratuito vía internet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fecha: 6 de Diciembre de 2007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8:00 a.m. a 8:45 a.m El derecho de autor en la Universidad, problemas y alternativas.  Carolina Botero&lt;br /&gt;
8:45 a.m. a 9:30 a m. Alternativas para la gestión del derecho de autor, ejemplos del sector editorial chileno.  Claudio Ruiz G.&lt;br /&gt;
9:30 a.m. a 10:00 a.m. Descanso&lt;br /&gt;
10:00 a.m. a 11:00 a.m. Sesión de Preguntas y respuestas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esto se va a transmitir de manera virtual, a través del videochat de la Universidad Nacional, si les interesa sigan las instrucciones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los requisitos que debe tener el computador para participar de la conferencia&lt;br /&gt;
1. Audífono (o parlantes)&lt;br /&gt;
2. Micrófono&lt;br /&gt;
3. Cámara Web (opcional)*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para ingresar al videochat, siga los pasos:&lt;br /&gt;
1. Ingrese a la dirección Web: http://aplicaciones.virtual.unal.edu.co/multimedia/eventos/DNSAV-Vide…&lt;br /&gt;
2. Ingrese los siguientes datos.&lt;br /&gt;
Usuario: nombre de quien se conecta&lt;br /&gt;
Contraseña: dnsav&lt;br /&gt;
Espectadores: 1&lt;br /&gt;
Conexión: LAN si esta desde la universidad, Modem y DSL desde otros lugares.&lt;br /&gt;
3. Haga clic en Entrar &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Espero verlos por ahí!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Indaba Music Adds CC-Licensing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7875</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7875</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indabamusic.com/&quot;&gt;Indaba Music&lt;/a&gt;, “an international community of musicians, music professionals, and fans exploring the creative possibilities of making music with people in different places”, has recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indabamusic.com/blogs/show/news/836-session-file-licensing&quot;&gt;added the ability to CC-license tracks to its user interface&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is great news, especially for a community that is firmly based around of the concept of new and interesting forms of collaboration. Incorporating CC-licenses on work posted to Indaba helps bring clarity to the community in terms of what can be shared and reused and what can’t. Now, artists and musicians can clearly dictate which works they wish others to build upon, and similarly, see which works allow themselves to be reused. Up until this point, Indaba’s community has certainly embodied the ethos behind CC-licenses - that of a flexible and user-defined approach to content creation. Now, it is able to do so more explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: Remix J.R. Writer and Tigarah at Jamglue</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7874</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7874</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7760&quot;&gt;good people&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamglue.com/&quot;&gt;Jamglue&lt;/a&gt; are at it again, this time giving you the opportunity to remix American hip-hop artist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamglue.com/contests/jrwriter?src=bnr&quot;&gt;J.R. Writer’s “Where You At”&lt;/a&gt; and Japanese Baile Funk emcee &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamglue.com/contests/tigarah&quot;&gt;Tigarah’s “Color, Culture, Money, Beauty”&lt;/a&gt;, with some very nice prizes for the respective winners. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both remix contests use CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/&quot;&gt;BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt; licenses on instrumental tracks, meaning you have access to cut up and modify each individual sound for your remix. While Jamglue has gotten a hold of some amazingly diverse and talented groups previously (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7683&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7603&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), it is just as important to recognize &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamglue.com/mixes&quot;&gt;the quality and variety of the community remixes&lt;/a&gt;. By using CC-licensing, Jamglue allows artists to open up their content to fans in a way that not only allows for positive interaction and creation, but also maintains the commercial interests of the artists at hand.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/jrwriter-contest_topv13092007.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/tigarah-contest_topv13092007.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 23:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Creative Commons: OnClassical</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7866</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7866</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In continuing our Featured Commoner series, we caught up with Alessandro Simonetto, founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://onclassical.com&quot;&gt;OnClassical&lt;/a&gt;, an audio label for classical music that uses CC licensing integrally in its business plan.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/ale_b_hammers_half-half_500.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s OnClassical all about? &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OnClassical is an online label for refined music. The name means both ON(line)CLASSICAL(music) and ON[about]CLASSICAL[music]. I define “classical” in the same way that &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/classical&quot;&gt;Wiktionary does&lt;/a&gt;, “of or relating to the first class, especially in literature or art” or, “that which designates a kind and forms a base.”. Of course we concern ourselves only with music, not with the other arts. Our aim is to publish music that is deeply rooted in the culture of music at its truest level, including music that is innovative or the fruit of improvisation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of OnClassical brings together not only quality compositions and performances, but also quality recordings that we either produce ourselves or carefully select from the submissions we receive. We recently chose to define onclassical.com as the “online label for audiophiles,” in large part due to a review by premier piano manufacturer Boesendorfer, in which a recording of ours was defined as “very excellent” (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onclassical.com/texts/press/07-03_boesendorfer_appreciation_to_alessandro_simonetto.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF available here&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The label proposes “a new way to think about music.” This means music with no packaging that is distributed via the Internet. OnClassical shares profits 50/50 with artists, and requests no fees or exclusive agreements to join. Besides this, the level of quality in its published performances and recordings is very high and for this reason it is not easy to become one of OnClassical’s featured artists.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7866#more-7866&quot; class=&quot;more-link&quot;&gt;(more…)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 20:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: Pubblicato &quot;Uno bianca e trame nere. Cronaca di un periodo di terrore&quot;</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/597</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/597</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;E' in uscita, sotto licenza CC, l'ultimo libro di Antonella Beccaria (collaboratrice pro bono di questo sito), dal titolo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stampalternativa.it/libri.php?id=978-88-6222-006-4&quot;&gt;&quot;Uno bianca e trame nere. Cronaca di un periodo di terrore&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, ISBN: 978-88-6222-006-4, Collana Eretica - Stampa Alternativa, Novembre 2007.&lt;br /&gt;
Questo libro è rilasciato con licenza Creative Commons-Attribuzione-Non commerciale-Non opere derivate 2.5 Italia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 17:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Netherlands: Manga vaart wel bij namaakindustrie</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.nl/2007/11/30/manga-vaart-wel-bij-namaakindustrie/</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.nl/2007/11/30/manga-vaart-wel-bij-namaakindustrie/</link>
		<category>nl</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In de voorlaatste editie van &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt; werd &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/techbiz/media/magazine/15-11/ff_manga&quot;&gt;uitgebreid aandacht besteed aan het fenomeen Manga&lt;/a&gt; (een Japans stripverhaal). Manga is momenteel een hype aan het worden in Europa en Amerika, onder andere vanwege talloze verfilmingen van de stripverhalen. Ook in Japan is de strip nog altijd ongekend populair. Toch hebben uitgevers van Manga in de afgelopen jaren de omzet zien verminderen. Lees hieronder hoe de Japans manga-industrie met behulp van een alternatief businessmodel een bredere afzetmarkt creëert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terwijl films van getekende superhelden zoals Superman, Spider-Man en Sin City steeds weer volle bioscoopzalen weten te trekken, is het armoe troef in de markt van het gedrukte stripboek in de Verenigde-Staten. Beroemde fabrikanten van comics over superhelden waren er met lede ogen getuige van hoe hun oplages de afgelopen decennia tot een inmiddels dramatisch dieptepunt geslonken zijn. Het lijkt wel alsof de eens zo populaire strips in het internettijdperk hebben afgedaan en alleen nog maar interessant zijn voor jong gebleven veertigers en stoffige verzamelaars.&lt;br /&gt;
Om aan deze trend een einde te maken zijn de laatste tijd veel grote uitgevers van strips er noodgedwongen toe over gegaan om hun comics via het web beschikbaar te maken, om zo een breder en veelal jonger publiek te trekken. Sinds vorige week dinsdag is de collectie van het vermaarde &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marvel.com/&quot;&gt;Marvel Comics&lt;/a&gt;, een van de grootste en bekendste Amerikaanse uitgevers van stripboeken en op strip gebaseerde films, eveneens beschikbaar. Moederbedrijf Marvel Entertainment bestaat sinds 1939 en heeft in het verleden een enorme hoeveelheid aan strips en stripseries uitgebracht. ‘The house of ideas’, zoals het bedrijf liefkozend onder fanatici genoemd wordt, heeft tal van bekende strips en helden onder haar hoede waaronder Captain Marvel, Spider-man en X-men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Op de site van Marvel zijn ongeveer 2500 edities van stripseries te vinden. Om toegang tot de collectie te krijgen moeten lezers echter eerst een maandabonnement afsluiten voor 10 dollar met een credit card. Het is, ondanks het grote aanbod, maar de vraag in hoeverre lezers hiervoor warmlopen aangezien op het web het publiek gewend is om niet te hoeven te betalen voor content. Bovendien zullen veel jongere klanten nog niet beschikken over de benodigde credit card, hetgeen de drempel eveneens verhoogt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dat het ook anders kan, bewijst het artikel in het tijdschrift Wired over Manga. Manga is onderdeel van de zogenaamde ‘pop-art culture’ en kent thans een veel breder publiek dan strips uit de Verenigde Staten. Manga strips zijn vandaag de dag nog altijd immens populair in Japan, al is de omzet uit de fysieke verkoop niet meer zo hoog als in de hoogtijdagen.&lt;br /&gt;
Het inspirerende aan het artikel in Wired is dat er in Japan op een andere manier dan in de Verenigde Staten met de alsmaar tanende omzet wordt omgesprongen; vooralsnog weten Manga uitgevers prima het hoofd boven water te houden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naast de traditionele uitgevers van Manga is er in de afgelopen jaren een hele productie-industrie ontstaan waarbij niet-professionals manga’s zijn gaan maken doordat zij bestaande verhaallijnen van originele stripverhalen en stripfiguren zijn gaan overnemen en verder hebben uitgewerkt. Deze namaakindustrie noemt men in Japan ‘dojishi’. Aanvankelijk waren de traditionele Japanse stripuitgevers niet blij met de namaakindustrie maar zij begrepen op tijd dat zij zich aan de tijdsgeest moesten aanpassen. In feite wordt het auteursrecht geschonden, maar dit wordt door de originele uitgevers van strips door de vingers gezien. Iets dat in de Verenigde Staten ondenkbaar zou zijn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In het artikel in Wired komt naar voren dat Japanse manga-uitgevers hebben begrepen dat het namaken van de originele strip niet de oplages heeft verminderd maar juist heeft vergroot; er is een bredere afzetmarkt ontstaan. Bovendien wordt het gezien als een manier om nieuw talent te ontdekken en is het een goedkope manier van marktresearch om te achterhalen wat er leeft bij de lezers. De makers van de namaak manga’s zijn immers vaak ook de lezers van de originele verhalen. De duidelijke scheiding tussen producers en consumers, professionals en amateurs is aan het vervagen waardoor in feite een nieuwe, grotere afzetmarkt ontstaat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tussen de originele mangauitgevers en de ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%C5%8Djin&quot;&gt;dojinshi&lt;/a&gt;’ bestaan wel stilzwijgende afspraken -an moku noryokai- zoals dat er niet te veel namaak ‘stories’ en ook geen grote oplages op de markt komen. In Japan wordt deze manier van omgaan met reproducties en namaak gezien als een businessmodel dat in de toekomst naar bijvoorbeeld Amerika zou kunnen overwaaien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In het artikel wordt een link gelegd met Creative Commons. De auteur van het stuk in Wired is van mening dat de wijze waarop de belangen van alle partijen met elkaar in overeenstemming worden gebracht in Japan als een belangrijk leer-experiment beschouwd zou kunnen worden. De wijze waarop de Manga industrie zich heeft ontwikkeld buiten het beperkende auteursrecht zou zodoende ook kunnen bijdragen aan een bredere acceptatie van CC-licenties. Het is een wijze les voor Amerikaanse stripmakers, ze zouden eens naar het succes van de Manga strip moeten kijken, die ook in de Verenigde Staten erg populair aan het worden is!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 14:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Carolina Botero: Las músicas de fusión y el anarco punk en Bogotá y Medellín, algunas percepciones de lo legal.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=296</guid>
	<link>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=296</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carolina_publico/Estudios%20de%20Derecho%20caratula2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Caratula Estudios de Derecho&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A finales del 2006 y principios del 2007 participé en una investigación en torno al tema de Negocios Abiertos (aún inedita) que presentamos en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=237&quot;&gt;Rio de Janeiro&lt;/a&gt; por que fue &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=238&quot;&gt;coordinada desde la Fundación Getulio Vargas&lt;/a&gt;, financiada por el &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idrc.ca/es/ev-8513-201-1-DO_TOPIC.html&quot;&gt;IDRC &lt;/a&gt;y dirigida en Colombia  por &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nyu.edu/fas/faculty/cgi/gsas_local/dept/music/Ochoa.html&quot;&gt;Ana María Ochoa&lt;/a&gt;. Mis percepciones de la parte jurídica &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=241&quot;&gt;las presenté en una conferencia&lt;/a&gt; en el Centro de Investigación Valores Musicales Regionales de la Facultad de Artes de la Universidad de Antioquia y a partir de esa conferencia me pidieron de la Revista Estudios de Derecho de la Facultad de Derecho de la Universidad de Antioquia que escribiera un artículo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El artículo se tituló “Las músicas de fusión y el anaco punk en Bogotá y Medellín, algunas percepciones de lo legal” y fue publicado en el volúmen de junio pasado. Si a alguien le interesa el impreso deben comunicarse con &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;rderecho arroba mitra.udea.edu.co&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, por ahora les dejo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carolina_publico/UDEA.pdf&quot;&gt;la versión digital&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 09:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Chile: Alberto Montt</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.cl/2007/11/29/alberto-montt/</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.cl/2007/11/29/alberto-montt/</link>
		<category>cl</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.creativecommons.cl/archivos/amontt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alberto Montt&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://albertomontt.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alberto Montt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; es Artista Plástico y Diseñador Gráfico. Ha colaborado con El Mercurio y revistas como Fibra, Paula, Capital y Mira, entre otras. A diario, publica &lt;a href=&quot;http://albertomontt.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;En Dosis Diarias&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, donde sus viñetas hacen gala de un humor muy particular. Todas están liberadas con licencias &lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/strong&gt;, para que “mire sin compromiso” y “si le gusta, vuelva”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 21:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC China Mainland: 首届CC知识共享摄影大赛作品展 12月5日在北京佳能交流空间开幕</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cn.creativecommons.org/index.php/2007/11/29/%e9%a6%96%e5%b1%8acc%e7%9f%a5%e8%af%86%e5%85%b1%e4%ba%ab%e6%91%84%e5%bd%b1%e5%a4%a7%e8%b5%9b%e4%bd%9c%e5%93%81%e5%b1%95-12%e6%9c%885%e6%97%a5%e5%8c%97%e4%ba%ac%e4%bd%b3%e8%83%bd%e4%ba%a4%e6%b5%81/</guid>
	<link>http://cn.creativecommons.org/index.php/2007/11/29/canon-exhibition/</link>
		<category>cn</category>
	<description>展出时间：2007年12月5日 - 12月17日

讲座时间：12月8日14:00-16:30

展出地点：佳能交流空间·北京

地址：北京市西城区华远街13号置地星座A座首层（西单君太百货西）


展厅电话：010-66033680</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 13:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: Video &quot;Diritti d'autori creativi&quot;</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/595</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/595</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Segnaliamo il bel video &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biasco.ch/videoblog/vbp5/index.html&quot;&gt;&quot;Diritti d'autori creativi&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Testo, regia e montaggio: Christian Biasco, Francesca Terri (resto dei crediti sul sito).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 11:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: Pubblicata la prima bozza delle licenze CC 3.0</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/574</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/574</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Dopo un periodo di redazione interna, il gruppo di lavoro di Creative Commons Italia ha pubblicato la prima bozza della versione 3.0 delle licenze CC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 11:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: post-music industry forum reflections</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-2180834640865809378</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/post-music-industry-forum-reflections.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2147/2071127496_4abd73784d.jpg?v=0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2147/2071127496_4abd73784d.jpg?v=0&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 244px; height: 367px;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 78%;&quot;&gt;Me, Jessica Coates and Scot Morris at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicfourm&quot;&gt;ccau music industry fourm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/nicsuzor/2071127496/&quot;&gt;Photo&lt;/a&gt; by Nic Suzor, available under a &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en&quot;&gt;CC BY SA 2.0&lt;/a&gt; licence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yesterday we held the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum&quot;&gt;ccau music industry forum&lt;/a&gt; as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.auc.edu.au/&quot;&gt;Apple University Consortium&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://auc.edu.au/Create+World+2007&quot;&gt;Create World 2007&lt;/a&gt; conference. It was designed to explore possible options for harmonising the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apra.com.au/&quot;&gt;APRA&lt;/a&gt; and CC licensing models so Australia musicians can non-commercially CC licence while still collecting royalites from APRA for commercial use of their work. In summary the position at the moment is:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;In Australia (and New Zealand) the Australasian Performing Right Association (APRA), like many collecting societies around the world, takes a full assignment of the member’s performing rights of all past, present and future works. By assigning the rights to the collecting society it allows more efficient administration of the royalty collection process. However, this raises compatibility issues for creators who have assigned their rights to a collecting society but then seek to license a work or works under a Creative Commons “Non-Commercial” licence. In simple terms, once a person is a member of APRA, the performing right in all works is assigned to APRA and therefore the creator no longer has the right to issue any direct licences for the performance of their works.&lt;/blockquote&gt;In order to make CC a (legal) option for Australian musicians in the management of their content, APRA would need to create a process by which members can elect to apply a CC licence to defined works (similar to the current &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apra.com.au/writers/downloads/OOLB_OptOutAndLicenceBack.pdf&quot;&gt;licence back options&lt;/a&gt;). There are a range of issues that need to be addressed before such an arrangement could be made. Please read the information provided on the CCau website for &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/musicinfo&quot;&gt;more information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now Scot Morris, International Director of APRA said himself, “APRA artists have been releasing music under Creative Commons licences&quot; and &quot;we're not going to sue our members.&quot; Equally the record lables and APRA aren't suing non-commercial users of musical works (but, as Nic Suzor notes on his &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/span&gt;, &quot;...the threat is still a significant deterrent in many cases&quot; think Dean Gray and the remixed Green Day’s American Idiot album, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Edit&quot;&gt;American Edit&lt;/a&gt;). Big deal! For the sake of those non-commercial users I want to see a more official model that provides certainty of the legality of reusing content. I want to see a trial, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.nl/2007/08/23/cc-nl-start-pilot-flexibel-rechtenbeheer-samen-met-bumastemra/&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; (if you can read Dutch) happening in the Netherlands between &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativecommons.nl/&quot;&gt;CC Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bumastemra.nl/&quot;&gt;Buma/Stemra&lt;/a&gt;, where members are able to collect for commercial use of a work that is non-commercially licenced. The Fourm was designed to disemminate information on the situtation and to get the ball rolling on discussions of a possible trial here. As such it was great to see a lively, engaging debate emerge. That's exactly what we were looking for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A few things to come out of the Forum:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;APRA appear to be willing to work with CCau to find a solution to the discrepancies between the licensing models (which is good);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There is a need to define more clearly the term &quot;non-commerical&quot; (which has already &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.creativecommons.org/NonCommercial_Guidelines&quot;&gt;begun&lt;/a&gt; but would need to be customised to the specific situation here in Australia);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Members using CC would need to register the works that are licensed with APRA, which adds to APRA's administrative costs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;APRA are concerned about who will enforce the rights of the musician where the non-commercial licence is breached.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Economics is a key factor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;It is encouraging to see that APRA are (finally) willing to work with CCau to better the current situation. I conceed that to make it happen, CC may have to define in more detail what we mean by &quot;non-commerical&quot; in the licences. As Nic &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;said&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nic.suzor.com/20071128-ccau-musicforum&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;...APRA would normally collect on, for example, educational uses, whereas a musician who released their song under a CC NonCommercial licence would not be entitled to collect royalties for those classes of performance.&quot; APRA possed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/triplej/&quot;&gt;Triple J&lt;/a&gt; as another example; are they non-commercial or not? This is an area that will require some fleshing out before a trial can happen here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;APRA were also concerned about who would enforce a breach of the non-commercial licence. Now fair enough if the provision that is breached is the Attribution clause, but if the Noncommercial term is breached, then it has to have been a commerical use which means it is still a matter for APRA. And APRA can act on its members' behalf. And so they should in this instance I think.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the economics front, APRA made the point that they would have to keep data on who of their members were using CC and on what tracks. This would be an administratively arduous task apparently. But Scot Morris detailed and showed a screen shot of APRA's software that keeps detailed statistical data on each song played by is major licensees. The information this system can hold is impressive. (In full admission of my relative naievity on the technical/software side of things) becuase CC licences include metadata, then theoretically if you modified the software to read and recognise this metadata that would automate at least some of the admin required wouldn't it?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They also cited diminished bargaining power as a problem. They were concerned that by letting people CC licence for non-commercial use it would allow licensees who were using these tracks to argue for discounted licensing fees. Boo hoo I say. If a muscian has decided they are ok will allowing non-commercial use they clearly that means they've conceded to not getting a royalty for that use. What really seems to be the issue is that this might highlight a few statistical problems in the APRA charging shedule, not to mention APRA might just pull in less money (again, a point picked up by Nic,&quot;[APRA's] main concern seemed to be that Murdoch and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; would be able to exploit musicians by using Creative Commons licensed music&quot;).&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 03:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: welcoming new writers to cc through the looking glass</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-4148803808664495559</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/welcoming-new-writers-to-cc-through.html</link>
	<description>I've decided there is just too much to talk about around CC for me to do it alone (you should see how many draft entries are waiting to be finished!) So I've invited some other people who are involved with CCau to contribute as well. Say hello to:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Jessica Coates, Project Manager, &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccClinic&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Clinic&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nic Suzor, who doing his PhD on virtual environments;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rachel Cobcroft, who is currently developing case studies of projects and individuals using CC in Australia and is doing her PhD on motiviations for sharing on &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Emma Carroll, who is interested in CC and the music industry; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Isha Baywaters, who took the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccClinic&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Clinic&lt;/a&gt; course and is currently researching open business models for the music industry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Looking forward to their ideas!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, this is not an official CCau blog, it is the personal ideas and opinions of people involved with CCau.&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 02:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Lawrence Lessig: From the Why-a-GC-from-Cravath-is-great Department: The lawsuit is over</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3465</guid>
	<link>http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/from_the_whyagcfromcravathisgr.html</link>
	<description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/virgin.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/virgin-thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;virgin.jpg&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

We received this happy missive in the mail yesterday: The plaintiffs in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html&quot;&gt;lawsuit about Virgin using a CC-licensed photo&lt;/a&gt; have dismissed CC from the case. This is not a settlement. It is not the product of negotiation. It is the recognition by plaintiffs counsel that the laws of Texas and the United States give the plaintiffs no cause to sue Creative Commons.

As I said when I announced the lawsuit &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,  the fact that the laws of the United States don't make us liable for the misuse in this context doesn't mean that we're not working extremely hard to make sure misuse doesn't happen. It is always a problem (even if not a legal problem) when someone doesn't understand what our licenses do, or how they work. We need to work harder to make that clear. But the news today lets us go back to the work of &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;, without the burden of this lawsuit hanging above us. 

So how can you celebrate with us? Well, help us recover some of the costs (probably $15k) that we have to eat because of this suit (deductibles with our insurance company, etc) by &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;supporting CC&lt;/a&gt;. Or help us by joining as just a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/50000_friends.html&quot;&gt;friend of CC&lt;/a&gt;.  Or help us by spreading the news that the lawsuit is over.

And as one final word to the plaintiffs here -- a word I can utter because neither required nor asked: As CEO of Creative Commons, I apologize for any trouble that confusion about our licenses might have created. We thought the meaning was clear. We work hard to make this as clear as we can. We will work harder.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2007 22:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Italy: L'emittente pubblica tedesca NDR usa le licenze CC per (alcune) trasmissioni</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.it/node/594</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.it/node/594</link>
		<category>it</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Come già riportato &lt;a href=&quot;http://de.blognation.com/2007/11/22/ndr-german-public-television-experiments-with-creative-commons/&quot;&gt;in giro per la rete&lt;/a&gt;, l'emittente pubblica tedesca &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ndr.de/&quot;&gt;NDR&lt;/a&gt; sta usando delle licenze CC per due trasmissioni.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 14:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Lawrence Lessig: Big news, great party</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3464</guid>
	<link>http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/big_news_great_party.html</link>
	<description>&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/cc_party.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lessig.org/blog/cc_party-thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cc_party.jpg&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; width=&quot;603&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:party@creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 23:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Lawrence Lessig: German Public TV starts a CC experiment</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3463</guid>
	<link>http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/german_public_tv_starts_a_cc_e.html</link>
	<description>As &lt;a href=&quot;http://de.blognation.com/2007/11/22/ndr-german-public-television-experiments-with-creative-commons/&quot;&gt;reported at Blognation&lt;/a&gt;, German Public Television has started an experiment by licensing two of its shows under a CC license. 

For German speakers (and last week, my 4 year old informed me I was not a German speaker and I &quot;should only speak English&quot;), here's a clip explaining the decision:

&lt;center&gt;&lt;/center&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 23:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: remix MY lit!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-586901698085926063</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/remix-my-lit.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bp0.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R0pS5YNP4qI/AAAAAAAAAC8/QY81BI_rOe0/s1600-h/main+rml+logo+-+pink+-+web+big.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bp0.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R0pS5YNP4qI/AAAAAAAAAC8/QY81BI_rOe0/s400/main+rml+logo+-+pink+-+web+big.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; id=&quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5137009470673511074&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Amy Barker and I are working on a new CCau project that hasn't yet got legs (ie no funding) but which is sparking a fair bit of interest around the place called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.remixmylit.com/&quot;&gt;Remix my lit&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.varuna.com.au/alumni/alumninews&amp;amp;events.html#creativecommons&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://remixablefilms.multiply.com/journal/item/26/remix_my_lit&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Most of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asauthors.org/scripts/cgiip.exe/WService=ASP0016/ccms.r?PageId=10041&quot;&gt;writers' centres&lt;/a&gt; are really interested so we hope to go a lot further with it soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Basically, the idea is that remixing isn't limited to film and music. There is no reason why the written word should not be open to the possibility of creative play. Remix my lit exists to facilitate experimentation in literature remixing. The first planned project will see a body of works by established authors released into the commons for remixing. All remixes will be hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.remixmylit.com/&quot;&gt;remixmylit.com&lt;/a&gt; and a selection will (hopefully) be published in a printed volume. We aim to create a community of writers exploring new ways of writing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Writers that are endorsing the project include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.battersby.com.au/&quot;&gt;Lee Battersby&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribepublications.com.au/author/catekennedy&quot;&gt;Cate Kennedy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allen-unwin.com/Vogel/current.asp&quot;&gt;Stefan Laszczuk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://emilymaguire.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Emily McGuire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamesphelan.com.au/&quot;&gt;James Phelan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimwilkins.com/&quot;&gt;Kim Wilkins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allenandunwin.com/default.aspx?page=311&amp;amp;author=35&quot;&gt;Danielle Wood&lt;/a&gt; as well as poet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mandybeaumont.com/mandy/home.htm&quot;&gt;Mandy Beaumont&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And to put the money where my mouth is, you can even remix my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.remixmylit.com/2007/11/26/flash-photography-and-screams/&quot;&gt;short fiction piece&lt;/a&gt;. So go on, remix my lit!&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 05:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: ccau music industry forum</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-5963183950389660285</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/ccau-music-industry-forum.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2173/1867006343_4e309d705d.jpg?v=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;font face=&quot;Verdana&quot; size=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;28 november 2007, 2.00 till 4.00pm @ the queensland college of art, griffith university, 226 grey street, south bank, brisbane&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On 28 November, The ARC &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cci.edu.au&quot;&gt;Centre of Excellence for Creative Industries and Innovation&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting the CCau Music Industry Forum as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.auc.edu.au&quot;&gt;Apple University Consortium&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://auc.edu.au/Create+World+2007&quot;&gt;Create World 2007&lt;/a&gt; conference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is designed to provide a forum for the discussion of issues surrounding music licensing in Australia. It will take place from 2.00 till 4.00pm on Wednesday 28 November 2007 at the Queensland College of Art, Griffith University, Brisbane.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The digital environment presents new opportunities for musicians and new business models for the distribution of music. Creative Commons licensing in particular has gained considerable favour with content producers world-wide. However the legalities and practicalities of releasing music under these new models can be complicated, particularly when you wish to combine them with more traditional collective licensing options (for further information visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativecommons.org.au/musicinfo&quot;&gt;www.creativecommons.org.au/musicinfo&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The CCau Music Industry Forum aims to bring together industry representatives and interested parties to discuss issues such as:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• potential online distribution models for musicians and the music industry; &lt;br /&gt;• compatibility issues with current collective licensing schemes; and &lt;br /&gt;• legal and practical issues relating to the use of Creative Commons licences by Australian songwriters, composers and musicians.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Discussants at the Forum will include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• Professor Brian Fitzgerald, Project Lead, Creative Commons Australia; &lt;br /&gt;• Scot Morris, Director International Relations, APRA; &lt;br /&gt;• Professor Paul Draper, Director of IMERSD (Intermedia, Music Education &amp;amp; Research Design) and Deputy Director, Queensland Conservatorium Research Centre, Griffith University; and&lt;br /&gt;• Q Music&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The forum also aims to gather feedback regarding the current understanding of and attitudes towards copyright, open content licensing and Creative Commons within the Australian music industry whilst providing an opportunity for key music industry personnel in to learn more about these topics.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Creative Commons Australia is the Australian arm of the international Creative Commons project, a non-profit organisation that aims to promote flexible copyright options for creators. At the core of the Creative Commons project is a suite of licences, freely available to creators, that foster sharing and collaboration. Creative Commons builds upon the “all rights reserved” of traditional copyright to create a voluntary “some rights reserved” system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Persons  currently involved or interested in the licensing of musical works are welcome to attend. rsvp by friday 23 november 2007 to elliott at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:elliott@creativecommons.org.au&quot;&gt;elliott@creativecommons.org.au&lt;/a&gt; or call (07) 3138 9597.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2356/1867831670_9e6b023bfe.jpg?v=0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font face=&quot;Century Gothic&quot; size=&quot;1&quot;&gt;image: ventura mendoza, licensed under a creative commons &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot;&gt;attribution licence 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/vmendoza/490269072&quot;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/vmendoza/490269072&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 02:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: australian pc world writes up the ccau music forum</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-2015255158512747626</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/australian-pc-world-writes-up-ccau.html</link>
	<description>Danah McConnachie at Australian PC World &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.idg.com.au/index.php/id;1477749946&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; a great article about the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum&quot;&gt;ccau music industry forum&lt;/a&gt;. There's a whole spiel about why we are running the forum (which is great exposure for the event) and then there is a lengthy interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mabula.net/tbfw/&quot;&gt;Paul Wayper&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anu.edu.au&quot;&gt;ANU&lt;/a&gt; research programmer who uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmms.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;linux multimedia system&lt;/a&gt;. Wayper agrees with the CC argument that copyright is being used to lock down content:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;While Creative Commons licenses work to foster innovation and sharing or resources, traditional media companies and agencies and technologies such as DRM work against these freedoms.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some other great pull-outs from the article:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;There are two fundamental changes in the landscape of music, and art, production. Firstly, it no longer takes a dedicated artist who's spent thousands on special instruments to have the equipment and talent to produce a good-quality piece of music. Secondly, the actual distribution of music no longer takes arcane mixing processes, mastering to record or CD, printing and distribution of physical items. The only thing that hasn't really changed is that people still want to listen to music,&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;...I give away my pieces with a (CC) license that allows some reuse while not allowing total exploitation because I don't really expect someone to shell out money for them. If I were to turn to producing commercial trance full time I might expect to be paid, but only if I actually made something that other people were making money off. The key thing that people don't think about CC licenses is that it doesn't mean you can't negotiate the rights to other uses, just that they aren't given by default.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Wayer is talking at &lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.conf.au/&quot;&gt;linux.conf.au&lt;/a&gt; 2008 in January.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 02:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Japan: COMITIA/コミティアに行ってきました</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.jp/news/2007/11/25/comitia.html</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.jp/news/2007/11/25/comitia.html</link>
		<category>jp</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;11/18に東京ビッグサイトにて開催された、オリジナル作品のみの同人誌即売会「&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.comitia.co.jp/&quot;&gt;COMITIA&lt;/a&gt;」に、CCJPのメンバー数人で遊びに行ってきました！&lt;br /&gt;
# English at bottom&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 14:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Carolina Botero: FRANCIA, proponen quitarle Internet a los “piratas”.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=297</guid>
	<link>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=297</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Hace solo dos años, y por casi un año, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=28&quot;&gt;Francia revolucionaba la blogosfera &lt;/a&gt;con una opción concreta; la licencia global que se aprobaría a través del proyecto de ley de propiedad intelectual conocido como &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/index.php?s=dadvsi&quot;&gt;Dadvsi&lt;/a&gt;, la propuesta significaba la legalización de toda descarga de contenidos desde Internet, no se consiguió que pasara en el Congreso… pero estuvo cerca, muy cerca. Hoy sin embargo el pulso parece que lo ganan del otro lado:  bajo el liderazgo de FNAC (una de las tiendas europeas que tienen mayor participación en el mercado de venta de música y videos) se ha logrado un acuerdo entre el estado y la industria para quitar las cuentas de acceso a Internet a quienes descarguen de la red contenidos protegidos por el derecho de autor, y digo ganan por que por ahora el acuerdo ha tenido un respaldo decidido del presidente Sarkozy y parece que a pesar de las críticas saldrá adelante. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En resumen la propuesta es que se crearía una autoridad sometida a autoridad judicial para informar a quienes descarguen música y películas sobre la ilegalidad de tal acción, con el apoyo de los prestadores del servicio, las sanciones serán suspensión y cancelación del servicio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La situación por supuesto &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audionautes.net/pages/informer/communiques/voir.php?id=43&quot;&gt;ha sido rebatida por la Asociación de Audionautas&lt;/a&gt;, tan activos en su momento apoyando la licencia global, pero sobre todo son los artículos desde Nouvelle Observateur los que me han parecido más críticos. Particularmente me han gustado: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tempsreel.nouvelobs.com/actualites/20071124.OBS6556/&quot;&gt;“Piratería, el informe Olivennes la considera ´peligrosa´”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tempsreel.nouvelobs.com/actualites/20071123.OBS6440/&quot;&gt;“Descargas, un acuerdo firmado en el Eliseo”&lt;/a&gt; y esta en la que se reproduce &lt;a href=&quot;http://clubobs.nouvelobs.com/article/2007/11/23/20071123.FAP3625.xml&quot;&gt;un artículo de Associated Press&lt;/a&gt; (les aconsejo también las reacciones que tienen algunos de los artículos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otros artículos: en inglés &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/internetNews/idUSL2346825720071123&quot;&gt;el artículo de Reuters &lt;/a&gt;y en español acá está el de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elpais.com/articulo/radio/television/Francia/cortara/linea/quien/baje/musica/cine/elpeputec/20071124elpepirtv_4/Tes&quot;&gt;El Pais&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actualización: el tema en otros blogs (en construcción), Cory Doctorow en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boingboing.net/2007/11/25/french-law-will-forc.html&quot;&gt;BoingBoing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://einvents.wordpress.com/2007/11/26/francia-se-quedaran-sin-internet-usuarios-de-p2p/&quot;&gt;einvents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://technollama.blogspot.com/2007/11/french-strike-at-pirates.html&quot;&gt;Technollama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 11:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: why it is difficult to use MC Hammer in a documentary film</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-4122308235709345769</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/08/some-thoughts-from-cc-documentary-paper.html</link>
	<description>&lt;font color=&quot;7CFC00&quot; face=&quot;Verdana&quot; size=&quot;4&quot;&gt;some thoughts from writing an article on documentary and open content licensing&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've been working on an article about documentary, rights management and creative commons for far too long now. Since I spoke at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2007.aidc.com.au&quot;&gt;Australian International Documentary Conference&lt;/a&gt;, in February actually.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, here's a bit of precursor:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rights clearances are one of the biggest hurdles for filmmakers. Copyright clearances are required for each element in the film that is not the original creation of the filmmaker. Add the amount of money that often costs, the conditions on which rights are granted by gatekeepers and the need to take content out that ins't cleared (or risk being done for copyright infringement). Oh the pangs of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permission_culture&quot;&gt;permission culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But CC presents new ways of managing copyright and alternative avenues. The Creative Commons “some rights reserved” approach offers new ways of thinking about, managing and capitalising on creative content. But these are only part of what it offers. It is also a tool for assisting collaboration, innovation and experimentation, and can open up options for utilisation, promotion and distribution of content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;7CFC00&quot; face=&quot;Verdana&quot; size=&quot;2&quot;&gt;copyright's “can’t touch this” effect&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The practical effect of copyright is to restrict all but a narrow set of uses  of copyrighted material or works—including “literary, dramatic, musical or artistic” works  and “subject matter other than works” such as sound recordings , films , television and sound broadcasts  and published editions of works—automatically  at the point of creation. That copyright in original works  subsists for  70 years after the end of the calendar year in which the author of the work died.  For works considered to be other subject matter the duration varies. For sound recordings and films it's 70 years after the end of the calendar year in which the work is first published.  In the case of television or sound broadcasts, copyright expires at the end of 50 years after the end of the calendar year in which the first broadcast was made.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Any use of a copyrighted work without the permission of the creator is an infringement of copyright attracting possible civil and criminal actions. Copyright is somewhat of a misnomer. Really it should be called copyrights given that it encompasses a bundle or rights including the right to reproduce the work, publish the work, perform it in public, communicate it to the public and to make derivative/adaptive works from it . This is why the common phrase is “All Rights Reserved” as copyright by default protects all rights in the work. Like the MC Hammer song, what this means is “can’t touch this.” These are often referred to as the economic rights of copyright. The existence of these rights independently of each facilitates copyright licensing (see below). Copyright owners also have the right  to licence to another person authority to utilise their work in relation to any or all of those rights.So long as the licensee does not exercise powers beyond the scope of the licence, they are exempt from being sued from copyright infringement. If you haven’t been granted a licence and you make an unauthorised use of the copyright you are in breach. This is symptomatic of a permissions culture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;7CFC00&quot; face=&quot;Verdana&quot; size=&quot;2&quot;&gt;a permissions culture: copyright clearances&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The need to have approval to reuse content results in what Stanford Law Professor Lawrence Lessig calls a ‘permission culture.' [See &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.free-culture.cc/&quot;&gt;Free Culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;] It is an environment in which “creators get to create only with the permission of the powerful, or of creators from the past.” The permission culture stymies new creative endeavour; whether that is because of the complexity of getting clearance (or indeed identifying a copyright owner in order to get clearance) or the many explicit and hidden cost associated with getting copyright clearance. Possibly more concerning still is the ability of copyright holders to withhold consent to suppress negative commentary on them or affiliated organisations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are numerous examples of situations where films have been forced underground because of copyright. Take for example Peter Spears’s short &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Earnest and Bertram&lt;/span&gt;—an adaptation of Lillian Hellman’s play of unrequited gay love &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Children’s Hour&lt;/span&gt;. The film presents the Bert and Ernie characters from popular American childrens’ television program &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Seasame Street&lt;/span&gt; as closeted gay men. It was a huge success at Sundance Film Festival, but was soon off screens when owners of the characters and associated television program, Sesame Workshop issued Spears with a cease and desist notice. “I felt it was protected under First Amendment freedom of speech parody, but I understand that they have to protect their copyright,” Spears lamented in interview with the US editor of Screen International, Michael Goodridge, “When they served me the cease and desist, I didn't have the energy or financial resources to fight it.&quot;  Spears pulled the film from the festival circuit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Director of &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Velvet Goldmine&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Far From Heaven&lt;/span&gt;, Todd Haynes, is no stranger to the realities of rights clearances either. Even before his debut into feature, Haynes had felt the copyright pinch. His first popular short, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Superstar: The Karen Carpenter Story&lt;/span&gt;, used Barbie dolls to retell the singers’ life. Richard Carpenter took it out of circulation for its use of original music by The Carpenters. Toy-company giant Mattel didn’t get involved despite the use of their Barbie dolls in this instance, but Argentinean filmmaker Albertina Carri wasn’t so lucky. Her film &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Barbie Can Also Be Sad&lt;/span&gt; was pulled from a film festival in Mexico after legal action taken by the company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A more recent example is Robert Greenwald’s &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Outfoxed: Rupert Murdoch’s War on Journalism&lt;/span&gt;. It utilises extensive footage from the news service, leaked policy memos penned by Fox executives and interview footage with former employees to expose the ways that Fox News allegedly distorts it reporting to serve the conservative political leaning of its owner. Importantly, Greenwald used much of this content with Fox’s permission. Greenwald kept a lot of information about the project under wraps because he feared a court injunction would be sought to stop the films release. Today Fox has not responded publicly except to say in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/span&gt; “People steal our footage all the time. We generally sort of look the other way.&quot;  But of course, Fox had (and still have) the right to object to the film, and could have embroiled the film in a lengthy court battle to suppress it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But Fox were not the only third party with copyright tied up in &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Outfoxed&lt;/span&gt;. As &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/span&gt; outlined in an article in the lead up to the film’s release:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“…several major news organizations were unexpectedly refusing to license their clips. (Such licensing is ordinarily pro forma.) CBS wouldn't sell Greenwald the clip of Richard Clarke's appearance on ''60 Minutes,'' explaining that it didn't want to be associated with a controversial documentary about Murdoch. WGBH, the Boston PBS station, wouldn't let Greenwald use excerpts from ''Frontline'' for fear of looking too ''political,'' it said.” &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These copyright owners had the ability to force their copyrighted works to not be included in the documentary. (Not all the clearances were so negative it should be added; Eric Clapton granted the film the right to use ‘Layla’ at no charge as did Don Henley for the track ‘Dirty Laundry.’) Even if Greenwald had left the most contentious and litigious content in the film and relied on the strength of a fair use claim, “as a practical matter the high costs of litigation force most filmmakers to simply remove the material in question.”   Similarly here in Australia, reliance on fair dealing can be risky and the threat of litigation and the costs associated with it often results in filmmakers playing it safe and removing the questionable material.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although there are some legitimate uses of copyrighted material without the permission of the copyright owner, in most instances the right to reuse content will be granted by way of a licence from the copyright owner. Authorisation occurs when the copyright owner (or the “licensor”) grants (or “licences”) permission to another party (or the “licensee”) to exercise any right in the bundle.&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 08:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mike Linksvayer: Requirements for community funding of open source</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/24/cofundos/</guid>
	<link>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/24/cofundos/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cofundos.org/docs/crowdfunding.php&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cofundos.org/layout/cofundosprocess.png&quot; style=&quot;padding: 5px; float: right;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last month &lt;a href=&quot;http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/08/27/micropledge/&quot;&gt;another&lt;/a&gt; site for aggregating donation pledges to open source software projects &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.aksw.org/2007/open-source-innovation-platform-cofundosorg/&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure there’s anything significant that sets Cofundos apart from microPledge featurewise. Possibly a step where bidders (pledgers) vote on which developer bid to accept. However I’m not certain how a developer is chosen on microPledge — their FAQ &lt;a href=&quot;http://micropledge.com/help/dev#develop&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; “A quote will be chosen that delivers the finished and paid product to the pledgers most quickly based on their current pledging rate (not necessarily the shortest quote).” microPledge’s scheme for &lt;a href=&quot;http://micropledge.com/help/dev#estimate&quot;&gt;in progress payments&lt;/a&gt; may set it apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of marketing and associations, Cofundos comes from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://aksw.org&quot;&gt;Agile Knowledge Engineering and Semantic Web&lt;/a&gt; research group at the University of Leipzig, producers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DBpedia&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;DBpedia&lt;/a&gt;, about which I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/01/23/dbpedia/&quot;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the early proposed projects are directly related to AKSW research. Their &lt;a href=&quot;http://cofundos.org/docs/terms.php#Copyright&quot;&gt;copyright policy&lt;/a&gt; is appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;microPledge is produced by &lt;a href=&quot;http://micropledge.com/about&quot;&gt;three Christian siblings&lt;/a&gt; who &lt;a href=&quot;http://micropledge.com/religion&quot;&gt;don’t push their religion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cofundos lists &lt;a href=&quot;http://cofundos.org/projects.php&quot;&gt;61 proposed projects&lt;/a&gt; after one month, microPledge lists &lt;a href=&quot;http://micropledge.com/tags&quot;&gt;about 160&lt;/a&gt; after about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.micropledge.com/2007/08/micropledge-public-launch/&quot;&gt;three and a half months&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t see any great successes on either site, but both are young, and perhaps I’m not looking hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cofundos and microPledge are both welcome experiments, though I don’t expect either to become huge. On the other hand, even modest success would set a valuable precedent. In that vein I’ve been pretty &lt;a href=&quot;http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2006/03/18/sxswi-wrap/&quot;&gt;skeptical about the chances of Fundable&lt;/a&gt;, they seem to have attracted a steady stream of users. Although most projects seem to be uninteresting (pledges for bulk purchases, group trips, donations to an individual’s college fund, etc), some production of public goods does seem to being funded, including several film projects in the small thousands of dollars range. Indeed, “My short film” is the default project name in their form for starting a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that creating requirements and getting in front of interested potential donors are the main challenges for sites focused on funding open source software like Cofundos and microPledge (both say they are only starting with software). Requirements are just hard, and there’s little incentive for anyone to visit an aggregator who hasn’t aggregated anything of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if integrating financial donations into project bug tracking systems would address both challenges? Of course doing so would have risks, both of increasing bureaucracy around processing bugs and feature requests, necessity of implementing new features (and bugs) in the relevant bug tracking software, and altering the incentives of volunteer contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.okfn.org/2007/10/26/cofundos-community-innovation-and-funding/&quot;&gt;Via Open Knowledge Foundation Blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 23:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: ccau staff talk a lot: part 2</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-4119335692565245494</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/ccau-staff-talk-lot-part-2.html</link>
	<description>Another interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://abc.net.au&quot;&gt;ABC&lt;/a&gt;, this time with me ^_^  Back in April, while I was in Sydney for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ourmedia07.net/&quot;&gt;OURMEDIA VI&lt;/a&gt; I ducked into the ABC Ultimo building to record an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pool.org.au/node/894&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; for radio and that would become part of an exciting new ABC-run user-generated content project called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pool.org.au/&quot;&gt;Pool&lt;/a&gt;. More about Pool later, first here's the interview and accompanying video they made:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;


&lt;br /&gt;(available under a CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/au/&quot;&gt;BY-NC 2.5 Aus&lt;/a&gt; licence)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The video gives an overview of CC, the protocols, the commercial/non-commercial distinction and explains possible motivations for wanting to use CC.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So what is Pool? It's a collaborative production environment that people can submit their creative works to. In the about it says:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Grow ideas; download, remix and share with your friends and the world. Music, photos, videos, documentaries, interviews, animations, and more. Connect with people; by comments, tags, friend lists, and collaborative co-creation.  Is this the future of public media?&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The site is under a CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/au/&quot;&gt;BY-NC-ND 2.5 Aus&lt;/a&gt; licence, but also allows All Rights Reserved and the CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/au/&quot;&gt;BY-NC 2.5 Aus&lt;/a&gt; licence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And why did they decide to use CC?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;We decided to use Creative Commons licences for Pool because we think it's the best way possible to have some fun with content, without breaching any copyright laws.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beta_version#Beta&quot;&gt;beta testing&lt;/a&gt;, so go easy on it. Get on there and give some good feedback. CCau certainly wants to see it happen!&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 03:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.blogger.com/video-play.mp4?contentId=8c054774ddc15ceb&amp;type=video%2Fmp4" length="0" type="video/mp4"/>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: ccau staff talk a lot: part 1</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-197901850415640231</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/ccau-staff-talk-lot.html</link>
	<description>The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au&quot;&gt;ABC&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/rn&quot;&gt;Radio National&lt;/a&gt; recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/rn/lawreport/stories/2007/2095456.htm&quot;&gt;broadcast&lt;/a&gt; a mashup of content stimulated by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mwf.com.au&quot;&gt;Melbourne Writers' Festival&lt;/a&gt; debate &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mwf.com.au/2007/content/events.asp?name=20070826_1130_350WS&quot;&gt;Creative commons or common theft?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; recordings that had &lt;a href=&quot;http://craphound.com/&quot;&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://craphound.com/stories.php&quot;&gt;sci-fi author&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/2006/11/30/cory-doctorow-copyright-tech-media_cz_cd_books06_1201doctorow.html&quot;&gt;CC advocate&lt;/a&gt;) in the blue corner and Sandy Grant (Senior executive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hardiegrant.com.au/&quot;&gt;Hardie Grant Publishing&lt;/a&gt;, and member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.copyright.com.au/&quot;&gt;Copyright Agency Limited&lt;/a&gt; Board) in the red corner. holding the sweat towels were Mark Williams (Senior adviser with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jdrlegal.com.au/&quot;&gt;JDR Legal&lt;/a&gt;) and CCau's very own Jessica Coates (Project Manager, &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org.au/node/74&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Clinic&lt;/a&gt;). You can listen to the recording &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/rn/lawreport/stories/2007/2095456.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is great to see CC being talked about (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/rn/bookshow/stories/2007/2039471.htm&quot;&gt;again&lt;/a&gt;) on the Australian public broadcaster. But as always, I have a few gripes. Damien Carrick opens the podcast by saying:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;This morning, Creative Commons: making films, literature or music  for free online. It undermines copyright but is it also creating whole new business models and income streams for our artists?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don't like it. I know Jess tells me that it's to make it sound controversial to keep people listening, but its misinformation and i dont like it. Sorry Damien, Creative Commons does &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; undermine copyright, it remixes it to create more flexible (and arguably useful) ways of managing copyright. As such, I don't agree that CC &quot;essentially strip copyright of all meaning,&quot; but rather breaths new life and meaning into copyright (as I have said &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anat.org.au/stillopen/blog/2007/08/31/copy-me-pass-it-on/&quot;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;). As &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org/videos#gc&quot;&gt;Get Creative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; states, &quot;CC isn't meant to compete with copyright, but to compliment it.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moving on, Williams opened the debate with a tale of one of the first pirated works. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fergus_Hume&quot;&gt;Fergus Hume&lt;/a&gt;'s detective (self-published) novel, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The Mystery of the Hansom Cab&lt;/span&gt; (first published 1886, you can find it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org&quot;&gt;Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/etext/4223&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), was pirated and sold throughout Europe. It paved the way for a new genre of fiction (think &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sherlock_Holmes&quot;&gt;Sherlock Holmes)&lt;/a&gt;. Williams goes on to note that the pirated version went on to sell a huge number of copies, most of the money from which did not find its way into Hume's bank account. So no money there, but as Williams himself attests, &quot;[Hume] was famous, and it enabled him to then write another 100 or so novels...&quot; The problem for most artists, according to Doctorow, is obscurity not piracy. Therefore piracy = reputation (?) Without the piracy, would Hume have had the opportunity to write as much as he did?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then Grant gets amongst it. I love that Grant refers to CC as having &quot;something of a cult following.&quot; Gee, &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/5579&quot;&gt;53 million pages licensed&lt;/a&gt; and projects in &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/international/&quot;&gt;66 countries&lt;/a&gt; around the world with licences or in the process of drafting them. (Doctorow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.locusmag.com/Features/2007/11/cory-doctorow-creative-commons.html&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; 160 million+ works licensed since 2003, but i am not sure where he is getting that figure from. Cory?) That's a really big cult! Maybe we should try to get Creative Commons added to the recognised religions at the next &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.census.abs.gov.au/websitedbs/d3310114.nsf/Home/census&quot;&gt;ABS Census&lt;/a&gt;?!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;SIDE NOTE:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Grant highlights my comments about Doctorow as a case study. Doctorow's his prior net identity and fame made it far easier for him to push his novel out than other, totally unknown writers will. CC facilitated the distribution and reuse from a copyright management point of view for sure, but it was Doctorow's charisma that propelled it forward. This is the same argument I make as to why the user-specifies-value &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Rainbows&quot;&gt;Radiohead album &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;In Rainbows&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/a&gt;worked for them but it is doubtful it would for an emerging band.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant later says he doubts that if Doctorow get's as famous as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jkrowling.com/&quot;&gt;J K Rowling&lt;/a&gt; that \ he would still be giving his books away for free. Well Doctorow isn't that famous yet, but he is still quite famous (more so than both Grant and I anyway :p). And how many books is that under CC now Cory? Oh that's right, &lt;a href=&quot;http://craphound.com/stories.php&quot;&gt;five&lt;/a&gt;, all CC licensed. According to Doctorow,&quot;[His] books have outsold [his] publisher's expectations&quot; and the sales of colleagues of similar skill and career status. He also says that there isn't a single writer (that he knows anyway) &quot;Who has tried this and hasn't done it again.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I like Cory's comment:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;I think that Ms Rowling would be well advised to try it. Is there anyone here who really believes that no one would have picked up Harry Potter and the Sequel of Great Profitability if they'd gotten a free electronic copy. That what was driving people to the store at midnight in costume was the fact that they couldn't lay hands on a digital copy. Indeed, there was a digital copy, 24 hours before that book hit the stands. The $20 million spent on secrecy for that book was not only ineffective at secrecy, but as best understood as a marketing effort.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;END SIDE NOTE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CC is also a dog's breakfast to Grant, who says, there's &quot;Really good, quality material, of course like Cory's, sitting along side and mixed up with amateur, unreadable crap.&quot; He then proceeds to tout &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewkeen.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Andrew Keen&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Cult-Amateur-Internet-Killing-Culture/dp/0385520808&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Cult of the Amateur&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; rhetoric, which basically says we're becoming more stupid because anyone can post stuff online. Pffft, elitist wank if ever i heard it. So much for new technologies democratising information production. Not if these guys had the final word. I prefer the Robin Sloan and Matt Thompson's theory in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robinsloan.com/epic/&quot;&gt;EPIC 2014&lt;/a&gt; which will see individuals filtering content and managing their information intake (which is of course already happening).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The podcast also tackles the quashing of creative innovation that happens in a permissions culture. in my forthcoming documentary paper there is an entire section devoted to this syndrome but you can read a bit on it &lt;a href=&quot;http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/08/some-thoughts-from-cc-documentary-paper.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Interestingly, Doctorow also takes a freedom of expression argument, saying:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;The fact is that the purpose of copyright is promote the diversity of expression. It's not to pick the best works and ensure they're produced. The last thing any of us want our governments doing is deciding what's good and what's bad and then crafting law to ensure that only the good things get produced. Before copyright we had patronage–you could paint a painting if the Pope said so, you could make a ceiling up if the Duke said so, you could make a sculpture if the King said so–that produced the occasional nice fresco but it was a poor way to manage diversity of expression in a liberal society. The purpose of copyright was to change the arbitures of expression to the marketplace. And that's been a reasonably good diversifier of who gets to speak and under what circumstances, but the internet turns out to be an even better one.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And on the flip side, Grant says that he's worried that Doctorow's 'papal frescos' are not reality, but rather that democratisation of voices is &quot;encouraging mass graffiti.&quot; After all, &quot;that's what's happening on the internet.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Equally amusing is Grant's recommendation that we all read the Australian Copyright Council's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.copyright.org.au/pdf/acc/infosheets_pdf/g094.htm&quot;&gt;fact sheet&lt;/a&gt; on CC. &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;SIDE NOTE:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The fact sheet is factually incorrect in parts and is now out of date!&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;END SIDE NOTE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Grant's five word summary, &quot;Don't sign up too quickly.&quot; I'd make the same argument about publishing contracts, record deals, film production contracts, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.optapra.net/&quot;&gt;APRA&lt;/a&gt; and other royalty collecting arrangements. What are you really giving up and for how long when you enter these relationships? Why didn't you talk about that Grant?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He proceeds to bring up the same arguments always spouted around the irrevocability of CC licences. My response is still the same. If I went out on the street in front of my house right now, and I handed to the first 100 people who passed me a poem I had written, I can hardly come back in a week, a month or 20 years time and demand those 20 people give me back my poem. I'd just look like a madman ranting and raving to no one. Even more accurately, if i went out on the street in front of my house and left 100 copies of that poem on the fence for anyone to take and then went back in side, there is no way i could feasibly demand the poems back post-fact.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Be warned, you run the &quot;risk of being exploited by business professionals,&quot; Grant also cautions. He cites the pending &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7680&quot;&gt;Virgin case&lt;/a&gt; as evidence. Grant's synopsis:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Plenty of egg on the face for the photographer, no income, and Virgin got something for nothing.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If all the photographers were so up in arms at this use of their work, why is only one suing? And not for copyright infringement I might add, which is the part that CC is related to. What is of issue is the need for a model release form. And hey, if the great unwashed amateurs on &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; can &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/groups/central/discuss/72157600541608353/#comment72157600542022693&quot;&gt;tell&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/groups/central/discuss/72157600541608353/#comment72157600611463291&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that a CC attribution licence doesn't imply a release form was signed , they why the hell did Virgin's lawyers? The licence clearly states otherwise (see 5. Representations, Warranties and Disclaimer &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/legalcode&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So Grant then continues on, hypothetically asking himself if copyright will remain unchanged. &quot;No,&quot; he answers. And will people still be paying for things they really want? He says yes. I say it depends. The 'apple + c' syndrome makes it easy to get content at a reasonable enough quality to be contented. And as Doctorow says:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;...it is wildly implausable that as the year's tick by in this century it is going to get progressively harder to copy. Say what you will about the morals of downloading work, the real politic of downloading work is that it's already practically impossible to exclude someone from a collection of bits, and that impossibility will only increase as the year's tick by.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is only if the user's (emotional/cultural) investment in that content is deeper than a general interest that they will turn that into economic investment and buy the same thing. Besides, sampling work can lead to sales. As Doctorow says, &quot;It's a really rare, bookish person who would say, &quot;Well having been given all these all these free electronic texts, the last thing i need now is a printed work,&quot; after all, even I, who spends every hour god sends reading off a screen, don't like reading long-form works off of screen.&quot; He argues that self-discipline drives people off-screen (you've probably already been distracted three times by a new item in your RSS reader, a new email in your Inbox, a quick check of your fav social networking website and countless messages on an IM program), but I think it is more than that. It is hard to be comfortable in front of your computer to watch a feature film or a read a 200 page book. He argues that of the e-books he has, they are more of an enticement to pull down the real-world copy than a substitute for the bookshelf volume.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The CC explanation is very good. Jessica comes across very clear, concise and articulates the licensing model very well.&lt;br /&gt; All and all the entire podcast is very balanced. I think i might cut it up and reuse it in some of my presentations. With the ABC's permission of course :p&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;END POINT: I notice that the podcast is all rights reserved copyrighted by the ABC, but fails to attribute CC for the parts of the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://support.creativecommons.org/videos#gc&quot;&gt;Get Creative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; video they used.&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 02:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elliott Bledsoe: doctorow in australia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-141545364547446786</guid>
	<link>http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/09/cory-doctorow-well-known-well-travelled.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://craphound.com/&quot;&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, the well-known, well-travelled, CC &lt;a href=&quot;http://craphound.com/stories.php&quot;&gt;sci-fi author&lt;/a&gt;, was in Australia recently, and while he was here he stopped into &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/rn&quot;&gt;Radio National&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au&quot;&gt;ABC&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/rn/bookshow/stories/2007/2039471.htm&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; to Sarah L'Estrange about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/2006/11/30/cory-doctorow-copyright-tech-media_cz_cd_books06_1201doctorow.html&quot;&gt;giving it away&lt;/a&gt;. His books that is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The blurb states:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Since the 19th century copyright has served to protect the rights of authors. But has this protection become a hindrance to creativity? Supporters of creative commons licenses say the pendulum has swung too far towards protectionism, and that this is affecting our creative culture.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I missed in unfortunately. Sounds like it would have been a good interview. Anyone know if it's available online anywhere?&lt;div class=&quot;blogger-post-footer&quot;&gt;the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 01:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Joi Ito: Life and death on the Tokyo metro</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4720</guid>
	<link>http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/21/life_and_death_on_the_tokyo_metro.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/1465289559/&quot; title=&quot;Shibuya Toyoko Line by Joi, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1088/1465289559_9e3257d8bf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shibuya Toyoko Line&quot; height=&quot;336&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
I ended the work day with a study group and an expert guest where we discussed the Japanese legal system. Although there were some small signs of hope, I find that the more I learn about how things really work, the more pessimistic I get about causing actual change in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I pondered the futility of revolutionary activities in Japan, I jogged to try to catch the train to connect to the commuter train for my 1.5 hr shlep back to my home. As I entered the station, I noticed an unusually large crowd of people on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PA system announced a delay due to an accident. Japan has over 30,000 suicides a year (one of the highest rates in the world) and 800 or so of them as a result of “train accidents”. As I crammed myself into the standing-room-only train full of drunken businessmen, tired “office ladies” and shriveled old people, I thought about what kind of person might have jumped in front of the train this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approached the station where the accident occurred, the train came to a stop and the conductor apologized again for the delay. They shut down the motors as we waited and the everyone was silent and still. As I looked around at the tired people with their blank looks, it felt like we were all involuntarily mourning the death of another person in Japanese society who had to give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at at my home train station, Mizuka was there to pick me up. I shared my depressing thoughts and she scolded me for being so down. When we got home, our dog Pookie yapped away and almost blew these thoughts away, but I decided to share them with you anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

		

		&lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/21/life_and_death_on_the_tokyo_metro.html#comments&quot; title=&quot;Comment&quot;&gt;Comment&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/21/life_and_death_on_the_tokyo_metro.html#trackbacks&quot; title=&quot;Trackback&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 22:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mike Linksvayer: Semantic Web Web Web</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/21/semantic-www/</guid>
	<link>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/21/semantic-www/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web_Consortium&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;World Wide Web Consortium&lt;/a&gt; and particularly its &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;Semantic Web&lt;/a&gt; efforts do great, valuable work. I have one massive complaint, particularly about the latter: they ignore the Web at their peril. Yes, it’s true, as far as I can tell (but mind that I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://benlog.com/&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://yergler.net/blog/&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; steps removed from actually working on the problems), that the W3C and Semantic Web activities do not appreciate the importance of nor dedicate appropriate resources to the Web. Not just the theoretical Web of URIs, but the Web that billions of people use and see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m reminded of this by Ian Davis’ post &lt;a href=&quot;http://iandavis.com/blog/2007/11/is-the-semantic-web-destined-to-be-a-shadow&quot;&gt;Is the Semantic Web Destined to be a Shadow?&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My belief is that trust must be considered far earlier and that it largely comes from usage and the wisdom of the crowds, not from technology. Trust is a social problem and the best solution is one that involves people making informed judgements on the metadata they encounter. To make an effective evaluation they need to have the ability to view and explore metadata with as few barriers as possible. In practice this means that the web of data needs to be as accessible and visible as the web of documents is today and it needs to interweave transparently. A separate, dry, web of data is unlikely to attract meaningful attention, whereas one that is a full part of the visible and interactive web that the majority of the population enjoys is far more likely to undergo scrutiny and analysis. This means that HTML and RDF need to be much more connected than many people expect. In fact I think that the two should never be separate and it’s not enough that you can publish RDF documents, you need to publish visible, browseable and &lt;em&gt;engaging&lt;/em&gt; RDF that is meaningful to people. Tabular views are a weak substitute for a rich, readable description.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 22:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Netherlands: Auteursrecht bedreigt bibliotheken</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://creativecommons.nl/2007/11/21/auteursrecht-bedreigt-bibliotheken/</guid>
	<link>http://creativecommons.nl/2007/11/21/auteursrecht-bedreigt-bibliotheken/</link>
		<category>nl</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Zo voelt het in elk geval voor de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fobid.nl&quot;&gt;FOBID Netherlands Library Forum&lt;/a&gt;. Het landelijke samenwerkingsverband van Nederlandse bibliotheekorganisaties presenteerde op 15 november het Manifest ‘Auteursrecht in Balans’. Het Manifest is een oproep om informatie toegankelijk te houden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De bibliotheken maken zich steeds meer zorgen over de koers die (internationaal) gevaren wordt met betrekking tot auteursrecht. Digitalisering biedt uitgelezen mogelijkheden om informatie op nieuwe manieren te ontsluiten en te gebruiken. Maar de lobby naar de politiek lijkt juist de richting uit te gaan van meer beperkingen voor (her)gebruik. De bibliotheken willen daar nu een vuist tegen maken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het Manifest is &lt;a href=&quot;http://sitegenerator.bibliotheek.nl/fobid/overig46/overig46.asp?item=165698&amp;amp;NewsID165698=10923&quot;&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt; te vinden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 16:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Spain: Jornada Albedrío: Por una Cultura Libre</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://es.creativecommons.org/blog/index.php/2007/11/20/jornada-albedrio-por-una-cultura-libre/</guid>
	<link>http://es.creativecommons.org/blog/index.php/2007/11/19/jornada-albedrio-por-una-cultura-libre/</link>
		<category>es</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;El próximo 24 de noviembre se celebra la Jornada ” &lt;a href=&quot;http://albedrio.blogsite.org/&quot;&gt;Albedrío: Por una Cultura Libre&lt;/a&gt; ” en la sala Sagarra de l’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ateneubcn.org/web/continguts/ca/index.html&quot;&gt;Ateneu Barcelonès&lt;/a&gt;.  La jornada se organiza en diferentes charlas y debates que empezarán a las 10 de la mañana y terminarán a las 7 de la tarde. Por la noche habrá una fiesta &lt;em&gt;copyleft&lt;/em&gt; en el Bar Arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El propósito de la jornada es debatir sobre el libre flujo de la información en la nueva era digital con el lema: ¿Se están excediendo las entidades de gestión de derechos de autor?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 13:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Japan: iSummit2008開催とアンケートのお知らせ</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.jp/news/2007/11/20/isummit2008.html</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.jp/news/2007/11/20/isummit2008.html</link>
		<category>jp</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;   年に一度、世界中のクリエイティブ・コモンズ関係者やオープンな情報流通を応援する人たちが一堂に会し、最先端のフリーカルチャーについて多角的に検討する国際会議「iSummit」。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 13:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CC Japan: 学生インターン募集のお知らせ</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.creativecommons.jp/news/2007/11/20/post_37.html</guid>
	<link>http://www.creativecommons.jp/news/2007/11/20/post_37.html</link>
		<category>jp</category>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;＊大学生（学部・院生）を中心としたインターンシッププログラムの参加者の募集です。&lt;br /&gt;
＊所属中のインターンは、各々の興味関心や技能に応じて、様々なプロジェクトに参加しています。詳細は&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.creativecommons.jp/about/&quot;&gt;こちら&lt;/a&gt;をご覧下さい。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 12:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Carolina Botero: La tv pública alemana: ¡licencia con CC!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=295</guid>
	<link>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=295</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Por la lsita de&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icommons.org&quot;&gt; icommons&lt;/a&gt; nos informa Meike Richter (traduzco):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;El NDR (Nort German broadcasting station, parte de ARD, la estación pública alemana) empieza a usar Creative Commons para dos de sus espectáculos. Este proyecto durará 6 meses, si funciona bien continuará.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norddeutscher_Rundfunk&quot;&gt;más información sobre NDR&lt;/a&gt; y su &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/www.ndr.de&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los espectáculos de TV que participan son:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ndr.de/extra3&quot;&gt;Extra 3&lt;/a&gt;, a political comdy show.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ndr.de/zapp&quot;&gt;Zapp&lt;/a&gt;, a critical media magazine.&lt;br /&gt;
Algunos clips seleccionados de estos espectáculos serán licenciados con CC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El enlace al especial sobre &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.ndr.de/ratgeber/technik/creativecommonsindex2.html&quot;&gt;cc/NDR&lt;/a&gt; (en alemán) y el enlace al &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.ndr.de/unternehmen/presse/pressemitteilungen/pressemeldungndr934.html&quot;&gt;comunicado de prensa oficial&lt;/a&gt; (en alemán).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 11:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
