<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:planet="http://planet.intertwingly.net/" xmlns:indexing="urn:atom-extension:indexing" indexing:index="no"><access:restriction xmlns:access="http://www.bloglines.com/about/specs/fac-1.0" relationship="deny"/>
  <title>CC Interesting People</title>
  <updated>2007-12-21T00:07:37Z</updated>
  <generator uri="http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/">Venus</generator>
  <author>
    <name>Blogs by people who write about CC topics, including people affiliated with CC or jurisdiction projects.  To be included a blog must minimally be under a CC license and contain all highly relevant posts or be able to provide a feed of all highly relevant posts (e.g., a category feed).  Contact webmaster@creativecommons.org if you know of a blog that should be included.</name>
  </author>
  <id>http://localhost/cc/planet/www/people/atom.xml</id>
  <link href="http://localhost/cc/planet/www/people/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="http://localhost/cc/planet/www/people/" rel="alternate"/>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=305</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=305" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Algunas noticias para el fin de año</title>
    <summary>Se acaba el 2007, gracias a todos los que han seguido este espacio. Llegamos al final del año, y como preámbulo a unas vacaciones quiero dejarles algunos enlaces y comentarios para seguir:
- Concurso de Hojas de Estilo CSS Internet para rendición de cuentas en los municipios colombianos: “El Programa Agenda de Conectividad del Ministerio de [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Se acaba el 2007, gracias a todos los que han seguido este espacio. Llegamos al final del año, y como preámbulo a unas vacaciones quiero dejarles algunos enlaces y comentarios para seguir:</p>
<p>- <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">Concurso de Hojas de Estilo CSS Internet para rendición de cuentas en los municipios colombianos</a>: “El Programa Agenda de Conectividad del Ministerio de Comunicaciones, la Corporación Transparencia por Colombia, Colnodo, la Fundación para la Participación Ciudadana –Parcomún- (en Norte de Santander) y la Fundación Visión y Gestión Ingeniería Social (en Caldas), con el apoyo de la Agencia de Cooperación Alemana -GTZ-, están interesados en adelantar el desarrollo de nuevas hojas de estilo con el fin de ampliar las posibilidades de diseño gráfico para los sitios de los municipios, conservando la estructura de navegación y los estándares de accesibilidad Web que actualmente utilizan los sitios”. Se pide que los diseños sean presentados con una licencia Creative Commons, más información <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">en el sitio web</a>.</p>
<p>- La Universidad Nacional de Colombia, la Dirección Nacional de Servicios Académicos Virtuales junto con la Fundación Karisma realizarán el “Conversatorio sobre Educación Virtual Mòvil, Uso y aplicación de dispositivos móviles en la educación virtual”, se llevará a cabo el 22 de enero de 2008 en el Centro de Convenciones Alfonso López Pumarejo (Auditorio Anexo A, Trans 38 No. 40-04), entrada libre asì que los esperamos por allì. Más información.</p>
<p>- En Holanda es el ministerio de Hacienda el que en su Congreso ha adoptado un plan para migrar el sector público hacia los estándares abiertos y se insta al sector a que use software libre donde sea posible. En adelante deberán justificar por qué usan software privativo), la noticia es muy interesante y se puede ampliar <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">aquí</a>.</p>
<p>- En España hay un evento que paraliza el mundo juvenil y tecnológico, se trata de <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">Campus Party</a>, un lugar en el que por una semana (con sus noches y días) se reunen cientos de jóvenes que llevan sus equipos para disfrutar de la experiencia de una conectividad a velocidades increíbles y experimentar actividades, conferencias y personas en torno a temas de interés vinculados con la tecnología (astronomía, juegos, robotica…). Bueno, la noticia es que en el 2008 este evento se llevará a cabo también <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">en Brasil</a> (febrero) y <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">en Colombia</a> (junio) y… que yo estaré a cargo de “<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero">campus blog</a>”, así que: ¿nos vemos allí?</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-20T22:02:03Z</updated>
    <category term="Evento"/>
    <category term="Software libre"/>
    <category term="Licencias copyleft"/>
    <category term="General"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3478</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/sunlight_help_on_a_distributed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Sunlight: Help on a distributed research project</title>
    <summary>The Sunlight Foundation has launched a distributed research project. The aim is to learn what happened to former members of Congress and staffers after the 1 year "cooling off" period has come to the end (and thus, they can go work for lobbyists). Using a very cool interface, you can help track down former staffers, and add the results to the research database. Begin here.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Sunlight Foundation has launched a distributed research project. The aim is to learn what happened to former members of Congress and staffers after the 1 year "cooling off" period has come to the end (and thus, they can go work for lobbyists). Using a very cool interface, you can help track down former staffers, and add the results to the research database. Begin <a href="http://wherearetheynow.sunlightprojects.org/">here</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-20T18:33:11Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Corruption"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3476</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/from_cckorea.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>from ccKorea</title>
    <summary>wow.

wow indeed.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center/>

wow indeed.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-20T14:54:46Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-20T14:52:11Z</published>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3475</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/wired_science_final_episodes_o.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Wired Science -- final episodes of the season</title>
    <summary>So as an iTunes subscriber to Wired Science, I'm a bit biased here.  But you can get Wired Science for free tonight and next week -- last two episodes of this season -- on broadcast TV (PBS).</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center/>

<p>So as an iTunes subscriber to Wired Science, I'm a bit biased here.  But you can get Wired Science for free tonight and next week -- last two episodes of this season -- on broadcast TV (PBS).

</p><center><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/wiredscience_enewsletter_ep110.jpg"><img alt="wiredscience_enewsletter_ep110.jpg" height="500" src="http://lessig.org/blog/wiredscience_enewsletter_ep110-thumb.jpg" width="222"/></a><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/wiredscience_enewsletter_ep9.jpg"><img alt="wiredscience_enewsletter_ep9.jpg" height="500" src="http://lessig.org/blog/wiredscience_enewsletter_ep9-thumb.jpg" width="247"/></a></center></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-19T23:27:41Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-19T22:57:26Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="good code"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-6770814992177447989</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/12/ccau-bbq-bash-breakdown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=6770814992177447989" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/6770814992177447989/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6770814992177447989" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/6770814992177447989" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>ccau BBQ bash breakdown</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://bp1.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R2mVhc395uI/AAAAAAAAAD8/OVj_MVIgZlU/s1600-h/2113441767_4939dc4fe4_o.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5145808451166660322" src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R2mVhc395uI/AAAAAAAAAD8/OVj_MVIgZlU/s320/2113441767_4939dc4fe4_o.jpg" style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand;"/></a><br/><div style="text-align: center;">Image: <i><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pamrosengren/2113441767/in/pool-ccaustralia/">birthday cakes</a></i>  by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pamrosengren/">Pam Rosengren</a><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/deed.en"> <img src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/3.0/80x15.png"/></a><br/></div><br/>Aww our little CC is growing up so fast. The CCau BBQ Bash to celebrate the community's <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Birthday_Party">5th birthday</a> was great! There was a good turn out, it was a lovely day, and the champagne flowed as free as culture should!<div><br/></div><div>Thank you to everyone who made it on the day. A HUGE thank you to Jessica and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/felix42/">Rachel</a> from the CCau office for getting it all going. And to <a href="http://www.law.qut.edu.au/staff/lsstaff/fitzgerald.jsp">Brian</a> and <a href="http://www.tils.qut.edu.au/about/officeofthed/tomcochrane.jsp">Tom Cochrane</a>, the CCau Project Leads. <a href="http://nic.suzor.com">Nic</a>, thank you to you as well, for coming even though it was the day before you left. The CCau office wishes you and Kylie all the best in Canada. They aren't gonna know what hit them.</div><div><br/></div><div><a href="http://andy.brisgeek.com/">Andy</a> from Redhat, thanks for (personally) bringing beer and for brining along the Redhat swag. May we do more with you and your org in the future.</div><div><br/></div><div>More thank yous, now to <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pamrosengren/">Pam</a> and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/asnightfollowsday/">Steve</a> for taking photos. And again to Steve for regularly filling my glass (:D). And thank you to all those who would have if they could. It is a rare thing to be involved with a community with such passion and drive, and it remains an honour to work in that community. Check out more photos from the BBQ in the <a href="http://www.flickr.com/groups/ccaustralia/pool/">CCau photo pool</a>.</div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-19T22:29:28Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-15T07:02:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau photo pool"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau events"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-406032457235633744</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/09/virgin-case-why-cc-is-and-should-always.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=406032457235633744" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/406032457235633744/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/406032457235633744" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/406032457235633744" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>The Virgin case: why CC is (and should always be) just a copyright licence</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div>There's been a lot of talk/confusion/opinions around the case lodged <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/complaint.pdf">against</a> the Creative Commons international corporation, Virgin Mobile Australia and its American parent company, Virgin Mobile USA. Yes, CC has been sued, but not because of anything in the licences themselves per se, but rather what isn't in the licences.</div><div><br/></div><div>I don't want to go to deep into the detail of the matter. Lawrence Lessig has <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html">provided</a> a detailed overview of the matter which you should read if you are interested in know more. Also have a look at the CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7680">FAQ</a> on the matter. But in summary, Virgin Mobile Australia ran an advertising campaign called <a href="http://www.areyouwithusorwhat.com.au/">Are you with us or what?</a> which used a whole stack of images under the generic CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">Attribution 2.0</a> licences. The images were all from Yahoo's photo-publishing website, <a href="http://flickr.com/">Flickr</a>. [Not sure what I am on about? click <a href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/07/virgin-australia-uses-cc-images.html">here</a>]</div><div><br/></div><div>Now the case against CC and Virgin is actually not a copyright matter. As I said in my <a href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/07/virgin-australia-uses-cc-images.html">previous post</a> when the campaign started, because the licence was Attribution only, Virgin were permitted to make commerical reuse of the images. All the people saying that the photographers should have been paid have missed the point of that licence. Virgin <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;"><u>could</u></span> have paid the photographers if they liked, but there was <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;"><u>no legal obligation</u></span> to do so. So let's shove that to one side, because as far as I am concerned, that is a non-issue.</div><div><br/></div><div>Onto the meat of the matter: one of the photos reused by Virgin was an image of Alison Chang (a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minor_%28law%29">minor at law</a>)</div><div>who had been photographed by Justin Wong, who CC licensed the photo on Flickr. Virgin Mobile Australia reused the image in the Are you with us or what? campaign. The reuse included the overlaying of a slogan–dump your pen friend–along with the campaign slogan 'Are you with us or what?' and Virgin Mobile branding.</div><div><br/></div><div>The matter consists of a claim by the parents of Alison Chang (on her behalf) that the use was a breach of their daughter's right to privacy. The photographer is also arguing that CC  failed “to adequately educate and warn him … of the meaning of commercial use and the ramifications and effects of entering into a license allowing such use.”</div><div><br/></div><div>Firstly I want to say that I think the case against CC is weak. There is lots of information about the licences available on the CC website's <a href="http://creativecommons.org/about/">About section </a>including an <a href="http://creativecommons.org/about/license/">overview</a> of the standard licensing suite, a <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Before_Licensing">list</a> of things to think about before licensing you works, a detailed <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/FAQ">FAQ</a>, number of mailing lists, a <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Legal_Concepts">discussion</a> of the main legal concepts and various media (<a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Comics">comics</a> and <a href="http://creativecommons.org/about/ccvideos/">videos</a>) which explain aspects of the licensing model.</div><div><br/></div><div>If anything, they should have been arguing that Flickr should have been providing more information, since it was Yahoo who was publishing the image, not Creative Commons. I'm not too interested in whether a claim against Yahoo would stand up, but they do provide information on their site about CC including a brief summary of each type of licence and a link (on the right of the CC interface of the website) to the CC international website which provides all the information I listed above. If the user defines a CC licence as a default copyright licence when publishing on Flickr, information is listed under where you select your licence. When CC is set as a default for new uploaded images, and the image is published, on the right of that image's page it states 'Some Rights Reserved' followed by an option to change the licence on that particular image. At the bottom line, CC simply provides licences, how other people/organisations use them is up to them.</div><div><br/></div><div>So on the issue of model releases: CC licences are copyright only. As such, copyright hasn't been breached in this matter as so the matter does not (overtly) implicate the CC licence. The plaintiff is of course suing for breach of privacy. It is a well understood industry standard supported by the <a href="http://www.alliance.org">MEAA</a> that model clearances be sought when using images of other people, but where does it stand at law? My colleagues and I did some looking around to determine if model release forms are in fact required under Australian law. To date the only thing we've discovered that is of consideration is <a href="http://www.austlii.edu.au/au/legis/cth/consol_act/tpa1974149/s53.html">Section 53</a> of the Australian Federal <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">Trade Practices Act</span> 1974 which  prohibits commercial conduct that misleads or deceives consumers into thinking a particular person is affiliated with or has purchase a particular product. <a href="http://www.austlii.edu.au/cgi-bin/sinodisp/au/cases/qld/QSC/1996/34.html?query=talmax">Case law</a> on the matter involves people who are a celebrity or are well known to the public, where consumers were clearly mislead into believing that person had endorse the product. As my colleagues Jessica Coates and Emma Carroll <a href="http://icommons.org/articles/virgin-mobile-asleep-on-the-job">said</a>, "These ads, with their deliberate 'amateur' style and sarcastic bylines, don't really imply endorsement – if anything, they make it clear that the person is an unwitting participant in the joke."</div><div><br/></div><div>This is of course probably why the plaintiffs are suing in America, based on the argument that the image was published world wide when the media and bloggers became interested in the campaign. I admit I am not hugely knowledgeable in American privacy law, but I suspect that the disclaimer in the licence would apply here:</div><div><blockquote><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">5. Representations, Warranties and Disclaimer</span><br/><br/>UNLESS OTHERWISE MUTUALLY AGREED TO BY THE PARTIES IN WRITING, LICENSOR OFFERS THE WORK AS-IS AND MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND CONCERNING THE WORK...</blockquote>To the extent that it would include that no assertion that model releases have been cleared is made under the CC licence. Perhaps if the photographer gave an additional assertion on a webpage or by some other means that may stand up, but prima facie the licence does not claim to include a warranty that a model clearance has been gained.</div><div><br/>But I do want to say that I feel that the Commons Deed should have more information, such as the fact that periphery rights are not necessarily cleared. I say this because, despite being clearly articulated in the Legal Code, most users or CC content will probably never read the full licence. [Although I think it is very reasonable to have expected a large commercial entity such as Virgin to read it]. And isn't that the whole idea? We are aiming to create an easy-to-use/understand licensing model that doesn't require you to have a lawyer/be a lawyer. Expecting everyone to read the licence flies in the face of that aim. As Nic Suzor said on the Creative Commons Community list: </div><div><blockquote>I am wary of statements which could be seen to be misleading or deceptive. An argument could be raised (and I'm not saying that it would necessarily be correct) that the photographer, by saying "you can use this image commercially", is not being sufficiently clear that the permission only applies to copyright.</blockquote></div><div>So I think a short statement stating that CC licences apply to the copyright in the work only, and do not apply to other rights that may be vested in the work. </div><div><br/></div>Realistically, the plaintiffs have a case against Virgin. How strong that case is is anyone's bet. We'll just have to wait and see what the court says. But as a final point, Virgin's lawyers should have known better and sought the additional permissions.<br/><div><br/></div><div>On the issue, I highly recommend you read <a href="http://icommons.org/articles/virgin-mobile-asleep-on-the-job">"Virgin Mobile Asleep on the Job"</a> written by my colleagues Jessica Coates and Emma Carroll on the iCommons website.</div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-19T07:05:11Z</updated>
    <published>2007-09-27T00:25:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="jessica coates"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="virgin mobile case"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Flickr"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="emma carroll"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="nic suzor"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CC BY"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-7832971758686797573</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/07/virgin-australia-uses-cc-images.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=7832971758686797573" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/7832971758686797573/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/7832971758686797573" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/7832971758686797573" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>Virgin Australia uses CC images</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week <a href="http://www.virginmobile.com.au/">Virgin Moblie Australia</a> released a new advertising campaign called <a href="http://www.areyouwithusorwhat.com/">Are you with us or what?</a> which is using CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">Attribution 2.0</a> images off <a href="http://flickr.com/">Flickr</a>. Each image in the campaign presents a caption, followed by the campaign slogan 'Are you with us or what?' and a 'Yes' and 'No' option. The idea is that visitors to the site click through whether they agree with the caption. Once you select your answer, that image slide off screen and new image in the grid of images moved to the centre of your screen. And so the process continues...<div><br/></div><div>Despite the <a href="http://flickr.com/groups/central/discuss/72157600541608353/">murmurings</a> around the campaign, I think it is great to see an Australian example of where CC material is being reused on a large scale by a commercial entity. People are saying that the photographers should have been paid, but the photographers had made a decision to release their image for commerical reuse without remuneration to them (the <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/legalcode">licence</a> states it is a "royalty-free" licence). There is at least one <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/qole/197513122">example</a> where a photograph has openly admitted that he is glad his image was used regardless of not being paid. Virgin were allowed under  the licence to reuse these images for commercial purposes.<div><br/></div><div>That said, I personally am iffy about whether or not they have sufficed the attribution term. The <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/legalcode">licence</a> states:</div><div><blockquote>"If you distribute, publicly display, publicly perform, or publicly digitally perform the Work or any Derivative Works or Collective Works, You must keep intact all copyright notices for the Work and give the Original Author credit reasonable to the medium or means..."</blockquote>It qualifies credit by saying:<br/><blockquote>Licensees should credit "...by conveying the name (or pseudonym if applicable) of the Original Author if supplied; the title of the Work if supplied; to the extent reasonably practicable, the Uniform Resource Identifier, if any, that Licensor specifies to be associated with the Work, unless such URI does not refer to the copyright notice or licensing information for the Work; and in the case of a Derivative Work, a credit identifying the use of the Work in the Derivative Work (e.g., "French translation of the Work by Original Author," or "Screenplay based on original Work by Original Author"). Such credit may be implemented in any reasonable manner; provided, however, that in the case of a Derivative Work or Collective Work, at a minimum such credit will appear where any other comparable authorship credit appears and in a manner at least as prominent as such other comparable authorship credit."</blockquote>On the Are you with us or not? website each image that is used includes in the bottom left-hand corner the Flickr username of the photographer. That username links through to their photo stream on Flickr. Why I don't think this goes far enough to fulfill the attribution term:</div><div><ul id=""><li>It does not specify anywhere on the site (that I could find anyway) what type of licence the images were under;<br/></li><li>It does not specify the title of any of the photographs that were titled;</li><li>It does not link back to the unique URL of the image itself, but rather links to the photographer's photo stream; and</li><li>It does not specify the website is a derivative work of the originals (the placing of graphical elements on top of an image is a derivative).</li></ul><div>How hard would it have really been for Virgin to add in that extra information and link it to the image, not just the Flickr account? I think it is reasonable that given how easy it is to direct a hyperlink to a specified website, and that they had provided some information and a link already, that they could have easily provided better attribution. I also think they should have specified along the bottom of the website 'Images on this website are licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 2.0 licence' which would have sufficed the need for them to present the licence type.</div></div><div><br/>Also of note, at least one photo was under a Non-Commercial licence [Admitantly I am unsure whether it was under a broader licence before the campaign blew up]. Equally, another appears to be under a ShareAlike licence but no such ShareAlike option on the billboards.<br/><br/></div><div><div>On the issue, I highly recommend you read <a href="http://icommons.org/articles/virgin-mobile-asleep-on-the-job">"Virgin Mobile Asleep on the Job"</a> written by my colleagues Jessica Coates and Emma Carroll on the iCommons website.</div></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-19T06:55:53Z</updated>
    <published>2007-07-22T03:40:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Flickr"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="advertising"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CC BY"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-7450708574048344337</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/12/ccau-commoners-audiophile.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=7450708574048344337" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/7450708574048344337/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/7450708574048344337" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/7450708574048344337" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>CCau commoners :: audiophile</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over the past three years that CC has been in Australia, more and more Australian-based projects have been emerging. The <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccclinic">ccClinic</a> and <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/research">CC + OCL Research</a> Projects have of course been mapping the adoption of CC domestically and internationally, but I am going to feature some of them here.<div><br/><div><a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5145493874876999362" src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R2h3as395sI/AAAAAAAAADs/xB66FSnR2jM/s200/audiophilebanner.jpg" style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand;"/></a><a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5145483300667516594" src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R2htzM395rI/AAAAAAAAADk/0Bh8R8QApLk/s200/audiophile.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 10px 10px; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand;"/></a></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">project: </span>Audiophile</div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">type:</span> repository</div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">media/medium:</span> audio</div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">website:</span> <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/">www.audiophile.org.au</a></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">licensing framework:</span> content is under a CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/au/">BY-NC-SA 2.5 Aus</a> licence, blanket licensed</div><div><br/></div><div>The first project I want to feature is <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/">Audiophile</a>: an online repository of a range of exciting sound bites which are available under an Australian CC Attribution Non-Commercial ShareAlike <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/au/">licence</a>. It includes such tasty treats as field recordings"social documentaries, audio essays, cultural features and radio plays ... audio postcards and experimental sound design." Submissions that address topics such as social justice, environment, indigenous issues, popular culture, music and the arts as well as experimental sound design or drama.</div><div><br/>You can navigate content on the site by <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/?cat=1">category</a>, <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/?cat=3">genre</a> or the <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/?cat=4">producer</a> who submitted the work. You can of course search for keywords in the search bar as well.</div><div><br/>The site set up with the aim to provide opportunities for emerging media producers to showcase their audio works. Although the site doesn't have a huge amount of works on it yet, it has the potential to host loads more. So if you're a media producer and looking for somewhere to host your audio works, check out <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/">Audiophile</a>.</div><div><br/></div><div>I am very please to see that the site not only specifies that (unless otherwise expressly noted) all works are under the CC licence (with a link to the Commons Deed), but that they also replicate the text of the Deed on their <a href="http://www.audiophile.org.au/?page_id=3">own site</a>. This is good practice, because it ensures that contributors are aware of the terms of contribution before they upload content.</div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-19T01:53:55Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-19T00:37:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="licensing frameworks"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CC BY-NC-SA"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CCau commoners"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Aus 2.5 licences"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="open music"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc music"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="audiophile"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="licensing best practice"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="blanket licensing"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3474</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/on_what_exactly_happened_satur.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>On what exactly happened Saturday night</title>
    <summary>Flickr: fumi: 


So as you know, this weekend CC celebrated its fifth birthday. In parties in Beijing, Berlin,  Manila, Seoul, Belgrade, Brisbane, New York, Bangalore, Los Angeles, and San Francisco, thousands of CC supporters got together to remember the last five years, and get a peek of the next five. (Flickr stream).

I was in San Francisco at  an extraordinary event at which Gilberto Gil and his son, Bem, and DJ Spooky performed. During my talk, I made a bunch of announcements. The key points were these: Current TV will start integrating CC licenses into their citizen created content system.
CC0: On January 15, we will release a beta protocol to support a new tool, "CC0." CC0 will enable two things: (1) a simple, machine readable way to mark work with either a waiver of rights, or an assertion that no rights attach to a particular work, and (2) a simple way to sign that waiver/assertion. The protocol is intended to support use cases where the desire is that no rights attach to some work. E.g., databases in Europe (where the database rights muck up research), or material in the open education movement. Simultaneously with the announcement, Science Commons released its "Open Access Data Protocol," which implements CC0 to support freeing data.
Legal Commons (beta): Taking inspiration from the liberator and manumitter of government documents and legal cases, Carl Malamud, Creative Commons will enter into a joint venture with public.resource.org to collect and make available machine readable copies of government documents and law. Carl and I have committed to freeing all federal case law by the end of 2008. Importantly, this effort will not set up competing systems to the emerging ecology of great free law services (Cornell's LII, or Columbia's Altlaw.org). We instead will help gather and make available the resources those services use to provide their amazing service. So look for a tarball of all federal cases by the end of 2008, in parsable and usable plain text.
CC+: This protocol enables a simple click through ability to get rights or permissions beyond those provided by a CC license. So, e.g., a Flickr photo licensed under a BY-NC license could have a simple click through to some agent to provide commercial rights for that photo. We announced with a bunch of partners already. But really key was: 
Yahoo announced it was baking CC+ "into the system" of Yahoo, making it possible for any Yahoo service to offer content using the CC+ infrastructure.
The Annual Campaign, this year with a $500,000 target, has exceeded its target by almost $40,000. This includes $50,000 contributions from Sun and Microsoft, and a $20,000 contribution from Tim O'Reilly. 
[5x5] Challenge: After Hewlett issued a challenge to find 5 funders to promise 5 years of support at $500,000 a year, we announced pledges to match the commitment: The Hewlett Foundation, Omidyar Network, an (so far) anonymous European trust, Google/Mozilla/Red Hat (3-1-1), and amazingly, our board which promised to personally commit to either raise or contribute $500k/year. This means we've got core funding for 5 more years, and the first time I could breathe easily in more than 5 years.

Stay tuned for more on each. But suffice: it was an amazing night.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2114955426_36bd4327b6_o.jpg"><img alt="2114955426_36bd4327b6_o.jpg" height="266" src="http://lessig.org/blog/2114955426_36bd4327b6_o-thumb.jpg" width="400"/></a></center>
<center><a href="http://Flickr.com">Flickr</a>: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/fumi/">fumi</a>: <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/" rel="license"><img alt="Creative Commons License" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/3.0/80x15.png" style="border-width: 0;"/>
</a></center>

So as <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/big_news_great_party.html">you know</a>, this weekend <a href="http://Creativecommons.org">CC</a> celebrated its fifth birthday. In parties in <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/Birthday_party#Parties">Beijing, Berlin,  Manila, Seoul, Belgrade, Brisbane, New York, Bangalore, Los Angeles, and San Francisco</a>, thousands of CC supporters got together to remember the last five years, and get a peek of the next five. (<a href="http://flickr.com/photos/tags/ccbday5/">Flickr stream</a>).

I was in San Francisco at  an extraordinary event at which <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilberto_Gil">Gilberto Gil</a> and his son, Bem, and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dj_Spooky">DJ Spooky</a> performed. During my talk, I made a bunch of announcements. The key points were these: <ol type="1"><li><b><a href="http://current.com/">Current TV</a></b> will start integrating CC licenses into their citizen created content system.
</li><li><b><a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7920">CC0</a></b>: On January 15, we will release a beta protocol to support a new tool, "CC0." CC0 will enable two things: (1) a simple, machine readable way to mark work with either a waiver of rights, or an assertion that no rights attach to a particular work, and (2) a simple way to sign that waiver/assertion. The protocol is intended to support use cases where the desire is that no rights attach to some work. E.g., databases in Europe (where the database rights muck up research), or material in the open education movement. Simultaneously with the announcement, Science Commons released its "<a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7917">Open Access Data Protocol</a>," which implements CC0 to support freeing data.
</li><li><b>Legal Commons (beta)</b>: Taking inspiration from the liberator and manumitter of government documents and legal cases, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Malamud">Carl Malamud</a>, Creative Commons will enter into a joint venture with <a href="http://public.resource.org">public.resource.org</a> to collect and make available machine readable copies of government documents and law. Carl and I have committed to freeing all federal case law by the end of 2008. Importantly, this effort will not set up competing systems to the emerging ecology of great free law services (<a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/">Cornell's LII</a>, or Columbia's <a href="http://Altlaw.org">Altlaw.org</a>). We instead will help gather and make available the resources those services use to provide their amazing service. So look for a tarball of all federal cases by the end of 2008, in parsable and usable plain text.
</li><li><b><a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7920">CC+</a></b>: This protocol enables a simple click through ability to get rights or permissions beyond those provided by a CC license. So, e.g., a Flickr photo licensed under a BY-NC license could have a simple click through to some agent to provide commercial rights for that photo. We announced with a bunch of partners already. But really key was: 
</li><li><b><a href="http://Yahoo.com">Yahoo</a></b> announced it was baking CC+ "into the system" of Yahoo, making it possible for any Yahoo service to offer content using the CC+ infrastructure.
</li><li>The <b>Annual Campaign</b>, this year with a <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">$500,000 target</a>, has exceeded its target by almost $40,000. This includes $50,000 contributions from <a href="http://Sun.com">Sun</a> and <a href="http://Microsoft.com">Microsoft</a>, and a $20,000 contribution from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tim_O%27Reilly">Tim O'Reilly</a>. 
</li><li><b>[5x5] Challenge</b>: After <a href="http://Hewlett.org">Hewlett</a> issued a challenge to find 5 funders to promise 5 years of support at $500,000 a year, we announced pledges to match the commitment: The <a href="http://hewlett.org">Hewlett Foundation</a>, <a href="http://omidyar.net">Omidyar Network</a>, an (so far) anonymous European trust, <a href="http://Google.com">Google</a>/<a href="http://Mozilla.com">Mozilla</a>/<a href="http://redhat.com">Red Hat</a> (3-1-1), and amazingly, our board which promised to personally commit to either raise or contribute $500k/year. This means we've got core funding for 5 more years, and the first time I could breathe easily in more than 5 years.

Stay tuned for more on each. But suffice: it was an amazing night.</li></ol></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-18T00:49:11Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-17T23:45:20Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=304</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=304" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Science Commons anuncia el protocolo CC0 para bases de datos científicas</title>
    <summary>Desde el blog de CC llega el anuncio del lanzamiento durante el fin de semana del protocolo CCZero, que es un método para asegurar que las bases de datos pueden ser legalmente integradas con otras. Se anuncia como un protocolo que integra varios elementos sobre la base del estatus de dominio público que en algunas [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Desde el <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7917">blog de CC</a> llega el <a href="http://sciencecommons.org/weblog/archives/2007/12/16/announcing-protocol-for-oa-data/">anuncio del lanzamiento</a> durante el fin de semana del <a href="http://sciencecommons.org/projects/publishing/open-access-data-protocol/">protocolo CCZero</a>, que es un método para asegurar que las bases de datos pueden ser legalmente integradas con otras. Se anuncia como un protocolo que integra varios elementos sobre la base del estatus de dominio público que en algunas jurisdicciones tienen los datos que integran las bases de datos. </p>
<p>El tema tiene que ver con la forma como en Europa se asigna el derecho de autor a las bases de datos y la complicación que esto implica para su reutilización en el marco científico. La iniciativa busca recoger los desarrollos o personas que estan trabajando en ese camino en la actualidad. El tema lo he venido siguiendo desde hace algún tiempo pero aun no he revisado con calma el actual protocolo… Se oyen comentarios.</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-17T11:59:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Dominio P&#xFA;blico"/>
    <category term="Redise&#xF1;o de la Propiedad Intelectual"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=303</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=303" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>El que era el proyecto de software libre en el Congreso Colombiano</title>
    <summary>Es difícil resumir lo que sucede con el Proyecto de Ley de Software Libre (021 de 2007) que viene haciendo su curso en el Congreso Colombiano pero al menos dejaré un par de ideas con la esperanza de que no pase desapercibido en nuestro Congreso.
La comunidad de Software Libre intentó en el 2002 pasar un [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Es difícil resumir lo que sucede con el <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Proyecto de Ley 021 de 2007 http://slcolombia.org/Proyecto_de_Ley">Proyecto de Ley de Software Libre (021 de 2007)</a> que viene haciendo su curso en el Congreso Colombiano pero al menos dejaré un par de ideas con la esperanza de que no pase desapercibido en nuestro Congreso.</p>
<p>La comunidad de Software Libre <a href="http://bachue.com/colibri/ley.html">intentó en el 2002</a> pasar un proyecto de ley que apoyara públicamente esta forma de desarrollo en Colombia, este año se retomó esa idea y con el soporte político del MIRA consiguió impulsar una nueva iniciativa legislativa en el Congreso. Del proyecto original no quedó sino el nombre frente al <a href="http://direccion.camara.gov.co/camara/site/artic/20071004/pags/20071004095622.html">texto que está ahora disponible para votación </a>en la Plenaria de la Cámara de Representantes. Efectivamente en la comisión el texto se cambió por uno en que se definen unos principios, se aborda el tema de apropiación de Tecnologías de la Información y las Comunicaciones (TIC) y se aprovecha para ocuparse en varios artículos de COINFO (Comisión Intersectorial de Políticas y de Gestión de la Información para la Administración Pública), sin hacer ninguna referencia al Software Libre, a sus apuestas, ni a sus principios. <a class="more-link" href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=303#more-303">(more…)</a></p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-16T13:41:41Z</updated>
    <category term="Software libre"/>
    <category term="Actualidad"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4740</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/15/my_new_bike.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">My new bike</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">My new bike - Photo copyright Mission Bicycles - CC BY-NC When I read that Zack Rosen and his friends were starting a bike business, I ordered one right away. The basic configuration was $790, but I upgraded the...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mission_bicycles/2108803461/"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2312/2108803461_717a75ca0d.jpg"/></a>
My new bike - Photo copyright Mission Bicycles - <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/">CC BY-NC</a></p>

<p>When I read that Zack Rosen and his friends were <a href="http://www.zacker.org/mission_bicycles">starting a bike business</a>, I ordered one right away. The basic configuration was $790, but I upgraded the headset and crank and paid $850, which seems pretty reasonable. Zack is an old friend and a cool guy and I knew that a bike he was working on would be special. I wasn’t disappointed. I went to their web design studio/bike assembly area and picked up my new bike and rode it back to the hotel today. What a treat.</p>

<p>They’re called <a href="http://missionbicycle.com/">Mission Bicycles</a> and they are open for business now and taking orders. I’ve only taken my around for a few miles so far, but I love it.</p>

<!-- technorati tags start --><p style="text-align: right; font-size: 10px;">Technorati Tags: <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/cycling" rel="tag">cycling</a></p><!-- technorati tags end -->

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/15/my_new_bike.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/15/my_new_bike.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-15T17:03:47Z</published>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4739</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/13/mozilla_japan_get_firefox_video_awards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Mozilla Japan Get Firefox video awards</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">Mozilla Japan is currently running the Get Firefox Video Awards event, an online promotion for Firefox where over 100 Japanese video artists and animators have created some amazing videos to promote Firefox within 30 seconds. This is similar to the...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Mozilla Japan is currently running the <a href="http://getfirefox.jp/video/">Get Firefox Video Awards</a> event, an online promotion for Firefox where over 100 Japanese video artists and animators have created some <a href="http://getfirefox.jp/video/gallery/">amazing videos</a> to promote Firefox within 30 seconds. This is similar to the <a href="http://www.firefoxflicks.com/">Firefox Flicks</a> contest from a few years ago.  I am one of the judges along with Hiroyuki Nakano, Chiaki Hayashi, Andrew Thomas and Chibi Takita of Mozilla Japan.  The party to announce the winners of this event will be on Tuesday, December 18th in Tokyo at <a href="http://www.super-deluxe.com/">Super-Deluxe</a>, starting at 19:30.  The event is free and should be a lot of fun. Not sure if I can make the event myself but it should be a great event and I hope you can go to support some wonderful Japanese artists and creators.  Registration for the event is at the home page of the <a href="http://getfirefox.jp/video/">Get Firefox Video Awards</a>.
		
		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/13/mozilla_japan_get_firefox_video_awards.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/13/mozilla_japan_get_firefox_video_awards.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-13T14:07:06Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-13T14:07:05Z</published>
    <category term="Mozilla"/>
    <category term="Video"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4738</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/14/dopplr_opens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Dopplr opens</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">At LeWeb3, Dopplr announced (the release) that they have officially launched and are now open for registration without invitations. BBC did a nice story. Dopplr is currently my primary way of figuring out where I can meet friends coincidentally because...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>At <a href="http://www.leweb3.com/">LeWeb3</a>, <a href="http://www.dopplr.com/">Dopplr</a> announced (<a href="http://blog.dopplr.com/index.php/2007/12/11/dopplr-launches-at-leweb3-in-paris/">the release</a>) that they have officially launched and are now open for registration without invitations. <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/7139175.stm">BBC did a nice story.</a></p>

<p>Dopplr is currently my primary way of figuring out where I can meet friends coincidentally because it allows me to track where my travels overlap with my friends.</p>

<p>The only problem is that I can’t yet mark what days I’m busy so all of the extra opportunities to meet often stress my already busy scheduling. Personally, I think the net result is that we have more informed choices and opportunity, but we have to build the tools and the social norms for all of this, just like we’re having to develop them for the always-on mobile Internet.</p>

<p>PS I’m an investor in Dopplr.</p>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/14/dopplr_opens.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/14/dopplr_opens.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-13T13:26:54Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-14T05:25:22Z</published>
    <category term="Social Software"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4736</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/12/le_web_3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Le Web 3</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">The second day of Le Web 3 is starting today, but I unfortunately have to leave in a few hours to go to San Francisco to attend the Creative Commons board meeting and the 5th anniversary party later this...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/2105249666/" title="Loic and Geraldine listening to talks at Le Web by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="Loic and Geraldine listening to talks at Le Web" height="336" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2222/2105249666_4baaf8c45c.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>The second day of <a href="http://www.leweb3.com/leweb3/">Le Web 3</a> is starting today, but I unfortunately have to leave in a few hours to go to San Francisco to attend the Creative Commons board meeting and the 5th anniversary party later this week.</p>

<p>Le Web 3 was the best conference of its kind I attended this year. Great venue, great team and awesome speakers. Loic, Geraldine and team, super job. Thanks! Interestingly, my favorite talks were the two non-web people: Hans Rosling and Philippe Starck. Everyone else was great too. Ev gave an thought provoking talk about the importance of less features. (I’ve been thinking about this a lot recently too…) The “Kevin Rose - DIGG in conversation with Sarah Lacy - Author” was funny too. Anyway, I’m not positive, but I assume they will end up online. Worth taking a look. I talked about the World of Warcraft and Creative Commons. Yes. I managed to make a connection. ;-)</p>

<p>The only bad thing that happened to me was my file system melt-down that caused me to lose a bunch of stuff. The conference team was able to get me a copy of Leopard that I installed which allowed me to restore enough of my functionality to do my presentation.</p>

<p>However, as I was messing around around with it this morning, I managed to erase 5 gigs of original RAW images from trip. :-\ I was able to salvage some and have posted them on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/sets/72157603434359638/">a set on Flickr</a>.</p>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/12/le_web_3.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/12/le_web_3.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-12T06:53:33Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-12T03:53:29Z</published>
    <category term="Joi's Diary"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3472</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/doublemint_days.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Doublemint days</title>
    <summary>We're in the final four days of CC's push to complete the CC fundraising campaign by Saturday. Last week we learned that Sun had doubled its contribution from last year. On Friday, our local hero, Tim O'Reilly, doubled his contribution from last year. And today we learned that Microsoft has also doubled its contribution from last year. 

Doublemint yours today. Or singlemint if you've not given before. And if we can push a few more into the bucket, then we call can go back to work!</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We're in the final four days of CC's push to complete the <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">CC fundraising campaign</a> by Saturday. Last week we learned that <a href="http://sun.com">Sun</a> had doubled its contribution from last year. On Friday, our local hero, <a href="http://tim.oreilly.com/">Tim O'Reilly</a>, doubled his contribution from last year. And today we learned that <a href="http://Microsoft.com">Microsoft</a> has also doubled its contribution from last year. 

<a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">Doublemint</a> yours today. Or <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">singlemint</a> if you've not given before. And if we can push a few more into the bucket, then we call can go back to work!</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-11T21:13:58Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-11T20:54:44Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=302</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=302" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>“La ideología de la propiedad intelectual, la inconstitucionalidad de la tutela penal de los derechos patrimoniales de autor”</title>
    <summary>Por allá en el 2005 cuando me encontraba en la recta final de la maestria llegó a mis manos el artículo que da título a este post, me lo dio un amigo brasileño y por su intermedio me contactó con el autor (Tulio Vianna) a quien pude exponer algunas dudas e ideas que usé después [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Por allá en el 2005 cuando me encontraba en la recta final de la maestria llegó a mis manos el artículo que da título a este post, me lo dio un amigo brasileño y por su intermedio me contactó con el autor (<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/www.tuliovianna.org">Tulio Vianna</a>) a quien pude exponer algunas dudas e ideas que usé después en el texto de mi tesina y en el análisis de lo que luego sería <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=125">la reforma penal colombiana</a>.</p>
<p>El me envió una versión en portuñol que había hecho un amigo suyo para que se me facilitara terminar de leer y yo con base en lo ya hecho revisé esa traducción y la ajusté, se lo devolví con la alegría de un trabajo bien hecho y de un texto que merecía ser conocido más. Al final entre unas y otras nunca encontré donde publicarlo… hoy mi amigo <a href="http://www.ringenbach.org/">Jorge desde México</a> me manda esta sorpresa: <a href="http://www.juridicas.unam.mx/publica/librev/rev/boletin/cont/120/art/art5.pdf">mi traducción del artículo fue publicada</a> en el último número (120) del <a href="http://www.juridicas.unam.mx/publica/rev/cont.htm?r=boletin">Boletín Mexicano de Derecho Comparado</a> del Instituto de Investigaciones Jurídicas de la Universidad Autónoma de México. </p>
<p>Les recomiendo su lectura y reflexión!</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-11T17:59:49Z</updated>
    <category term="Textos amigos"/>
    <category term="pirateria"/>
    <category term="Traducci&#xF3;n"/>
    <category term="Redise&#xF1;o de la Propiedad Intelectual"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4734</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/11/icommons_fundraising_auction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">iCommons fundraising auction</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">iCommons is doing a fundraising auction. There are lots of cool things that you can bid on and help iCommons at the same time. My contribution are some photographs.A set of five photographs from Joi Ito's Flickr collection, showing nature...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://icommons.org/auction">iCommons is doing a fundraising auction.</a> There are lots of cool things that you can bid on and help iCommons at the same time. My contribution are some photographs.</p><blockquote>A set of five photographs from Joi Ito's Flickr collection, showing nature and landscape portraits from Japan.<p/>

<p>Apart from being the chairman of the board of Creative Commons and a member of the board of iCommons, Joi Ito is an avid photographer. In this collection he shoots a Shinkansen station in Yamagata, a view of Shanghai from the JW Marriot, a bamboo thicket from his yard and detail of dragonfly wings.</p></blockquote><a href="http://cgi.ebay.com/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ViewItem&amp;item=360001773843">You can bid on my photos here.</a> My apologies for the delay in blogging this, but you only have one more day. ;-)<p/>
		
		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/11/icommons_fundraising_auction.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/11/icommons_fundraising_auction.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-11T04:41:42Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-11T04:37:46Z</published>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4732</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/10/computer_broken.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Computer broken</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">My computer broke when I was messing with it on the plane. The good news is that I think I can recover most of the data. The bad news is that I don't have a computer for the next two...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>My computer broke when I was messing with it on the plane. The good news is that I think I can recover most of the data. The bad news is that I don't have a computer for the next two or three days until Fumi/Mika bring my backup computer to SF and I go there from here (Paris).</p>

<p>I also stupidly don't remember the password for my main mail account (it is encrypted on my computer) so can only retrieve email sporadically on my iPhone from my main account. If you need to reach me urgently, please SMS me and/or send email to joiito at gmail where I will be sending my web mail from.</p>

<p>I can't believe that I literally had my backup disk in my hand and decided not to pack it because I had too much stuff to carry this trip... *sigh*</p>
		
		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/10/computer_broken.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/10/computer_broken.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-10T23:44:24Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-10T23:40:43Z</published>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=301</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=301" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Esta semana: Prográmate en Bogotá</title>
    <summary>Les tengo dos invitaciones para mañana, dos invitaciones muy diversas que interesan a muchos. La primera es en el marco de educación y acceso abierto una sesión en la Universidad Nacional en compañía de Ignasi Labastida (Universidad de Barcelona y lider de Creative Commons en España) y por la tarde en el marco de Video [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Les tengo dos invitaciones para mañana, dos invitaciones muy diversas que interesan a muchos. La primera es en el marco de educación y acceso abierto una sesión en la Universidad Nacional en compañía de Ignasi Labastida (Universidad de Barcelona y lider de Creative Commons en España) y por la tarde en el marco de Video Afuera con Graciela Melo (Cecolda) y Jorge Mario Durán (Mambo).</p>
<p>Los detalles a continuación:</p>
<p><em>MARTES 11 DE DICIEMBRE POR LA MAÑANA: EDUCACION</em><br/>
<strong>LA DIRECCIÓN NACIONAL DE SERVICIOS ACADÉMICOS VIRUTALES: Invita a todos aquellos interesados en participar en la Conferencia sobre Derechos de Autor y Problemáticas en el sector educativo, los repositorios, organizada por la Fundación Karisma</strong>. Con esta sesión se continúa el proceso de capacitación <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=298">iniciado la semana pasada</a></p>
<p>PROGRAMA</p>
<p>9:00 a.m.  Acceso abierto, recursos abiertos, nuevas tendencias para los repositorios universitarios.  Carolina Botero<br/>
9:45 a.m.  Repositorios  de Cursos Virtuales en las Universidades Catalanas, ventajas y problemas de las licencias CC. <a href="http://www.banquete.org/banquete05/visualizacion.php?id=120">Ignasi Labastida</a>. (Videochat desde Barcelona)<br/>
10:30 a.m.  11:00 a.m.	Descanso<br/>
11:00 a.m.  12:30 m.	Sesión de Preguntas y respuestas</p>
<p>La conferencia se va a transmitir de manera virtual, a través del videochat<br/>
Los requisitos que debe tener el computador para participar de la conferencia<br/>
1. Audífono (o parlantes)<br/>
2. Micrófono<br/>
3. Cámara Web (opcional)<br/>
Para ingresar al videochat, siga los siguientes pasos:<br/>
1.	Ingrese a la dirección Web: <a href="http://aplicaciones.virtual.unal.edu.co/multimedia/eventos/DNSAV-Videochat/index.html">http://aplicaciones.virtual.unal.edu.co/multimedia/eventos/DNSAV-Videochat/index.html</a><br/>
2. Ingrese los siguientes datos.<br/>
•	Usuario: nombre de quien se conecta<br/>
•	Contraseña: dnsav<br/>
•	Espectadores: 1<br/>
•	Conexión: LAN si esta desde la universidad<br/>
         Modem y DSL desde otros lugares.<br/>
3. Haga clic en Entrar</p>
<p><em>MARTES 11 DE DICIEMBRE POR LA TARDE: CULTURA Y ARTE</em><br/>
<strong>FESTIVAL VIDEO AFUERA, organizado por el <a href="http://www.mediatorta.gov.co/web/index.php">Centro cultural Media Torta</a></strong><br/>
CONVERSATORIO<br/>
5:00 p.m.<br/>
Alianza Francesa<br/>
Carrera 3 No. 18 - 45<br/>
Foro sobre la propuesta de uso de derechos de Creative Commons en Colombia y la jurisprudencia en el país para la proyección de películas y vídeos en cine club’s.<br/>
Panelistas: <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?page_id=17">CAROLINA BOTERO</a> y <a href="http://www.cecolda.org.co/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=57&amp;Itemid=47">GRACIELA MELO</a><br/>
Moderador: <a href="http://www.colombia.com/entrevistas/autonoticias/varios/2004/04/22/detallenoticia311.asp">JORGE MARIO DURAN</a> </p>
<p>Se puede participar gratis de los dos eventos, <strong>los espero!</strong></p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-10T15:51:54Z</updated>
    <category term="LibreCultura"/>
    <category term="Evento"/>
    <category term="Acceso Abierto"/>
    <category term="Cultura"/>
    <category term="En la educaci&#xF3;n"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <category term="En la biblioteca"/>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=300</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=300" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Desde equinoXio: el caso de Mariacecita y El Pais.</title>
    <summary>Por considerarla de importancia para los lectores de este blog transcribo el artículo que acabo de publicar en equinoXio.org:

Ilustrar artículos en medios comerciales con licencias Creative Commons, el caso de Mariacecita y El Pais.
“Esta semana la blogosfera colombiana se ha visto revuelta, unida, confrontada, etc., por el uso que en El País (diario de Cali) [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Por considerarla de importancia para los lectores de este blog transcribo el artículo que <a href="http://www.equinoxio.org/columnas/ilustrar-articulos-en-medios-comerciales-con-licencias-creative-commons-el-caso-de-mariacecita-y-el-pais-2143/">acabo de publicar en equinoXio.org</a>:<br/>
<strong><br/>
Ilustrar artículos en medios comerciales con licencias Creative Commons, el caso de Mariacecita y El Pais.</strong></p>
<p>“Esta semana <a href="http://patton.blogdeldia.com/item/518">la blogosfera colombiana</a> se ha visto revuelta, unida, confrontada, etc., por el uso que en <a href="http://www.elpais.com.co/paisonline/">El País </a>(diario de Cali) hicieron de una foto de Flickr. <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mariacecita/2053011425/">La foto en cuestión</a> se encuentra en la galería de este sitio y es de una <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mariacecita/">fotógrafa </a>que la colgó allí con una licencia <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/">Creative Commons AtribuciónNoComercialNoDerivadas Genérica</a>, la foto <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/vik407/2090869371/">fue incluída en una de las revistas del diario </a>(publicación con fines comerciales) editada (es decir, fue modificada) con el fin, según el diario de, <a href="http://www.elpais.com.co/paisonline/notas/Diciembre072007/mariaclaudiamontano.html">“contextualizar la información relacionada con la exposición (de fotografía que se llevará a cabo pronto en Cali)”</a>.</p>
<p>He leído muchas de las <a href="http://carloscaicedo.net/derecho-e/sobre-el-pais-cali-y-la-propiedad-intelectual">reacciones </a>y <a href="http://victorsolano.com/2007/12/06/el-pais-toma-sin-permiso-fotos-de-usuarios-de-flickr/">comentarios </a>que se difundieron sobre el caso en la blogosfera (incluso <a href="http://alt1040.com/archivo/2007/12/07/el-diario-el-pais-de-colombia-publica-una-foto-sin-permiso/">fuera de la Colombiana</a>) y creo que es la primera vez que en Colombia se abre tanto interés sobre el tema, por lo que quiero aportar mi propia óptica como una de las promotoras de las licencias en Colombia. <a class="more-link" href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=300#more-300">(more…)</a></p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-09T14:01:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Periodismo Ciudadano"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <category term="Actualidad"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3471</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/a_us_cto.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>A US CTO?</title>
    <summary>The Stanford Center for Internet and Society is now in the early planning stages for a conference to be held April 18/19 about the idea of a CTO for the United States government. Obama of course suggested the idea in his tech program. But this conference has nothing to do with the Obama campaign. 

My current thinking is to pick four policy areas, and get experts to reflect upon how a CTO might impact or advance policy interests within each area. The four I now plan are (1) privacy, (2) security, (3) transparency, and (4) efficiency. Then at the end of the day, experts in administrative law will reflect upon how best to architect the office of the CTO to achieve these objectives.

No doubt there will be lots of fun speculation about who the US CTO should be. My own view is that the person should be someone at least with experience as a CTO at a major organization. (I.e., s/he needs to be a credible techie.) S/he should also have a rich sense of policy.

I've set up a page on my wiki to invite suggestions for the planning of the conference. And if you'd like to be informed when final plans are made, send a note to uscto@pobox.com.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The <a href="http://cyberlaw.stanford.edu/">Stanford Center for Internet and Society </a>is now in the early planning stages for a conference to be held April 18/19 about the idea of a CTO for the United States government. Obama of course suggested the idea in his <a href="http://www.barackobama.com/2007/11/14/obama_shares_his_tech_plan_tod.php">tech program</a>. But this conference has nothing to do with the Obama campaign. 

My current thinking is to pick four policy areas, and get experts to reflect upon how a CTO might impact or advance policy interests within each area. The four I now plan are (1) privacy, (2) security, (3) transparency, and (4) efficiency. Then at the end of the day, experts in administrative law will reflect upon how best to architect the office of the CTO to achieve these objectives.

No doubt there will be lots of fun speculation about who the US CTO should be. My own view is that the person should be someone at least with experience as a CTO at a major organization. (I.e., s/he needs to be a credible techie.) S/he should also have a rich sense of policy.

I've set up a <a href="http://wiki.lessig.org/index.php/USCTO%3F">page</a> on my <a href="http://wiki.lessig.org/index.php/Main_Page">wiki</a> to invite suggestions for the planning of the conference. And if you'd like to be informed when final plans are made, send a note to <a href="mailto:uscto@pobox.com.">uscto@pobox.com.</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-08T16:08:05Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-08T15:56:55Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="good code"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3469</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/the_economist_on_corruption.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>The Economist on corruption</title>
    <summary>The Economist has a piece about my shift to work on corruption. Fortunately, it was finished before my (arguably) corrupt offer to send a (CC-licensed) DVD to anyone who contributes $100 to Creative Commons. If you'd like to participate in that scandal, send an email after the contribution to corrupt_lessig@pobox.com.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://www.economist.com/search/displaystory.cfm?story_id=10202766&amp;CFID=2877818&amp;CFTOKEN=1318480d9272e6a3"><center><img alt="economist-image.jpg" height="409" src="http://lessig.org/blog/economist-image.jpg" width="400"/></center>
</a>
<a href="http://economist.com">The Economist</a> has <a href="http://www.economist.com/search/displaystory.cfm?story_id=10202766&amp;CFID=2877818&amp;CFTOKEN=1318480d9272e6a3">a piece</a> about my shift to work on corruption. Fortunately, it was finished before my (arguably) <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/9_days_till_were_5.html">corrupt offer</a> to send a (CC-licensed) DVD to anyone who <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">contributes</a> $100 to Creative Commons. If you'd like to participate in that scandal, send an email after the contribution to <a href="mailto:corrupt_lessig@pobox.com">corrupt_lessig@pobox.com</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-07T17:02:38Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-07T15:03:40Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="Corruption"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4730</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/07/cc_5th_birthday_party_in_sf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">CC 5th Birthday Party in SF</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">Be there or be square....</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Be there or be square.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/2093076116/" title="CC 5th Birthday Party in SF by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="CC 5th Birthday Party in SF" height="327" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2243/2093076116_7ec9acc454.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>
		
		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/07/cc_5th_birthday_party_in_sf.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/07/cc_5th_birthday_party_in_sf.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-07T07:36:47Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-07T07:36:44Z</published>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-705270565332099165</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/12/you-say-non-commercial-i-say-huh-what.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=705270565332099165" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/705270565332099165/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/705270565332099165" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/705270565332099165" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>you say non-commercial, i say "huh what?!"</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of the questions/issues that comes up in our role as the CC organisation for Australia is what non-commercial means. good question, what does non-commercial mean?<div><br/></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: large;">the background</span></span></span></div><div><br/></div><div>Creative Commons offers three non-commercial licences: Attribution-Noncommercial (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/">BY-NC</a>), Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/">BY-NC-ND</a>) and Attribution-Noncommercial-ShareAlike (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/">BY-NC-SA</a>) in the standard suite. The Australian suite of licences naturally offers the same types of licences (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/au/">BY-NC</a>, <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/au/">BY-NC-ND</a> and <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/au/">BY-NC-SA</a>) for the Australian jurisdiction.<br/></div><div><br/></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span"><u>side note:</u></span> CC also offers one non-commercial licence as part of the <a href="http://creativecommons.org/license/sampling">Sampling Licences</a>: Noncommercial-Sampling Plus (<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/nc-sampling+/1.0/">NC-Sampling+</a>) <span class="Apple-style-span"><u>end side note</u></span><div><br/>For the purposes of this entry I am talking mainly about the meaning of non-commercial within an Australian context.</div><div><br/></div><div>The related restriction outlined on the Australian Commons Deeds states:</div><div><blockquote>"<span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-weight: bold;">Noncommercial.</span> You may not use this work for commercial purposes."</blockquote>In the Australian legal code (Version 2.5), the licence says (in Section 4, Part b):</div><div><blockquote> You may not exercise any of the rights granted to You in Section 3 above in any manner that is primarily intended for or directed toward commercial advantage or private monetary compensation. The exchange of the Work for other copyrighted works by means of digital file-sharing or otherwise shall not be considered to be intended for or directed toward commercial advantage or private monetary compensation, provided there is no payment of any monetary compensation in connection with the exchange of copyrighted works. </blockquote>Creative Commons recognised that this may not provide detailed enough clarification of what is and what isn't commercial reuse. To help provide clarity, CC produced a set of <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/DiscussionDraftNonCommercial_Guidelines">draft Non-commercial Guidelines</a>, but to date these have not been officially endorsed by the organisation.</div><div><br/><br/></div><div><br/></div><div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">We want to hear from you, the users of CC. When you decide (or not decide if that be the case) to put your work under a non-commercial licence, what are you motivations? Should CCau develop Australia-specific non-commercial guidelines? <a href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=705270565332099165">What do you think non-commercial means?</a></span></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-07T06:15:44Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-07T05:29:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="meaning of non-commercial"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3468</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/9_days_till_were_5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>9 days till we're 5</title>
    <summary>By Tama Lever at Flickr,



Tama's is the latest winning Flickr photo in the CC Flickr contest. It nicely captures my obsessive focus these next 9 days. 

We turn 5 on the 15th. We've got a long way to got to meet our target for the year. Ordinarily we'd have till the end  of the year. But this year, I want to meet the target by December 15. We've all been working insanely hard to pull this (and a list of amazing announcements) together. I want to be able to let the staff go back to life on December 16. And I want to have sometime to explain to my 4 year old just how reindeer fly. 

So please, if you haven't, support us now. If you have, support us again. If you've got any really good dirt on someone, blackmail them now. And, as a special (if corrupt) bonus: If you donate $100 or more, I'll send a free DVD of my first corruption lecture. Just send an email to corrupt_lessig@pobox.com after you make your donation with an address, and off it will go.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center><img alt="2046561465_d5b03292de_b.jpg" height="341" src="http://lessig.org/blog/2046561465_d5b03292de_b.jpg" width="612"/></center>
By Tama Lever at <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/tamaleaver/2046561465/">Flickr</a>,
<a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/" rel="license">
<img alt="Creative Commons License" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/3.0/80x15.png" style="border-width: 0;"/></a>

Tama's is the latest winning Flickr photo in the <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org/contest">CC Flickr contest</a>. It nicely captures my obsessive focus these next 9 days. 

We turn 5 on the 15th. We've got a long way to got to meet our target for the year. Ordinarily we'd have till the end  of the year. But this year, I want to meet the target by December 15. We've all been working insanely hard to pull this (and a list of amazing announcements) together. I want to be able to let the staff go back to life on December 16. And I want to have sometime to explain to my 4 year old just how reindeer fly. 

So please, if you haven't, <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">support</a> us now. If you have, <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">support</a> us again. If you've got any really good dirt on someone, blackmail them now. And, as a special (if corrupt) bonus: If you donate $100 or more, I'll send a free DVD of my first <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/10/corruption_lecture_alpha_versi_1.html">corruption lecture</a>. Just send an email to <a href="mailto:corrupt_lessig@pobox.com">corrupt_lessig@pobox.com</a> after you make your donation with an address, and off it will go. 
</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-06T15:34:25Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-06T15:08:28Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3467</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/the_icommons_auction_1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>the iCommons Auction</title>
    <summary>iCommons is the group CC incubated and then have begun to spin out this year. Its aim is to build a common (but not CC owned) platform for digital freedom related issues (A2K, free software, open source software, free culture, free knowledge, activism, etc.). Its main annual event is a conference. The first year was Boston. The second, Brazil. Last year, Croatia. Next year Japan.

iCommons is having an auction to build support (and $$!, or actually €) for iCommons. Among the items auctioned is the (embarrassingly worn) black jacket I have worn while traveling about 500,000 miles over the last few years. Weird (but clean). Bid away!</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://icommons.org/auction"><center><img alt="auction_button_final.jpg" height="200" src="http://lessig.org/blog/auction_button_final.jpg" width="200"/></center></a>

<a href="http://iCommons.org">iCommons</a> is the group CC incubated and then have begun to spin out this year. Its aim is to build a common (but not CC owned) platform for digital freedom related issues (A2K, free software, open source software, free culture, free knowledge, activism, etc.). Its main annual event is a conference. The first year was <a href="http://www.icommons.org/isummit05/">Boston</a>. The second, <a href="http://www.icommons.org/isummit06/">Brazil</a>. Last year, <a href="http://www.icommons.org/isummit07/">Croatia</a>. Next year <a href="http://www.icommons.org/isummit08/">Japan</a>.

iCommons is having an <a href="http://icommons.org/auction">auction</a> to build support (and $$!, or actually €) for iCommons. Among the items auctioned is the (<a href="http://cgi.ebay.com/ws/eBayISAPI.dll?ViewItem&amp;item=360003000531">embarrassingly worn) black jacket I have worn</a> while traveling about 500,000 miles over the last few years. Weird (but clean). Bid away!</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-06T14:44:06Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-05T17:21:20Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-3029810488315553963</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/12/mayer-bettle-sequel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=3029810488315553963" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/3029810488315553963/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3029810488315553963" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/3029810488315553963" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>mayer + bettle: the sequel?!</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">There's word on the street is that the loveable CC duo Mayer and Bettle featured in the <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/animation_train">CCau animation film</a> are planning to hit the set on a new sequel to the much loved, much distributed film. Almost three years on and the pair feel it is time to update their message. The duo aren't saying much at this early stage, but Mayer did say, "It's more of what you loved, but this time we're talking creator's rights."<div><br/></div><div>"Much has changed since we shot the first film," Mayer said, "Which is why Bettle and I are getting back in front of the Camera." Tightening of the licences, expanded metadata, a dedicated <a href="http://learn.creativecommons.org/">education division</a> and exploration into <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/CCPlus">complimentary licensing options</a> are just some of the key developments. <br/><div><br/></div><div>Bettle, who is still riding high on the success of <span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style: italic;">The Best Song in the World</span>, has been spending much of her time exploring different ways of using CC. "With this new animation we want to help you, the creators out there, to understand the great potential of CC," she told CCau staff this morning. "Give some, take some. That's what it's all about," she said, "If you're taking from the commons, and you want to put it back, this new film will show you how."</div><div><br/></div><div>The first animation film, which has been republished 1000s of times, translated and subtitled and <a href="http://revver.com/">Revver</a>ised to help fundraise for CC internationally, was a huge success.  Mayer and Bettle are enthusiastically joined by the original film team, CCau staffer <a href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/">Elliott Bledsoe</a>, animator <a href="http://iusebiro.blogspot.com/">Pete Foley</a>, musician Chris Perren and actors Dash Kruck and Mem Rynne in the production of the sequel.</div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-05T05:44:44Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-05T04:05:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CCau animation"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CC+"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Mayer + Bettle"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-3822023774284084223</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/cc-birthday-party-by-ccau.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=3822023774284084223" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/3822023774284084223/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3822023774284084223" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/3822023774284084223" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>cc birthday party by ccau</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/cc5logo.png"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://creativecommons.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/cc5logo.png" style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand; width: 400px;"/></a><br/><br/>CC is turning 5 and they are encouraging people to host parties. America is having a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7855">party</a> in San Francisco that will include:<br/><br/><blockquote>...announcements by Joi Ito and Lawrence Lessig, a live acoustic performance by Gilberto Gil, video remixing by Phi Phenomenon, and music provided by DJ Spooky.<br/></blockquote><br/><br/>If you're over there, <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/images/8/8c/Flier-general-final.pdf">get along</a>.<br/><br/>Here in Australia, we're hosting a party for CC at my house!! We're leveraging our time zone advantage to kick off the 5th birthday celebrations for Creative Commons. And how? We're having a true blue Aussie breakfast BBQ (and some champagne too!) on Saturday December 15. So unless the newbies over at CC New Zealand host a midnight party we're the first!<br/><br/>Come along any time after 10am. We'll provide some BBQ treats, but bring some of your own. Email <a href="mailto:jessica@creativecommons.org.au">Jessica Coates</a> for more details if you wanna come!<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-05T04:06:51Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-28T02:45:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc parties"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau events"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4728</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/05/tttttwitter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">T.t.t.t.twitter...</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">Denied in Dubai. Time to fire up my VPN&amp;#8230;...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img src="http://joi.ito.com/twitterblock.jpg"/></p>

<p>Denied in Dubai.</p>

<p>Time to fire up my VPN…</p>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/05/tttttwitter.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/05/tttttwitter.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-05T03:44:39Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-05T03:44:33Z</published>
    <category term="Global Voices"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=299</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=299" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Wikipedia: GFDL y CCBYSA ¡Compatibles!</title>
    <summary>Barrapunto trae el recuento de lo que Lessig anuncia en su blog y que desde la Fundación Wikimedia explican: FSF ha acordado hacer los ajustes necesarios a la GFDL que permita hacer compatible esta licencia con la de Creative Commons AtribuciónCompartiIgual. Cuando esto se verifique será la comunidad de wikipedia la que deberá pronunciarse para [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://barrapunto.com/article.pl?sid=07/12/02/028227&amp;from=rss">Barrapunto</a> trae el recuento de lo que Lessig anuncia en <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html">su blog</a> y que desde la <a href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update">Fundación Wikimedia explican</a>: FSF ha acordado hacer los ajustes necesarios a la GFDL que permita hacer compatible esta licencia con la de Creative Commons AtribuciónCompartiIgual. Cuando esto se verifique será la comunidad de wikipedia la que deberá pronunciarse para que Wikipedia “<strong>relicencie</strong>” con CCBYSA. </p>
<p>El tema ha tenido un importante eco en la <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/">blogosfera de gente relacionada con Creative Commons</a>, pero seguramente lo más interesante va a ser la discusión sobre el proceso de migración que se inicie en la comunidad de Wikipedia.</p>
<p>Primer gran paso el que se hace en compatibilidad y un gran cambio si wikipedia relicencia, no? (gracias <a href="http://blog.eljeffto.com/">Jeffrey</a>)</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-02T10:07:50Z</updated>
    <category term="LibreCultura"/>
    <category term="Licencias copyleft"/>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4725</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/wikipedia_and_creative_commons_move_closer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Wikipedia and Creative Commons move closer</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">Lessig BlogSome important news from Wikipedia to understand clearly As you&amp;#8217;ll see in this video, there has been important progress in making Wikipedia compatible with the world of Creative Commons licensed work. But we should be very precise about...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
</p><blockquote><div class="personquote">Lessig Blog</div><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html">Some important news from Wikipedia to understand clearly</a><p/>

<p>As you’ll see in this video, there has been important progress in making Wikipedia compatible with the world of <a href="http://creativecommons.org/">Creative Commons</a> licensed work. But we should be very precise about this extremely good news: As Jimmy announces, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Foundation">Wikimedia Foundation Board</a> has agreed with a proposal made by the Free Software Foundation that will permit Wikipedia (and other such wikis) to relicense under a <a href="http://http//creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license</a>.</p>

<p>That is very different from saying that Wikipedia has relicensed under a CC license. The decision whether to take advantage of this freedom granted by the FSF when the FSF grants it will be a decision the Wikipedia community will have to make. We are very hopeful that the community will ratify this move to compatible freedoms. And if they do, we are looking forward to an extraordinary celebration.</p>

<p>Read the Wikimedia Foundation resolution <a href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update">here</a>.</p>

<p>My endless thanks to everyone who has helped make this possible, from Richard Stallman and the FSF board, to the important leaders within the Wikipedia community who say yet another legal obstacle to freedom that they could remove. </p></blockquote>Thanks to everyone who has been working on it. This is a very significant step in improving interoperability and I think this is a great example of how we can all work together to benefit the free culture community. Thank you, thank you, thank you.
<!-- technorati tags start --><p style="text-align: right; font-size: 10px;">Technorati Tags: <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/Wikipedia" rel="tag">Wikipedia</a></p><!-- technorati tags end --><p/>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/wikipedia_and_creative_commons_move_closer.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/wikipedia_and_creative_commons_move_closer.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-02T09:50:02Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-02T09:48:39Z</published>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4724</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/lawsuit_against_cc_dismissed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Lawsuit against CC dismissed</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">Lessig BlogFrom the Why-a-GC-from-Cravath-is-great Department: The lawsuit is over We received this happy missive in the mail yesterday: The plaintiffs in the lawsuit about Virgin using a CC-licensed photo have dismissed CC from the case. This is not a settlement....</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p/><blockquote><div class="personquote">Lessig Blog</div><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/from_the_whyagcfromcravathisgr.html">From the Why-a-GC-from-Cravath-is-great Department: The lawsuit is over</a><p/>

<p>We received this happy missive in the mail yesterday: The plaintiffs in the <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html">lawsuit about Virgin using a CC-licensed photo</a> have dismissed CC from the case. This is not a settlement. It is not the product of negotiation. It is the recognition by plaintiffs counsel that the laws of Texas and the United States give the plaintiffs no cause to sue Creative Commons.</p></blockquote>This is great news. Congratulations to the whole team who worked on this including a number of volunteers from the community.<p/>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/lawsuit_against_cc_dismissed.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/12/02/lawsuit_against_cc_dismissed.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-02T09:39:56Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-02T09:39:37Z</published>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/12/01/copyleft-pd/</id>
    <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/12/01/copyleft-pd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Steps toward better software and content</title>
    <summary>The Wikimedia Foundation board has passed a resolution that is a step toward Wikipedia migrating to the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license. I have an uninteresting interest in this due to working at Creative Commons (I do not represent them on this blog), but as someone who wants to see free knowledge “win” and achieve revolutionary [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Wikimedia Foundation board has passed a <a href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update">resolution</a> that is a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7876">step toward Wikipedia migrating to the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license</a>. I have an uninteresting interest in this due to working at Creative Commons (I do <em>not</em> represent them on this blog), but as someone who wants to see free knowledge “win” and achieve <a href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2006/12/10/peer-production-revolution/">revolutionary</a> impact, I declare this an important step forward. The current fragmentation of the universe of free content along the lines of legally incompatible but similar in spirit <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyleft" rel="tag">copyleft</a> licenses delays and endangers the point at which that universe reaches critical mass — when any given project decides to use a copyleft license merely because then being able to include content from the free copyleft universe makes that decision make sense. This has worked fairly well in the software world with the GPL as <em>the</em> copyleft license.</p>
<p>Copyleft was and is a great hack, and useful in many cases. But practically it is a major barrier to collaboration in some contexts and politically it is still based on <a href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/09/10/copyright-intervention/">censorship</a>. So I’m always extremely pleased by any expansion of the public domain. There could hardly be a more welcome expansion than <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_J._Bernstein" rel="tag">Daniel J. Bernstein</a>’s <a href="http://lwn.net/Articles/260481/">release</a> of his code (most notably <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qmail" rel="tag">qmail</a>) into the public domain. Most of the practical benefit (including his code in free software distributions) could have been achieved by released under any free software license, including the GPL. But politically, check out this <a href="http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-3147768955127254412&amp;q=%22Bernstein+releases+code+to+public+domain%22&amp;total=1&amp;start=0&amp;num=10&amp;so=0&amp;type=search&amp;plindex=0">two minute video</a> of Bernstein pointing out some of the problems of copyright and announcing that his code is in the public domain.</p>
<p>Bernstein (usually referred to as ‘djb’) also recently doubled the reward for finding a security hole in qmail to US$1,000. I highly recommend his <em><a href="http://cr.yp.to/qmail/qmailsec-20071101.pdf">Some thoughts on security after ten years of qmail 1.0</a></em>, also available as something approximating <a href="http://cr.yp.to/talks/2007.11.02/slides.pdf">slides</a> (also see an interesting <a href="http://www.eros-os.org/pipermail/cap-talk/2007-November/thread.html#9202">discussion of the paper on cap-talk</a>).</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-02T00:38:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Computers"/>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <category term="Economics"/>
    <category term="Free Speech"/>
    <category term="Intellectual Protectionism"/>
    <category term="Open Source"/>
    <category term="Peeves"/>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Programming"/>
    <category term="Public Domain"/>
    <category term="Wikipedia"/>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Linksvayer</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog</id>
      <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/category/creative-commons/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>My opinions only. I do not represent any organization in this publication.</subtitle>
      <title>Mike Linksvayer » Creative Commons</title>
      <updated>2007-12-17T04:27:51Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3466</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/12/some_important_news_from_wikip.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Some important news from Wikipedia to understand clearly</title>
    <summary>As you'll  see in this video, there has been important progress in making Wikipedia compatible with the world of Creative Commons licensed work. But we should be very precise about this extremely good news: As Jimmy announces, the Wikimedia Foundation Board has agreed with a proposal made by the Free Software Foundation that will permit Wikipedia (and other such wikis) to relicense under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license. 

That is very different from saying that Wikipedia has relicensed under a CC license. The decision whether to take advantage of this freedom granted by the FSF when the FSF grants it will be a decision the Wikipedia community will have to make. We are very hopeful that the community will ratify this move to compatible freedoms. And if they do, we are looking forward to an extraordinary celebration.

Read the Wikimedia Foundation resolution here. 

My endless thanks to everyone who has helped make this possible, from Richard Stallman and the FSF board, to the important leaders within the Wikipedia community who say yet another legal obstacle to freedom that they could remove.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center/>

As you'll  see in this video, there has been important progress in making Wikipedia compatible with the world of <a href="http://creativecommons.org">Creative Commons</a> licensed work. But we should be very precise about this extremely good news: As Jimmy announces, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikimedia_Foundation">Wikimedia Foundation Board</a> has agreed with a proposal made by the Free Software Foundation that will permit Wikipedia (and other such wikis) to relicense under a <a href="http://http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license</a>. 

That is very different from saying that Wikipedia has relicensed under a CC license. The decision whether to take advantage of this freedom granted by the FSF when the FSF grants it will be a decision the Wikipedia community will have to make. We are very hopeful that the community will ratify this move to compatible freedoms. And if they do, we are looking forward to an extraordinary celebration.

Read the Wikimedia Foundation resolution <a href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Resolution:License_update">here</a>. 

My endless thanks to everyone who has helped make this possible, from Richard Stallman and the FSF board, to the important leaders within the Wikipedia community who say yet another legal obstacle to freedom that they could remove.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-01T18:51:44Z</updated>
    <published>2007-12-01T17:10:22Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=298</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=298" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Claudio Ruiz en Bogotá, para SLUD y…</title>
    <summary>Como en otras oportunidades que han venido amigos líderes de Creative Commons a Bogotá aprovechamos para que dejen acá sus conocimientos y opiniones, como siempre junto con nuestros amigos de la comunidad de Software Libre. Esta vez, estará acá la próxima semana Claudio Ruiz, si el blogger de QuemarLasNaves, y participará en la Sexta Semana [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Como en otras oportunidades que <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=88">han venido amigos líderes </a>de Creative Commons a Bogotá aprovechamos para que dejen acá sus conocimientos y opiniones, como siempre junto con nuestros amigos de la comunidad de Software Libre. Esta vez, estará acá la próxima semana Claudio Ruiz, si el blogger de <a href="http://www.quemarlasnaves.net/">QuemarLasNaves</a>, y participará en <a href="http://glud.udistrital.edu.co/slud6/">la Sexta Semana Linux de la Universidad Distrital (SLUD VI)</a> y lo aprovecharé, claro, para otras cositas:</p>
<p><strong>Sexta Semana Linux </strong></p>
<p>Les recomiendo todo el <a href="http://glud.udistrital.edu.co/slud6/?q=node/19">programa</a> (aunque no está de más decir que yo estaré el lunes a las 11am) pero para los interesados en Creative Commons anoten las charlas de Claudio:</p>
<p>El martes<br/>
1:15 a 2:40 pm 	Qué y a quienes protege el derecho de autor: Una historia de intereses y desequilibrios - Claudio Ruíz (Chile) - Invitado Internacional<br/>
El jueves<br/>
1:25 a 2:50 pm 	Creative Commons como herramienta para el desarrollo - Claudio Ruíz (Chile) - Invitado Internacional</p>
<p>Lugar: Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas<br/>
Facultad de Ingeniería<br/>
Auditorio Sabio Caldas<br/>
Carrera 8 N. 40-53<br/>
Bogotá, Colombia.</p>
<p>Entrada Libre.</p>
<p><strong>Derecho de autor y alternativas en la Universidad Nacional</strong></p>
<p>Adicionalmente estaremos participando en una sesión de capacitación para docentes que hace la Fundación Karisma: el tema es Derecho de Autor y problemáticas en el sector educativo y editorial y se organiza por y para LA DIRECCIÓN NACIONAL DE SERVICIOS ACADÉMICOS VIRUTALES, UNIBIBLOS y LA DIRECCIÓN NACIONAL DE BIBLIOTECAS de la Universidad Nacional, y además habrá ¡acceso libre y gratuito vía internet!</p>
<p>Fecha: 6 de Diciembre de 2007</p>
<p>8:00 a.m. a 8:45 a.m El derecho de autor en la Universidad, problemas y alternativas.  Carolina Botero<br/>
8:45 a.m. a 9:30 a m. Alternativas para la gestión del derecho de autor, ejemplos del sector editorial chileno.  Claudio Ruiz G.<br/>
9:30 a.m. a 10:00 a.m. Descanso<br/>
10:00 a.m. a 11:00 a.m. Sesión de Preguntas y respuestas</p>
<p>Esto se va a transmitir de manera virtual, a través del videochat de la Universidad Nacional, si les interesa sigan las instrucciones:</p>
<p>Los requisitos que debe tener el computador para participar de la conferencia<br/>
1. Audífono (o parlantes)<br/>
2. Micrófono<br/>
3. Cámara Web (opcional)*</p>
<p>Para ingresar al videochat, siga los pasos:<br/>
1. Ingrese a la dirección Web: http://aplicaciones.virtual.unal.edu.co/multimedia/eventos/DNSAV-Vide…<br/>
2. Ingrese los siguientes datos.<br/>
Usuario: nombre de quien se conecta<br/>
Contraseña: dnsav<br/>
Espectadores: 1<br/>
Conexión: LAN si esta desde la universidad, Modem y DSL desde otros lugares.<br/>
3. Haga clic en Entrar </p>
<p>¡Espero verlos por ahí!</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-12-01T00:24:04Z</updated>
    <category term="LibreCultura"/>
    <category term="Evento"/>
    <category term="Acceso Abierto"/>
    <category term="Software libre"/>
    <category term="En la educaci&#xF3;n"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <category term="En la biblioteca"/>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=296</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=296" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Las músicas de fusión y el anarco punk en Bogotá y Medellín, algunas percepciones de lo legal.</title>
    <summary>A finales del 2006 y principios del 2007 participé en una investigación en torno al tema de Negocios Abiertos (aún inedita) que presentamos en Rio de Janeiro por que fue coordinada desde la Fundación Getulio Vargas, financiada por el IDRC y dirigida en Colombia  por Ana María Ochoa. Mis percepciones de la parte jurídica [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img alt="Caratula Estudios de Derecho" src="http://www.karisma.org.co/carolina_publico/Estudios%20de%20Derecho%20caratula2.jpg"/></p>
<p>A finales del 2006 y principios del 2007 participé en una investigación en torno al tema de Negocios Abiertos (aún inedita) que presentamos en <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=237">Rio de Janeiro</a> por que fue <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=238">coordinada desde la Fundación Getulio Vargas</a>, financiada por el <a href="http://www.idrc.ca/es/ev-8513-201-1-DO_TOPIC.html">IDRC </a>y dirigida en Colombia  por <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/fas/faculty/cgi/gsas_local/dept/music/Ochoa.html">Ana María Ochoa</a>. Mis percepciones de la parte jurídica <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=241">las presenté en una conferencia</a> en el Centro de Investigación Valores Musicales Regionales de la Facultad de Artes de la Universidad de Antioquia y a partir de esa conferencia me pidieron de la Revista Estudios de Derecho de la Facultad de Derecho de la Universidad de Antioquia que escribiera un artículo.</p>
<p>El artículo se tituló “Las músicas de fusión y el anaco punk en Bogotá y Medellín, algunas percepciones de lo legal” y fue publicado en el volúmen de junio pasado. Si a alguien le interesa el impreso deben comunicarse con <strong><em>rderecho arroba mitra.udea.edu.co</em></strong>, por ahora les dejo <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carolina_publico/UDEA.pdf">la versión digital</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-30T09:57:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Negocios abiertos"/>
    <category term="Textos amigos"/>
    <category term="Redise&#xF1;o de la Propiedad Intelectual"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-2180834640865809378</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/post-music-industry-forum-reflections.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=2180834640865809378" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/2180834640865809378/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2180834640865809378" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/2180834640865809378" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>post-music industry forum reflections</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2147/2071127496_4abd73784d.jpg?v=0"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2147/2071127496_4abd73784d.jpg?v=0" style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 244px; height: 367px;"/></a><span style="font-size: 78%;">Me, Jessica Coates and Scot Morris at the <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicfourm">ccau music industry fourm</a>. <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nicsuzor/2071127496/">Photo</a> by Nic Suzor, available under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en">CC BY SA 2.0</a> licence.</span><br/><br/><br/>Yesterday we held the <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum">ccau music industry forum</a> as part of <a href="http://www.auc.edu.au/">Apple University Consortium</a>’s <a href="http://auc.edu.au/Create+World+2007">Create World 2007</a> conference. It was designed to explore possible options for harmonising the <a href="http://www.apra.com.au/">APRA</a> and CC licensing models so Australia musicians can non-commercially CC licence while still collecting royalites from APRA for commercial use of their work. In summary the position at the moment is:<br/><br/><blockquote>In Australia (and New Zealand) the Australasian Performing Right Association (APRA), like many collecting societies around the world, takes a full assignment of the member’s performing rights of all past, present and future works. By assigning the rights to the collecting society it allows more efficient administration of the royalty collection process. However, this raises compatibility issues for creators who have assigned their rights to a collecting society but then seek to license a work or works under a Creative Commons “Non-Commercial” licence. In simple terms, once a person is a member of APRA, the performing right in all works is assigned to APRA and therefore the creator no longer has the right to issue any direct licences for the performance of their works.</blockquote>In order to make CC a (legal) option for Australian musicians in the management of their content, APRA would need to create a process by which members can elect to apply a CC licence to defined works (similar to the current <a href="http://www.apra.com.au/writers/downloads/OOLB_OptOutAndLicenceBack.pdf">licence back options</a>). There are a range of issues that need to be addressed before such an arrangement could be made. Please read the information provided on the CCau website for <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/musicinfo">more information</a>.<br/><br/>Now Scot Morris, International Director of APRA said himself, “APRA artists have been releasing music under Creative Commons licences" and "we're not going to sue our members." Equally the record lables and APRA aren't suing non-commercial users of musical works (but, as Nic Suzor notes on his <span style="text-decoration: underline;">blog</span>, "...the threat is still a significant deterrent in many cases" think Dean Gray and the remixed Green Day’s American Idiot album, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Edit">American Edit</a>). Big deal! For the sake of those non-commercial users I want to see a more official model that provides certainty of the legality of reusing content. I want to see a trial, similar to the <a href="http://creativecommons.nl/2007/08/23/cc-nl-start-pilot-flexibel-rechtenbeheer-samen-met-bumastemra/">one</a> (if you can read Dutch) happening in the Netherlands between <a href="http://www.creativecommons.nl/">CC Netherlands</a> and <a href="http://www.bumastemra.nl/">Buma/Stemra</a>, where members are able to collect for commercial use of a work that is non-commercially licenced. The Fourm was designed to disemminate information on the situtation and to get the ball rolling on discussions of a possible trial here. As such it was great to see a lively, engaging debate emerge. That's exactly what we were looking for.<br/><br/>A few things to come out of the Forum:<br/><br/><ol><li>APRA appear to be willing to work with CCau to find a solution to the discrepancies between the licensing models (which is good);</li><li>There is a need to define more clearly the term "non-commerical" (which has already <a href="http://wiki.creativecommons.org/NonCommercial_Guidelines">begun</a> but would need to be customised to the specific situation here in Australia);</li><li>Members using CC would need to register the works that are licensed with APRA, which adds to APRA's administrative costs.<br/></li><li>APRA are concerned about who will enforce the rights of the musician where the non-commercial licence is breached.</li><li>Economics is a key factor.<br/></li></ol>It is encouraging to see that APRA are (finally) willing to work with CCau to better the current situation. I conceed that to make it happen, CC may have to define in more detail what we mean by "non-commerical" in the licences. As Nic <span style="text-decoration: underline;">said</span><a href="http://nic.suzor.com/20071128-ccau-musicforum"/>, "...APRA would normally collect on, for example, educational uses, whereas a musician who released their song under a CC NonCommercial licence would not be entitled to collect royalties for those classes of performance." APRA possed <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/triplej/">Triple J</a> as another example; are they non-commercial or not? This is an area that will require some fleshing out before a trial can happen here.<br/><br/>APRA were also concerned about who would enforce a breach of the non-commercial licence. Now fair enough if the provision that is breached is the Attribution clause, but if the Noncommercial term is breached, then it has to have been a commerical use which means it is still a matter for APRA. And APRA can act on its members' behalf. And so they should in this instance I think.<br/><br/>On the economics front, APRA made the point that they would have to keep data on who of their members were using CC and on what tracks. This would be an administratively arduous task apparently. But Scot Morris detailed and showed a screen shot of APRA's software that keeps detailed statistical data on each song played by is major licensees. The information this system can hold is impressive. (In full admission of my relative naievity on the technical/software side of things) becuase CC licences include metadata, then theoretically if you modified the software to read and recognise this metadata that would automate at least some of the admin required wouldn't it?<br/><br/>They also cited diminished bargaining power as a problem. They were concerned that by letting people CC licence for non-commercial use it would allow licensees who were using these tracks to argue for discounted licensing fees. Boo hoo I say. If a muscian has decided they are ok will allowing non-commercial use they clearly that means they've conceded to not getting a royalty for that use. What really seems to be the issue is that this might highlight a few statistical problems in the APRA charging shedule, not to mention APRA might just pull in less money (again, a point picked up by Nic,"[APRA's] main concern seemed to be that Murdoch and <a href="http://www.google.com/">Google</a> would be able to exploit musicians by using Creative Commons licensed music").<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-29T03:37:56Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-29T03:20:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="royalties"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="apra"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau music industry forum"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau events"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-4148803808664495559</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/welcoming-new-writers-to-cc-through.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=4148803808664495559" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/4148803808664495559/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4148803808664495559" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/4148803808664495559" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>welcoming new writers to cc through the looking glass</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I've decided there is just too much to talk about around CC for me to do it alone (you should see how many draft entries are waiting to be finished!) So I've invited some other people who are involved with CCau to contribute as well. Say hello to:<br/><br/><ul><li>Jessica Coates, Project Manager, <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccClinic">Creative Commons Clinic</a>;</li><li>Nic Suzor, who doing his PhD on virtual environments;<br/></li><li>Rachel Cobcroft, who is currently developing case studies of projects and individuals using CC in Australia and is doing her PhD on motiviations for sharing on <a href="http://flickr.com/">Flickr</a>;</li><li>Emma Carroll, who is interested in CC and the music industry; and<br/></li><li>Isha Baywaters, who took the <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccClinic">Creative Commons Clinic</a> course and is currently researching open business models for the music industry.<br/></li></ul>Looking forward to their ideas!<br/><br/>Of course, this is not an official CCau blog, it is the personal ideas and opinions of people involved with CCau.<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-29T02:45:29Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-29T02:25:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="jessica coates"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="isha baywaters"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="emma carroll"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="rachel cobcroft"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="nic suzor"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3465</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/from_the_whyagcfromcravathisgr.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>From the Why-a-GC-from-Cravath-is-great Department: The lawsuit is over</title>
    <summary>We received this happy missive in the mail yesterday: The plaintiffs in the lawsuit about Virgin using a CC-licensed photo have dismissed CC from the case. This is not a settlement. It is not the product of negotiation. It is the recognition by plaintiffs counsel that the laws of Texas and the United States give the plaintiffs no cause to sue Creative Commons.

As I said when I announced the lawsuit here,  the fact that the laws of the United States don't make us liable for the misuse in this context doesn't mean that we're not working extremely hard to make sure misuse doesn't happen. It is always a problem (even if not a legal problem) when someone doesn't understand what our licenses do, or how they work. We need to work harder to make that clear. But the news today lets us go back to the work of Creative Commons, without the burden of this lawsuit hanging above us. 

So how can you celebrate with us? Well, help us recover some of the costs (probably $15k) that we have to eat because of this suit (deductibles with our insurance company, etc) by supporting CC. Or help us by joining as just a friend of CC.  Or help us by spreading the news that the lawsuit is over.

And as one final word to the plaintiffs here -- a word I can utter because neither required nor asked: As CEO of Creative Commons, I apologize for any trouble that confusion about our licenses might have created. We thought the meaning was clear. We work hard to make this as clear as we can. We will work harder.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/virgin.jpg"><img alt="virgin.jpg" height="776" src="http://lessig.org/blog/virgin-thumb.jpg" width="600"/></a></center>

We received this happy missive in the mail yesterday: The plaintiffs in the <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html">lawsuit about Virgin using a CC-licensed photo</a> have dismissed CC from the case. This is not a settlement. It is not the product of negotiation. It is the recognition by plaintiffs counsel that the laws of Texas and the United States give the plaintiffs no cause to sue Creative Commons.

As I said when I announced the lawsuit <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/09/on_the_texas_suit_against_virg.html">here</a>,  the fact that the laws of the United States don't make us liable for the misuse in this context doesn't mean that we're not working extremely hard to make sure misuse doesn't happen. It is always a problem (even if not a legal problem) when someone doesn't understand what our licenses do, or how they work. We need to work harder to make that clear. But the news today lets us go back to the work of <a href="http://creativecommons.org">Creative Commons</a>, without the burden of this lawsuit hanging above us. 

So how can you celebrate with us? Well, help us recover some of the costs (probably $15k) that we have to eat because of this suit (deductibles with our insurance company, etc) by <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">supporting CC</a>. Or help us by joining as just a <a href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/50000_friends.html">friend of CC</a>.  Or help us by spreading the news that the lawsuit is over.

And as one final word to the plaintiffs here -- a word I can utter because neither required nor asked: As CEO of Creative Commons, I apologize for any trouble that confusion about our licenses might have created. We thought the meaning was clear. We work hard to make this as clear as we can. We will work harder.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-28T22:50:21Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-28T21:38:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3464</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/big_news_great_party.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Big news, great party</title>
    <summary>RSVP.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center><a href="http://lessig.org/blog/cc_party.jpg"><img alt="cc_party.jpg" height="394" src="http://lessig.org/blog/cc_party-thumb.jpg" width="603"/></a></center>

<a href="mailto:party@creativecommons.org">RSVP</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-26T23:04:24Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-26T16:13:46Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3463</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/german_public_tv_starts_a_cc_e.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>German Public TV starts a CC experiment</title>
    <summary>As reported at Blognation, German Public Television has started an experiment by licensing two of its shows under a CC license. 

For German speakers (and last week, my 4 year old informed me I was not a German speaker and I "should only speak English"), here's a clip explaining the decision:</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As <a href="http://de.blognation.com/2007/11/22/ndr-german-public-television-experiments-with-creative-commons/">reported at Blognation</a>, German Public Television has started an experiment by licensing two of its shows under a CC license. 

For German speakers (and last week, my 4 year old informed me I was not a German speaker and I "should only speak English"), here's a clip explaining the decision:

<center/></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-26T23:03:27Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-26T16:08:44Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-586901698085926063</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/remix-my-lit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=586901698085926063" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/586901698085926063/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/586901698085926063" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/586901698085926063" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>remix MY lit!</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://bp0.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R0pS5YNP4qI/AAAAAAAAAC8/QY81BI_rOe0/s1600-h/main+rml+logo+-+pink+-+web+big.png"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5137009470673511074" src="http://bp0.blogger.com/_CT_0Kb25oLs/R0pS5YNP4qI/AAAAAAAAAC8/QY81BI_rOe0/s400/main+rml+logo+-+pink+-+web+big.png" style="display: block; margin: 0px auto 10px; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; cursor: hand;"/></a><br/><br/>Amy Barker and I are working on a new CCau project that hasn't yet got legs (ie no funding) but which is sparking a fair bit of interest around the place called <a href="http://www.remixmylit.com/">Remix my lit</a> (see <a href="http://www.varuna.com.au/alumni/alumninews&amp;events.html#creativecommons">here</a> and <a href="http://remixablefilms.multiply.com/journal/item/26/remix_my_lit">here</a>). Most of the <a href="http://www.asauthors.org/scripts/cgiip.exe/WService=ASP0016/ccms.r?PageId=10041">writers' centres</a> are really interested so we hope to go a lot further with it soon.<br/><br/>Basically, the idea is that remixing isn't limited to film and music. There is no reason why the written word should not be open to the possibility of creative play. Remix my lit exists to facilitate experimentation in literature remixing. The first planned project will see a body of works by established authors released into the commons for remixing. All remixes will be hosted on <a href="http://www.remixmylit.com/">remixmylit.com</a> and a selection will (hopefully) be published in a printed volume. We aim to create a community of writers exploring new ways of writing.<br/><br/>Writers that are endorsing the project include <a href="http://www.battersby.com.au/">Lee Battersby</a>, <a href="http://www.scribepublications.com.au/author/catekennedy">Cate Kennedy</a>, <a href="http://www.allen-unwin.com/Vogel/current.asp">Stefan Laszczuk</a>, <a href="http://emilymaguire.typepad.com/">Emily McGuire</a>, <a href="http://www.jamesphelan.com.au/">James Phelan</a>, <a href="http://www.kimwilkins.com/">Kim Wilkins</a> and <a href="http://www.allenandunwin.com/default.aspx?page=311&amp;author=35">Danielle Wood</a> as well as poet <a href="http://www.mandybeaumont.com/mandy/home.htm">Mandy Beaumont</a>.<br/><br/>And to put the money where my mouth is, you can even remix my <a href="http://www.remixmylit.com/2007/11/26/flash-photography-and-screams/">short fiction piece</a>. So go on, remix my lit!<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-26T05:01:42Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-26T04:11:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="elliott bledsoe"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="text"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau projects"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="remix"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="amy barker"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="literature"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="writing"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-5963183950389660285</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/ccau-music-industry-forum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=5963183950389660285" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/5963183950389660285/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5963183950389660285" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/5963183950389660285" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>ccau music industry forum</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2173/1867006343_4e309d705d.jpg?v=0"/></a><br/><br/><br/><p style="color: red;"><font face="Verdana" size="4"><br/>28 november 2007, 2.00 till 4.00pm @ the queensland college of art, griffith university, 226 grey street, south bank, brisbane<br/></font></p><br/><br/><br/>On 28 November, The ARC <a href="http://www.cci.edu.au">Centre of Excellence for Creative Industries and Innovation</a> will be hosting the CCau Music Industry Forum as part of <a href="http://www.auc.edu.au">Apple University Consortium</a>’s <a href="http://auc.edu.au/Create+World+2007">Create World 2007</a> conference.<br/><br/>It is designed to provide a forum for the discussion of issues surrounding music licensing in Australia. It will take place from 2.00 till 4.00pm on Wednesday 28 November 2007 at the Queensland College of Art, Griffith University, Brisbane.<br/><br/>The digital environment presents new opportunities for musicians and new business models for the distribution of music. Creative Commons licensing in particular has gained considerable favour with content producers world-wide. However the legalities and practicalities of releasing music under these new models can be complicated, particularly when you wish to combine them with more traditional collective licensing options (for further information visit <a href="http://www.creativecommons.org.au/musicinfo">www.creativecommons.org.au/musicinfo</a>).<br/><br/>The CCau Music Industry Forum aims to bring together industry representatives and interested parties to discuss issues such as:<br/><br/>• potential online distribution models for musicians and the music industry; <br/>• compatibility issues with current collective licensing schemes; and <br/>• legal and practical issues relating to the use of Creative Commons licences by Australian songwriters, composers and musicians.<br/><br/>Discussants at the Forum will include:<br/><br/>• Professor Brian Fitzgerald, Project Lead, Creative Commons Australia; <br/>• Scot Morris, Director International Relations, APRA; <br/>• Professor Paul Draper, Director of IMERSD (Intermedia, Music Education &amp; Research Design) and Deputy Director, Queensland Conservatorium Research Centre, Griffith University; and<br/>• Q Music<br/><br/>The forum also aims to gather feedback regarding the current understanding of and attitudes towards copyright, open content licensing and Creative Commons within the Australian music industry whilst providing an opportunity for key music industry personnel in to learn more about these topics.<br/><br/>Creative Commons Australia is the Australian arm of the international Creative Commons project, a non-profit organisation that aims to promote flexible copyright options for creators. At the core of the Creative Commons project is a suite of licences, freely available to creators, that foster sharing and collaboration. Creative Commons builds upon the “all rights reserved” of traditional copyright to create a voluntary “some rights reserved” system.<br/><br/>Persons  currently involved or interested in the licensing of musical works are welcome to attend. rsvp by friday 23 november 2007 to elliott at <a href="mailto:elliott@creativecommons.org.au">elliott@creativecommons.org.au</a> or call (07) 3138 9597.<br/><br/><br/><a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum"><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2356/1867831670_9e6b023bfe.jpg?v=0"/></a><br/><br/><font face="Century Gothic" size="1">image: ventura mendoza, licensed under a creative commons <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">attribution licence 2.0</a><br/><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/vmendoza/490269072">http://www.flickr.com/photos/vmendoza/490269072</a></font><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-26T02:47:08Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-05T03:45:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="royalties"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="apra"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau music industry forum"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau events"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-2015255158512747626</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/australian-pc-world-writes-up-ccau.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=2015255158512747626" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/2015255158512747626/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2015255158512747626" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/2015255158512747626" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>australian pc world writes up the ccau music forum</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Danah McConnachie at Australian PC World <a href="http://www.pcworld.idg.com.au/index.php/id;1477749946">published</a> a great article about the upcoming <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/ccmusicforum">ccau music industry forum</a>. There's a whole spiel about why we are running the forum (which is great exposure for the event) and then there is a lengthy interview with <a href="http://www.mabula.net/tbfw/">Paul Wayper</a>, and <a href="http://www.anu.edu.au">ANU</a> research programmer who uses the <a href="http://lmms.sourceforge.net/">linux multimedia system</a>. Wayper agrees with the CC argument that copyright is being used to lock down content:<br/><br/><blockquote>"While Creative Commons licenses work to foster innovation and sharing or resources, traditional media companies and agencies and technologies such as DRM work against these freedoms."<br/></blockquote><br/><br/>Some other great pull-outs from the article:<br/><br/><blockquote>"There are two fundamental changes in the landscape of music, and art, production. Firstly, it no longer takes a dedicated artist who's spent thousands on special instruments to have the equipment and talent to produce a good-quality piece of music. Secondly, the actual distribution of music no longer takes arcane mixing processes, mastering to record or CD, printing and distribution of physical items. The only thing that hasn't really changed is that people still want to listen to music,"</blockquote><br/><br/><blockquote>"...I give away my pieces with a (CC) license that allows some reuse while not allowing total exploitation because I don't really expect someone to shell out money for them. If I were to turn to producing commercial trance full time I might expect to be paid, but only if I actually made something that other people were making money off. The key thing that people don't think about CC licenses is that it doesn't mean you can't negotiate the rights to other uses, just that they aren't given by default."</blockquote><br/><br/><span style="font-style: italic;">Wayer is talking at <a href="http://linux.conf.au/">linux.conf.au</a> 2008 in January.</span><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-26T02:44:14Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-17T02:22:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="royalties"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="apra"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau music industry forum"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ccau events"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=297</id>
    <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=297" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>FRANCIA, proponen quitarle Internet a los “piratas”.</title>
    <summary>Hace solo dos años, y por casi un año, Francia revolucionaba la blogosfera con una opción concreta; la licencia global que se aprobaría a través del proyecto de ley de propiedad intelectual conocido como Dadvsi, la propuesta significaba la legalización de toda descarga de contenidos desde Internet, no se consiguió que pasara en el Congreso… [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Hace solo dos años, y por casi un año, <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/?p=28">Francia revolucionaba la blogosfera </a>con una opción concreta; la licencia global que se aprobaría a través del proyecto de ley de propiedad intelectual conocido como <a href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero/index.php?s=dadvsi">Dadvsi</a>, la propuesta significaba la legalización de toda descarga de contenidos desde Internet, no se consiguió que pasara en el Congreso… pero estuvo cerca, muy cerca. Hoy sin embargo el pulso parece que lo ganan del otro lado:  bajo el liderazgo de FNAC (una de las tiendas europeas que tienen mayor participación en el mercado de venta de música y videos) se ha logrado un acuerdo entre el estado y la industria para quitar las cuentas de acceso a Internet a quienes descarguen de la red contenidos protegidos por el derecho de autor, y digo ganan por que por ahora el acuerdo ha tenido un respaldo decidido del presidente Sarkozy y parece que a pesar de las críticas saldrá adelante. </p>
<p>En resumen la propuesta es que se crearía una autoridad sometida a autoridad judicial para informar a quienes descarguen música y películas sobre la ilegalidad de tal acción, con el apoyo de los prestadores del servicio, las sanciones serán suspensión y cancelación del servicio.</p>
<p>La situación por supuesto <a href="http://www.audionautes.net/pages/informer/communiques/voir.php?id=43">ha sido rebatida por la Asociación de Audionautas</a>, tan activos en su momento apoyando la licencia global, pero sobre todo son los artículos desde Nouvelle Observateur los que me han parecido más críticos. Particularmente me han gustado: <a href="http://tempsreel.nouvelobs.com/actualites/20071124.OBS6556/">“Piratería, el informe Olivennes la considera ´peligrosa´”</a>, <a href="http://tempsreel.nouvelobs.com/actualites/20071123.OBS6440/">“Descargas, un acuerdo firmado en el Eliseo”</a> y esta en la que se reproduce <a href="http://clubobs.nouvelobs.com/article/2007/11/23/20071123.FAP3625.xml">un artículo de Associated Press</a> (les aconsejo también las reacciones que tienen algunos de los artículos).</p>
<p>Otros artículos: en inglés <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/internetNews/idUSL2346825720071123">el artículo de Reuters </a>y en español acá está el de <a href="http://www.elpais.com/articulo/radio/television/Francia/cortara/linea/quien/baje/musica/cine/elpeputec/20071124elpepirtv_4/Tes">El Pais</a>.</p>
<p>Actualización: el tema en otros blogs (en construcción), Cory Doctorow en <a href="http://www.boingboing.net/2007/11/25/french-law-will-forc.html">BoingBoing</a>, <a href="http://einvents.wordpress.com/2007/11/26/francia-se-quedaran-sin-internet-usuarios-de-p2p/">einvents</a>, <a href="http://technollama.blogspot.com/2007/11/french-strike-at-pirates.html">Technollama</a></p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-25T11:02:50Z</updated>
    <category term="DADVSI"/>
    <category term="pirateria"/>
    <category term="p2p"/>
    <category term="Derecho de autor"/>
    <author>
      <name>carobotero</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero</id>
      <link href="http://www.karisma.org.co/carobotero" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carobotero" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>Ideas de mi viaje por internet en temas de LibreCultura, derecho y nuevas tecnologías. Carta de navegación desde la América Meridional.</subtitle>
      <title>carobotero-co</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T22:13:31Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-4122308235709345769</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/08/some-thoughts-from-cc-documentary-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=4122308235709345769" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/4122308235709345769/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4122308235709345769" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/4122308235709345769" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>why it is difficult to use MC Hammer in a documentary film</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><font color="7CFC00" face="Verdana" size="4">some thoughts from writing an article on documentary and open content licensing</font><br/><br/>I've been working on an article about documentary, rights management and creative commons for far too long now. Since I spoke at the <a href="http://2007.aidc.com.au">Australian International Documentary Conference</a>, in February actually.<br/><br/>Anyway, here's a bit of precursor:<br/><br/>Rights clearances are one of the biggest hurdles for filmmakers. Copyright clearances are required for each element in the film that is not the original creation of the filmmaker. Add the amount of money that often costs, the conditions on which rights are granted by gatekeepers and the need to take content out that ins't cleared (or risk being done for copyright infringement). Oh the pangs of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permission_culture">permission culture</a>.<br/><br/>But CC presents new ways of managing copyright and alternative avenues. The Creative Commons “some rights reserved” approach offers new ways of thinking about, managing and capitalising on creative content. But these are only part of what it offers. It is also a tool for assisting collaboration, innovation and experimentation, and can open up options for utilisation, promotion and distribution of content.<br/><br/><font color="7CFC00" face="Verdana" size="2">copyright's “can’t touch this” effect</font><br/><br/>The practical effect of copyright is to restrict all but a narrow set of uses  of copyrighted material or works—including “literary, dramatic, musical or artistic” works  and “subject matter other than works” such as sound recordings , films , television and sound broadcasts  and published editions of works—automatically  at the point of creation. That copyright in original works  subsists for  70 years after the end of the calendar year in which the author of the work died.  For works considered to be other subject matter the duration varies. For sound recordings and films it's 70 years after the end of the calendar year in which the work is first published.  In the case of television or sound broadcasts, copyright expires at the end of 50 years after the end of the calendar year in which the first broadcast was made.<br/><br/>Any use of a copyrighted work without the permission of the creator is an infringement of copyright attracting possible civil and criminal actions. Copyright is somewhat of a misnomer. Really it should be called copyrights given that it encompasses a bundle or rights including the right to reproduce the work, publish the work, perform it in public, communicate it to the public and to make derivative/adaptive works from it . This is why the common phrase is “All Rights Reserved” as copyright by default protects all rights in the work. Like the MC Hammer song, what this means is “can’t touch this.” These are often referred to as the economic rights of copyright. The existence of these rights independently of each facilitates copyright licensing (see below). Copyright owners also have the right  to licence to another person authority to utilise their work in relation to any or all of those rights.So long as the licensee does not exercise powers beyond the scope of the licence, they are exempt from being sued from copyright infringement. If you haven’t been granted a licence and you make an unauthorised use of the copyright you are in breach. This is symptomatic of a permissions culture.<br/><br/><font color="7CFC00" face="Verdana" size="2">a permissions culture: copyright clearances</font><br/><br/>The need to have approval to reuse content results in what Stanford Law Professor Lawrence Lessig calls a ‘permission culture.' [See <span style="font-style: italic;"><a href="http://www.free-culture.cc/">Free Culture</a></span>] It is an environment in which “creators get to create only with the permission of the powerful, or of creators from the past.” The permission culture stymies new creative endeavour; whether that is because of the complexity of getting clearance (or indeed identifying a copyright owner in order to get clearance) or the many explicit and hidden cost associated with getting copyright clearance. Possibly more concerning still is the ability of copyright holders to withhold consent to suppress negative commentary on them or affiliated organisations.<br/><br/>There are numerous examples of situations where films have been forced underground because of copyright. Take for example Peter Spears’s short <span style="font-style: italic;">Earnest and Bertram</span>—an adaptation of Lillian Hellman’s play of unrequited gay love <span style="font-style: italic;">The Children’s Hour</span>. The film presents the Bert and Ernie characters from popular American childrens’ television program <span style="font-style: italic;">Seasame Street</span> as closeted gay men. It was a huge success at Sundance Film Festival, but was soon off screens when owners of the characters and associated television program, Sesame Workshop issued Spears with a cease and desist notice. “I felt it was protected under First Amendment freedom of speech parody, but I understand that they have to protect their copyright,” Spears lamented in interview with the US editor of Screen International, Michael Goodridge, “When they served me the cease and desist, I didn't have the energy or financial resources to fight it."  Spears pulled the film from the festival circuit.<br/><br/>Director of <span style="font-style: italic;">Velvet Goldmine</span> and <span style="font-style: italic;">Far From Heaven</span>, Todd Haynes, is no stranger to the realities of rights clearances either. Even before his debut into feature, Haynes had felt the copyright pinch. His first popular short, <span style="font-style: italic;">Superstar: The Karen Carpenter Story</span>, used Barbie dolls to retell the singers’ life. Richard Carpenter took it out of circulation for its use of original music by The Carpenters. Toy-company giant Mattel didn’t get involved despite the use of their Barbie dolls in this instance, but Argentinean filmmaker Albertina Carri wasn’t so lucky. Her film <span style="font-style: italic;">Barbie Can Also Be Sad</span> was pulled from a film festival in Mexico after legal action taken by the company.<br/><br/>A more recent example is Robert Greenwald’s <span style="font-style: italic;">Outfoxed: Rupert Murdoch’s War on Journalism</span>. It utilises extensive footage from the news service, leaked policy memos penned by Fox executives and interview footage with former employees to expose the ways that Fox News allegedly distorts it reporting to serve the conservative political leaning of its owner. Importantly, Greenwald used much of this content with Fox’s permission. Greenwald kept a lot of information about the project under wraps because he feared a court injunction would be sought to stop the films release. Today Fox has not responded publicly except to say in <span style="font-style: italic;">The Washington Post</span> “People steal our footage all the time. We generally sort of look the other way."  But of course, Fox had (and still have) the right to object to the film, and could have embroiled the film in a lengthy court battle to suppress it.<br/><br/>But Fox were not the only third party with copyright tied up in <span style="font-style: italic;">Outfoxed</span>. As <span style="font-style: italic;">The New York Times</span> outlined in an article in the lead up to the film’s release:<br/><br/><blockquote>“…several major news organizations were unexpectedly refusing to license their clips. (Such licensing is ordinarily pro forma.) CBS wouldn't sell Greenwald the clip of Richard Clarke's appearance on ''60 Minutes,'' explaining that it didn't want to be associated with a controversial documentary about Murdoch. WGBH, the Boston PBS station, wouldn't let Greenwald use excerpts from ''Frontline'' for fear of looking too ''political,'' it said.” </blockquote><br/><br/>These copyright owners had the ability to force their copyrighted works to not be included in the documentary. (Not all the clearances were so negative it should be added; Eric Clapton granted the film the right to use ‘Layla’ at no charge as did Don Henley for the track ‘Dirty Laundry.’) Even if Greenwald had left the most contentious and litigious content in the film and relied on the strength of a fair use claim, “as a practical matter the high costs of litigation force most filmmakers to simply remove the material in question.”   Similarly here in Australia, reliance on fair dealing can be risky and the threat of litigation and the costs associated with it often results in filmmakers playing it safe and removing the questionable material.<br/><br/><br/><br/>Although there are some legitimate uses of copyrighted material without the permission of the copyright owner, in most instances the right to reuse content will be granted by way of a licence from the copyright owner. Authorisation occurs when the copyright owner (or the “licensor”) grants (or “licences”) permission to another party (or the “licensee”) to exercise any right in the bundle.<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-25T08:05:22Z</updated>
    <published>2007-08-08T02:15:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="documentary"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="film"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/24/cofundos/</id>
    <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/24/cofundos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Requirements for community funding of open source</title>
    <summary>Last month another site for aggregating donation pledges to open source software projects launched.
I’m not sure there’s anything significant that sets Cofundos apart from microPledge featurewise. Possibly a step where bidders (pledgers) vote on which developer bid to accept. However I’m not certain how a developer is chosen on microPledge — their FAQ says “A [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://cofundos.org/docs/crowdfunding.php"><img border="0" src="http://cofundos.org/layout/cofundosprocess.png" style="padding: 5px; float: right;"/></a>Last month <a href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/08/27/micropledge/">another</a> site for aggregating donation pledges to open source software projects <a href="http://blog.aksw.org/2007/open-source-innovation-platform-cofundosorg/">launched</a>.</p>
<p>I’m not sure there’s anything significant that sets Cofundos apart from microPledge featurewise. Possibly a step where bidders (pledgers) vote on which developer bid to accept. However I’m not certain how a developer is chosen on microPledge — their FAQ <a href="http://micropledge.com/help/dev#develop">says</a> “A quote will be chosen that delivers the finished and paid product to the pledgers most quickly based on their current pledging rate (not necessarily the shortest quote).” microPledge’s scheme for <a href="http://micropledge.com/help/dev#estimate">in progress payments</a> may set it apart.</p>
<p>In terms of marketing and associations, Cofundos comes from the <a href="http://aksw.org">Agile Knowledge Engineering and Semantic Web</a> research group at the University of Leipzig, producers of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DBpedia" rel="tag">DBpedia</a>, about which I’ve <a href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/01/23/dbpedia/">written</a>. Many of the early proposed projects are directly related to AKSW research. Their <a href="http://cofundos.org/docs/terms.php#Copyright">copyright policy</a> is appreciated.</p>
<p>microPledge is produced by <a href="http://micropledge.com/about">three Christian siblings</a> who <a href="http://micropledge.com/religion">don’t push their religion</a>.</p>
<p>Cofundos lists <a href="http://cofundos.org/projects.php">61 proposed projects</a> after one month, microPledge lists <a href="http://micropledge.com/tags">about 160</a> after about <a href="http://blog.micropledge.com/2007/08/micropledge-public-launch/">three and a half months</a>. I don’t see any great successes on either site, but both are young, and perhaps I’m not looking hard enough.</p>
<p>Cofundos and microPledge are both welcome experiments, though I don’t expect either to become huge. On the other hand, even modest success would set a valuable precedent. In that vein I’ve been pretty <a href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2006/03/18/sxswi-wrap/">skeptical about the chances of Fundable</a>, they seem to have attracted a steady stream of users. Although most projects seem to be uninteresting (pledges for bulk purchases, group trips, donations to an individual’s college fund, etc), some production of public goods does seem to being funded, including several film projects in the small thousands of dollars range. Indeed, “My short film” is the default project name in their form for starting a project.</p>
<p>It seems to me that creating requirements and getting in front of interested potential donors are the main challenges for sites focused on funding open source software like Cofundos and microPledge (both say they are only starting with software). Requirements are just hard, and there’s little incentive for anyone to visit an aggregator who hasn’t aggregated anything of interest.</p>
<p>I wonder if integrating financial donations into project bug tracking systems would address both challenges? Of course doing so would have risks, both of increasing bureaucracy around processing bugs and feature requests, necessity of implementing new features (and bugs) in the relevant bug tracking software, and altering the incentives of volunteer contributors.</p>
<p><small><a href="http://blog.okfn.org/2007/10/26/cofundos-community-innovation-and-funding/">Via Open Knowledge Foundation Blog.</a></small></p></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-24T23:22:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <category term="Economics"/>
    <category term="Open Source"/>
    <category term="Public Goods"/>
    <category term="Semantic Web"/>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Linksvayer</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog</id>
      <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/category/creative-commons/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>My opinions only. I do not represent any organization in this publication.</subtitle>
      <title>Mike Linksvayer » Creative Commons</title>
      <updated>2007-12-17T04:27:51Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-4119335692565245494</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/ccau-staff-talk-lot-part-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/video-play.mp4?contentId=8c054774ddc15ceb&amp;type=video%2Fmp4" length="0" rel="enclosure" type="video/mp4"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=4119335692565245494" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/4119335692565245494/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4119335692565245494" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/4119335692565245494" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>ccau staff talk a lot: part 2</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Another interview with <a href="http://abc.net.au">ABC</a>, this time with me ^_^  Back in April, while I was in Sydney for <a href="http://www.ourmedia07.net/">OURMEDIA VI</a> I ducked into the ABC Ultimo building to record an <a href="http://www.pool.org.au/node/894">interview</a> for radio and that would become part of an exciting new ABC-run user-generated content project called <a href="http://www.pool.org.au/">Pool</a>. More about Pool later, first here's the interview and accompanying video they made:<br/><br/>


<br/>(available under a CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.5/au/">BY-NC 2.5 Aus</a> licence)<br/><br/>The video gives an overview of CC, the protocols, the commercial/non-commercial distinction and explains possible motivations for wanting to use CC.<br/><br/><br/>So what is Pool? It's a collaborative production environment that people can submit their creative works to. In the about it says:<br/><br/><blockquote>"Grow ideas; download, remix and share with your friends and the world. Music, photos, videos, documentaries, interviews, animations, and more. Connect with people; by comments, tags, friend lists, and collaborative co-creation.  Is this the future of public media?"</blockquote><br/><br/>The site is under a CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/au/">BY-NC-ND 2.5 Aus</a> licence, but also allows All Rights Reserved and the CC <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/au/">BY-NC 2.5 Aus</a> licence.<br/><br/>And why did they decide to use CC?<br/><br/><blockquote>"We decided to use Creative Commons licences for Pool because we think it's the best way possible to have some fun with content, without breaching any copyright laws."</blockquote><br/><br/>It is in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beta_version#Beta">beta testing</a>, so go easy on it. Get on there and give some good feedback. CCau certainly wants to see it happen!<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-23T03:35:26Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-23T03:07:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CC BY-NC"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CC BY-NC-ND"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ABC"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="elliott bledsoe"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ABC pool"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="BY-NC"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-197901850415640231</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/ccau-staff-talk-lot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=197901850415640231" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/197901850415640231/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/197901850415640231" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/197901850415640231" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>ccau staff talk a lot: part 1</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The <a href="http://www.abc.net.au">ABC</a>'s <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/rn">Radio National</a> recently <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/rn/lawreport/stories/2007/2095456.htm">broadcast</a> a mashup of content stimulated by the <a href="http://www.mwf.com.au">Melbourne Writers' Festival</a> debate <span style="font-style: italic;"><a href="http://www.mwf.com.au/2007/content/events.asp?name=20070826_1130_350WS">Creative commons or common theft?</a></span> recordings that had <a href="http://craphound.com/">Cory Doctorow</a>, (<a href="http://craphound.com/stories.php">sci-fi author</a> and <a href="http://www.forbes.com/2006/11/30/cory-doctorow-copyright-tech-media_cz_cd_books06_1201doctorow.html">CC advocate</a>) in the blue corner and Sandy Grant (Senior executive <a href="http://www.hardiegrant.com.au/">Hardie Grant Publishing</a>, and member of <a href="http://www.copyright.com.au/">Copyright Agency Limited</a> Board) in the red corner. holding the sweat towels were Mark Williams (Senior adviser with <a href="http://www.jdrlegal.com.au/">JDR Legal</a>) and CCau's very own Jessica Coates (Project Manager, <a href="http://creativecommons.org.au/node/74">Creative Commons Clinic</a>). You can listen to the recording <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/rn/lawreport/stories/2007/2095456.htm">here</a>.<br/><br/>It is great to see CC being talked about (<a href="http://www.abc.net.au/rn/bookshow/stories/2007/2039471.htm">again</a>) on the Australian public broadcaster. But as always, I have a few gripes. Damien Carrick opens the podcast by saying:<br/><br/><blockquote>This morning, Creative Commons: making films, literature or music  for free online. It undermines copyright but is it also creating whole new business models and income streams for our artists?</blockquote><br/><br/>I don't like it. I know Jess tells me that it's to make it sound controversial to keep people listening, but its misinformation and i dont like it. Sorry Damien, Creative Commons does <b><u>not</u></b> undermine copyright, it remixes it to create more flexible (and arguably useful) ways of managing copyright. As such, I don't agree that CC "essentially strip copyright of all meaning," but rather breaths new life and meaning into copyright (as I have said <a href="http://www.anat.org.au/stillopen/blog/2007/08/31/copy-me-pass-it-on/">before</a>). As <span style="font-style: italic;"><a href="http://support.creativecommons.org/videos#gc">Get Creative</a></span> states, "CC isn't meant to compete with copyright, but to compliment it."<br/><br/>Moving on, Williams opened the debate with a tale of one of the first pirated works. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fergus_Hume">Fergus Hume</a>'s detective (self-published) novel, <span style="font-style: italic;">The Mystery of the Hansom Cab</span> (first published 1886, you can find it on <a href="http://www.gutenberg.org">Project Gutenberg</a> <a href="http://www.gutenberg.org/etext/4223">here</a>), was pirated and sold throughout Europe. It paved the way for a new genre of fiction (think <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sherlock_Holmes">Sherlock Holmes)</a>. Williams goes on to note that the pirated version went on to sell a huge number of copies, most of the money from which did not find its way into Hume's bank account. So no money there, but as Williams himself attests, "[Hume] was famous, and it enabled him to then write another 100 or so novels..." The problem for most artists, according to Doctorow, is obscurity not piracy. Therefore piracy = reputation (?) Without the piracy, would Hume have had the opportunity to write as much as he did?<br/><br/>Then Grant gets amongst it. I love that Grant refers to CC as having "something of a cult following." Gee, <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/5579">53 million pages licensed</a> and projects in <a href="http://creativecommons.org/international/">66 countries</a> around the world with licences or in the process of drafting them. (Doctorow <a href="http://www.locusmag.com/Features/2007/11/cory-doctorow-creative-commons.html">says</a> 160 million+ works licensed since 2003, but i am not sure where he is getting that figure from. Cory?) That's a really big cult! Maybe we should try to get Creative Commons added to the recognised religions at the next <a href="http://www.census.abs.gov.au/websitedbs/d3310114.nsf/Home/census">ABS Census</a>?!<br/><br/><br/><span style="font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-style: italic;"><u>SIDE NOTE:</u></span></span> Grant highlights my comments about Doctorow as a case study. Doctorow's his prior net identity and fame made it far easier for him to push his novel out than other, totally unknown writers will. CC facilitated the distribution and reuse from a copyright management point of view for sure, but it was Doctorow's charisma that propelled it forward. This is the same argument I make as to why the user-specifies-value <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/In_Rainbows">Radiohead album <span style="font-style: italic;">In Rainbows</span> </a>worked for them but it is doubtful it would for an emerging band.<br/><br/>Grant later says he doubts that if Doctorow get's as famous as <a href="http://www.jkrowling.com/">J K Rowling</a> that \ he would still be giving his books away for free. Well Doctorow isn't that famous yet, but he is still quite famous (more so than both Grant and I anyway :p). And how many books is that under CC now Cory? Oh that's right, <a href="http://craphound.com/stories.php">five</a>, all CC licensed. According to Doctorow,"[His] books have outsold [his] publisher's expectations" and the sales of colleagues of similar skill and career status. He also says that there isn't a single writer (that he knows anyway) "Who has tried this and hasn't done it again."<br/><br/>I like Cory's comment:<br/><br/><blockquote>"I think that Ms Rowling would be well advised to try it. Is there anyone here who really believes that no one would have picked up Harry Potter and the Sequel of Great Profitability if they'd gotten a free electronic copy. That what was driving people to the store at midnight in costume was the fact that they couldn't lay hands on a digital copy. Indeed, there was a digital copy, 24 hours before that book hit the stands. The $20 million spent on secrecy for that book was not only ineffective at secrecy, but as best understood as a marketing effort."</blockquote><br/><br/><span style="font-style: italic;"><u>END SIDE NOTE</u></span><br/><br/>CC is also a dog's breakfast to Grant, who says, there's "Really good, quality material, of course like Cory's, sitting along side and mixed up with amateur, unreadable crap." He then proceeds to tout <a href="http://andrewkeen.typepad.com/">Andrew Keen</a>'s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Cult-Amateur-Internet-Killing-Culture/dp/0385520808"><span style="font-style: italic;">Cult of the Amateur</span></a> rhetoric, which basically says we're becoming more stupid because anyone can post stuff online. Pffft, elitist wank if ever i heard it. So much for new technologies democratising information production. Not if these guys had the final word. I prefer the Robin Sloan and Matt Thompson's theory in <a href="http://www.robinsloan.com/epic/">EPIC 2014</a> which will see individuals filtering content and managing their information intake (which is of course already happening).<br/><br/>The podcast also tackles the quashing of creative innovation that happens in a permissions culture. in my forthcoming documentary paper there is an entire section devoted to this syndrome but you can read a bit on it <a href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/08/some-thoughts-from-cc-documentary-paper.html">here</a>. Interestingly, Doctorow also takes a freedom of expression argument, saying:<br/><br/><blockquote>"The fact is that the purpose of copyright is promote the diversity of expression. It's not to pick the best works and ensure they're produced. The last thing any of us want our governments doing is deciding what's good and what's bad and then crafting law to ensure that only the good things get produced. Before copyright we had patronage–you could paint a painting if the Pope said so, you could make a ceiling up if the Duke said so, you could make a sculpture if the King said so–that produced the occasional nice fresco but it was a poor way to manage diversity of expression in a liberal society. The purpose of copyright was to change the arbitures of expression to the marketplace. And that's been a reasonably good diversifier of who gets to speak and under what circumstances, but the internet turns out to be an even better one."</blockquote><br/><br/>And on the flip side, Grant says that he's worried that Doctorow's 'papal frescos' are not reality, but rather that democratisation of voices is "encouraging mass graffiti." After all, "that's what's happening on the internet."<br/><br/>Equally amusing is Grant's recommendation that we all read the Australian Copyright Council's <a href="http://www.copyright.org.au/pdf/acc/infosheets_pdf/g094.htm">fact sheet</a> on CC. <span style="font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-style: italic;"><u>SIDE NOTE:</u></span></span> The fact sheet is factually incorrect in parts and is now out of date!<span style="font-style: italic;"><u>END SIDE NOTE</u></span> Grant's five word summary, "Don't sign up too quickly." I'd make the same argument about publishing contracts, record deals, film production contracts, <a href="http://www.optapra.net/">APRA</a> and other royalty collecting arrangements. What are you really giving up and for how long when you enter these relationships? Why didn't you talk about that Grant?<br/><br/>He proceeds to bring up the same arguments always spouted around the irrevocability of CC licences. My response is still the same. If I went out on the street in front of my house right now, and I handed to the first 100 people who passed me a poem I had written, I can hardly come back in a week, a month or 20 years time and demand those 20 people give me back my poem. I'd just look like a madman ranting and raving to no one. Even more accurately, if i went out on the street in front of my house and left 100 copies of that poem on the fence for anyone to take and then went back in side, there is no way i could feasibly demand the poems back post-fact.<br/><br/>Be warned, you run the "risk of being exploited by business professionals," Grant also cautions. He cites the pending <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7680">Virgin case</a> as evidence. Grant's synopsis:<br/><br/><blockquote>"Plenty of egg on the face for the photographer, no income, and Virgin got something for nothing."</blockquote><br/><br/>If all the photographers were so up in arms at this use of their work, why is only one suing? And not for copyright infringement I might add, which is the part that CC is related to. What is of issue is the need for a model release form. And hey, if the great unwashed amateurs on <a href="http://flickr.com">Flickr</a> can <a href="http://flickr.com/groups/central/discuss/72157600541608353/#comment72157600542022693">tell</a> (and <a href="http://flickr.com/groups/central/discuss/72157600541608353/#comment72157600611463291">here</a>) that a CC attribution licence doesn't imply a release form was signed , they why the hell did Virgin's lawyers? The licence clearly states otherwise (see 5. Representations, Warranties and Disclaimer <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/legalcode">here</a>).<br/><br/>So Grant then continues on, hypothetically asking himself if copyright will remain unchanged. "No," he answers. And will people still be paying for things they really want? He says yes. I say it depends. The 'apple + c' syndrome makes it easy to get content at a reasonable enough quality to be contented. And as Doctorow says:<br/><br/><blockquote>"...it is wildly implausable that as the year's tick by in this century it is going to get progressively harder to copy. Say what you will about the morals of downloading work, the real politic of downloading work is that it's already practically impossible to exclude someone from a collection of bits, and that impossibility will only increase as the year's tick by.</blockquote><br/><br/>It is only if the user's (emotional/cultural) investment in that content is deeper than a general interest that they will turn that into economic investment and buy the same thing. Besides, sampling work can lead to sales. As Doctorow says, "It's a really rare, bookish person who would say, "Well having been given all these all these free electronic texts, the last thing i need now is a printed work," after all, even I, who spends every hour god sends reading off a screen, don't like reading long-form works off of screen." He argues that self-discipline drives people off-screen (you've probably already been distracted three times by a new item in your RSS reader, a new email in your Inbox, a quick check of your fav social networking website and countless messages on an IM program), but I think it is more than that. It is hard to be comfortable in front of your computer to watch a feature film or a read a 200 page book. He argues that of the e-books he has, they are more of an enticement to pull down the real-world copy than a substitute for the bookshelf volume.<br/><br/>The CC explanation is very good. Jessica comes across very clear, concise and articulates the licensing model very well.<br/> All and all the entire podcast is very balanced. I think i might cut it up and reuse it in some of my presentations. With the ABC's permission of course :p<br/><br/>END POINT: I notice that the podcast is all rights reserved copyrighted by the ABC, but fails to attribute CC for the parts of the <span style="font-style: italic;"><a href="http://support.creativecommons.org/videos#gc">Get Creative</a></span> video they used.<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-23T02:45:46Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-21T12:06:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="get creative"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CCau staff"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="creative commons"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CAL"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ABC"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Radio National"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="jessica coates"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="virgin mobile case"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cory doctorow"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc misinformation"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="CCau"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="piracy = reputation"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-141545364547446786</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/09/cory-doctorow-well-known-well-travelled.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=141545364547446786" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/141545364547446786/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/141545364547446786" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/141545364547446786" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>doctorow in australia</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://craphound.com/">Cory Doctorow</a>, the well-known, well-travelled, CC <a href="http://craphound.com/stories.php">sci-fi author</a>, was in Australia recently, and while he was here he stopped into <br/><br/><a href="http://www.abc.net.au/rn">Radio National</a> on the <a href="http://www.abc.net.au">ABC</a> to <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/rn/bookshow/stories/2007/2039471.htm">talk</a> to Sarah L'Estrange about <a href="http://www.forbes.com/2006/11/30/cory-doctorow-copyright-tech-media_cz_cd_books06_1201doctorow.html">giving it away</a>. His books that is.<br/><br/>The blurb states:<br/><br/><blockquote>Since the 19th century copyright has served to protect the rights of authors. But has this protection become a hindrance to creativity? Supporters of creative commons licenses say the pendulum has swung too far towards protectionism, and that this is affecting our creative culture.</blockquote><br/><br/>I missed in unfortunately. Sounds like it would have been a good interview. Anyone know if it's available online anywhere?<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-23T01:48:34Z</updated>
    <published>2007-09-25T01:37:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ABC"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Radio National"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cory doctorow"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4720</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/21/life_and_death_on_the_tokyo_metro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Life and death on the Tokyo metro</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">I ended the work day with a study group and an expert guest where we discussed the Japanese legal system. Although there were some small signs of hope, I find that the more I learn about how things really...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/1465289559/" title="Shibuya Toyoko Line by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="Shibuya Toyoko Line" height="336" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1088/1465289559_9e3257d8bf.jpg" width="500"/></a>
I ended the work day with a study group and an expert guest where we discussed the Japanese legal system. Although there were some small signs of hope, I find that the more I learn about how things really work, the more pessimistic I get about causing actual change in Japan.</p>

<p>As I pondered the futility of revolutionary activities in Japan, I jogged to try to catch the train to connect to the commuter train for my 1.5 hr shlep back to my home. As I entered the station, I noticed an unusually large crowd of people on the platform.</p>

<p>The PA system announced a delay due to an accident. Japan has over 30,000 suicides a year (one of the highest rates in the world) and 800 or so of them as a result of “train accidents”. As I crammed myself into the standing-room-only train full of drunken businessmen, tired “office ladies” and shriveled old people, I thought about what kind of person might have jumped in front of the train this time.</p>

<p>As we approached the station where the accident occurred, the train came to a stop and the conductor apologized again for the delay. They shut down the motors as we waited and the everyone was silent and still. As I looked around at the tired people with their blank looks, it felt like we were all involuntarily mourning the death of another person in Japanese society who had to give up.</p>

<p>When I arrived at at my home train station, Mizuka was there to pick me up. I shared my depressing thoughts and she scolded me for being so down. When we got home, our dog Pookie yapped away and almost blew these thoughts away, but I decided to share them with you anyway.</p>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/21/life_and_death_on_the_tokyo_metro.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/21/life_and_death_on_the_tokyo_metro.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-21T22:26:46Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-21T14:05:00Z</published>
    <category term="Japanese Culture"/>
    <category term="Japanese Policy"/>
    <category term="People"/>
    <category term="Photo"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="en">
    <id>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/21/semantic-www/</id>
    <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/2007/11/21/semantic-www/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Semantic Web Web Web</title>
    <summary>The World Wide Web Consortium and particularly its Semantic Web efforts do great, valuable work. I have one massive complaint, particularly about the latter: they ignore the Web at their peril. Yes, it’s true, as far as I can tell (but mind that I’m one or two steps removed from actually working on the problems), [...]</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web_Consortium" rel="tag">World Wide Web Consortium</a> and particularly its <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web" rel="tag">Semantic Web</a> efforts do great, valuable work. I have one massive complaint, particularly about the latter: they ignore the Web at their peril. Yes, it’s true, as far as I can tell (but mind that I’m <a href="http://benlog.com/">one</a> or <a href="http://yergler.net/blog/">two</a> steps removed from actually working on the problems), that the W3C and Semantic Web activities do not appreciate the importance of nor dedicate appropriate resources to the Web. Not just the theoretical Web of URIs, but the Web that billions of people use and see.</p>
<p>I’m reminded of this by Ian Davis’ post <a href="http://iandavis.com/blog/2007/11/is-the-semantic-web-destined-to-be-a-shadow">Is the Semantic Web Destined to be a Shadow?</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>My belief is that trust must be considered far earlier and that it largely comes from usage and the wisdom of the crowds, not from technology. Trust is a social problem and the best solution is one that involves people making informed judgements on the metadata they encounter. To make an effective evaluation they need to have the ability to view and explore metadata with as few barriers as possible. In practice this means that the web of data needs to be as accessible and visible as the web of documents is today and it needs to interweave transparently. A separate, dry, web of data is unlikely to attract meaningful attention, whereas one that is a full part of the visible and interactive web that the majority of the population enjoys is far more likely to undergo scrutiny and analysis. This means that HTML and RDF need to be much more connected than many people expect. In fact I think that the two should never be separate and it’s not enough that you can publish RDF documents, you need to publish visible, browseable and <em>engaging</em> RDF that is meaningful to people. Tabular views are a weak substitute for a rich, readable description.</p></blockquote></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-21T22:01:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Creative Commons"/>
    <category term="Microformats"/>
    <category term="Peeves"/>
    <category term="Semantic Web"/>
    <author>
      <name>Mike Linksvayer</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>http://gondwanaland.com/mlog</id>
      <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://gondwanaland.com/mlog/category/creative-commons/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <subtitle>My opinions only. I do not represent any organization in this publication.</subtitle>
      <title>Mike Linksvayer » Creative Commons</title>
      <updated>2007-12-17T04:27:51Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3462</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/50000_friends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>50,000 friends</title>
    <summary>To celebrate its 5th birthday (Dec 15), Creative Commons is launching a drive to get 50,000 friends. From the CC Blog: Through sites like Facebook, MySpace, and Flickr, you can help us broaden our reach and educate the masses about the Creative Commons mission.

So, starting today, we're issuing a 50,000 friend challenge to our community. We'reasking you to help us expand CC's overall friend network to 50,000 people across the Web's various social networking and content sharing sites by December 15 – the date of our fifth birthday party.

Here are some ways you can help our friend network grow. If you aren't a member of any of these sites, please help us by starting (or expanding) a CC group on any site you do use. Join our Facebook Cause, become a top recruiter, or become a  CC Fan Participate in the 2007 CC Swag photo contest on Flickr Become a Creative Commons friend on MySpace or FriendsterOf course, you can also help Creative Commons by contributing to our annual fundraising campaign. As always, we thank you sincerely for your support!</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">To celebrate its 5th birthday (Dec 15), Creative Commons is launching a drive to get 50,000 friends. From the <a href="http://creativecommons.org/weblog/entry/7835">CC Blog</a>: <blockquote>Through sites like <a href="http://facebook.com">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://myspace.com">MySpace</a>, and <a href="http://flickr.com">Flickr</a>, you can help us broaden our reach and educate the masses about the Creative Commons mission.

So, starting today, we're issuing a 50,000 friend challenge to our community. We'reasking you to help us expand CC's overall friend network to 50,000 people across the Web's various social networking and content sharing sites by December 15 – the date of our fifth birthday party.

Here are some <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org/spread">ways you can help</a> our friend network grow. If you aren't a member of any of these sites, please help us by starting (or expanding) a CC group on any site you do use. <ul><li>Join our <a href="http://apps.facebook.com/causes/view_cause/151">Facebook Cause</a>, become a top recruiter, or become a <a href="http://usc.facebook.com/profile.php?id=18870062776"> CC Fan</a></li> <li>Participate in the <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org/contest">2007 CC Swag photo contest</a> on Flickr</li> <li>Become a Creative Commons friend on <a href="http://www.myspace.com/creativecommons">MySpace</a> or <a href="http://www.friendster.com/creativecommons">Friendster</a></li></ul>Of course, you can also help Creative Commons by <a href="http://support.creativecommons.org">contributing to our annual fundraising campaign</a>. As always, we thank you sincerely for your support!</blockquote></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-20T03:56:03Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-20T03:47:53Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="creative commons"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4719</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/20/shibuya_photowalk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Shibuya Photowalk</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">We did another photo walk the other day. This time we wandered around Shibuya. I just realized that I didn&amp;#8217;t blog about it. I posted my set to Flickr and you can see the images of the rest of...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/1974191475/" title="Nonbeiyokocho by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="Nonbeiyokocho" height="375" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2372/1974191475_17ff0f4ece.jpg" width="500"/></a></p>

<p>We did another photo walk the other day. This time we wandered around Shibuya. I just realized that I didn’t blog about it. I <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/sets/72157603095536166/">posted my set to Flickr</a> and you can see the images of the rest of the photographers <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/tags/ccphotowalk071111/">tagged with ccphotowalk071111</a>. Thanks to everyone who participated and special thanks to Fumi and Mika for organizing everything.</p>

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/20/shibuya_photowalk.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/20/shibuya_photowalk.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-20T01:19:57Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-20T01:19:29Z</published>
    <category term="People"/>
    <category term="Photo"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4718</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/20/enjin01_in_niigata.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Enjin01 in Niigata</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">Got back yesterday from the Enjin01 event in Niigata. The theme of this year&amp;#8217;s event was laughter. (Flickr set here.) Enjin01 is a Japanese non-profit that I helped start. It is a funny mishmash of people including artists, business...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/2038022354/" title="Dancers in Niigata by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="Dancers in Niigata" height="336" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2116/2038022354_d8d547c761.jpg" width="500"/></a>
Got back yesterday from the Enjin01 event in Niigata. The theme of this year’s event was laughter. (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/sets/72157603209481395/">Flickr set here</a>.)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.enjin01.org/index2.html">Enjin01</a> is a Japanese non-profit that I helped start. It is a funny mishmash of people including artists, business people, politicians, academics, journalists, novelists… just about every kind of background you can imagine. It is a membership organization with about 180 people. It is a totally volunteer organization and no one gets paid for talks we give or activities we participate in and it is funded by membership fees from the members and corporate donations. Some members give a percentage of their normal lecture fees to the organization as well. I was involved in the selection of members and setting up the organization a lot at the beginning, but am mostly just a member now.</p>

<p>One of the activities that we do is go teach at Jr. High Schools that want us to go. Any Jr. High School can sign up for us to dispatch teachers on our websie. <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/10/31/enjin01_talk_to_jr_high_school_students_in_yamagata.html">I blogged about this earlier.</a> We also have a group that focuses on trying to change government policy, especially in the area of taxation of donations to non-profits.</p>

<p>The main activity of Enjin01 is to organize an annual meeting in a different region of Japan each year. Most of the members attend this annual meeting. The meeting is organized into a few plenary talks, a bunch of workshops and panels, and a “yagaku” where we go to dinner with people from the local community. We also usually have a closed meeting where the members meet an invited guest.</p>

<p>The program committee assigns the participant members to various panels and different “yagaku”. This year, I was assigned to a panel about IT, which is par for the course.</p>

<p>I was also assigned to be on a panel at a workshop lead by <a href="http://koichi-inakoshi.com/">Koichi Inakoshi</a> to learn about and actually participate in photographing a nude model. I had never photographed a nude model before so I was quite nervous at the beginning. Mr. Inakoshi started by explaining that we should think about the beauty of the model and imagine looking at our own bodies while we are bathing. He told us to try to imagine and see the beauty of the human body. After showing us some of his nude images, he told us to try taking photographs ourselves.</p>

<p>The audience was also invite to participate. The audience probably consisted of 50% women and maybe 50% of them over 40 years old. The panel, which I was on, chose a number of winning photos. One of the women who won a prizes was wearing a kimono. I wish I had a photo of the woman in a kimono photographing a nude model. ;-)</p>

<p>One side-effect of this session was that I ended up with some nude photographs. <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/tags/nude/">I posted them in Flickr flagged</a> as “Moderate” and “Hide this photo from public searches”. I still got a few people telling me that they were surprised and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/2041342791/">a thread started</a> on one of my photos about nudes and sensitivity about nude images. After reading a bunch of posts about nude vs naked, I realized this is an old and deep discussion online. The collapsed context of the Internet forces us to deal with these cultural differences in a very real way. With nudes, I find that even in the same society, there is a very wide range of sensitivity levels. One curious thing is why people turn “safe mode” off when they don’t want to see nudes…</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/2038950080/" title="Charles Robert Jenkins by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="Charles Robert Jenkins" height="337" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2160/2038950080_3c0d7008d4.jpg" width="500"/></a>
The special guest for the closed member meeting this year was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Robert_Jenkins">Charles Robert Jenkins</a>, the former US Army soldier who lived in North Korea for 39 years. He gave us a very candid and real account of his time in North Korea and while some of the facts and assertions were interesting and shocking, his personal account of his day-to-day life in North Korea left the strongest impression. He now lives in Niigata, Japan.</p>

<p>The “yagaku” can be hit or miss, but this year it was a lot of fun. The deal with the “yagaku” is that we choose a dozen or so local restaurants and several members are assigned to each venue. Then all of the local people are invited to join us to dinner where we are the hosts. We learn a lot about the local culture and they get to spend “quality time” with us. This year, I sat with a number of women who had worked in Tokyo at companies like Fujitsu and Intel but returned to Niigata after getting married. We talked about how to use the net to “stay in the loop”.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/2041436373/" title="Ken Mogi by Joi, on Flickr"><img alt="Ken Mogi" height="336" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2360/2041436373_265685f5f7.jpg" width="500"/></a>
One of the highlights of the event was getting to hear <a href="http://qualiajournal.blogspot.com/">Ken Mogi</a> speak and having time to chat with him a bit. In addition to being one of the most brilliant people I know, it turns out that he has a very funny and rich personality.</p>

<p>Next year, we will be holding the event in Nagoya. Anyone is welcome to join us.</p>

<!-- technorati tags start --><p style="text-align: right; font-size: 10px;">Technorati Tags: <a href="http://www.technorati.com/tag/Enjin01" rel="tag">Enjin01</a></p><!-- technorati tags end -->

		

		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/20/enjin01_in_niigata.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/20/enjin01_in_niigata.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-20T00:56:46Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-20T00:54:54Z</published>
    <category term="Japanese Culture"/>
    <category term="People"/>
    <category term="Photo"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog//1.3461</id>
    <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/2007/11/tom_bell_on_intellectual_privi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Tom Bell on "Intellectual Privilege"</title>
    <summary>Tom Bell is writing a book about (what's called) "intellectual property" in public. He calls it "intellectual privilege." I here offer a third view of copyright. I largely agree with my friends on the left that copyright represents not so much a form of property as it does a policy device designed to "promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts" (as the Constitution puts it). I thus call copyright a form of intellectual privilege.

Like my friends on the right, however, I hold our common law rights in very high regard. Hence my complaint against copyright: it violates the rights we would otherwise enjoy at common law to peaceably enjoy the free use our throats, pens, and presses. That is not to say that copyright is per se unjustified. We can excuse facial violations of our common law rights, such as the takings effectuated by taxation or the restraints imposed by antitrust law, as the costs of obtaining a greater good. But it does mean that copyright qualifies, at best, as a necessary evil.

Watch and participate at his website.</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="http://www.tomwbell.com/">Tom Bell</a> is writing a book about (what's called) "intellectual property" in public. He calls it "intellectual privilege." <blockquote>I here offer a third view of copyright. I largely agree with my friends on the left that copyright represents not so much a form of property as it does a policy device designed to "promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts" (as the Constitution puts it). I thus call copyright a form of intellectual privilege.

Like my friends on the right, however, I hold our common law rights in very high regard. Hence my complaint against copyright: it violates the rights we would otherwise enjoy at common law to peaceably enjoy the free use our throats, pens, and presses. That is not to say that copyright is per se unjustified. We can excuse facial violations of our common law rights, such as the takings effectuated by taxation or the restraints imposed by antitrust law, as the costs of obtaining a greater good. But it does mean that copyright qualifies, at best, as a necessary evil.</blockquote>

Watch and participate at his <a href="http://www.intellectualprivilege.com/book.html">website</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-19T15:15:28Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-19T15:11:18Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" term="good code"/>
    <author>
      <name/>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:lessig.org,2007:/blog/1</id>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://lessig.org/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>Lessig Blog</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T18:37:21Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-6965179227102849508</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/10/shaun-miller-on-creative-commons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=6965179227102849508" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/6965179227102849508/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6965179227102849508" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/6965179227102849508" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>shaun miller on creative commons</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">seth keen, a lecturer from <a href="http://www.rmit.edu.au">rmit</a> who attended the melbourne <a href="http://www.anat.org.au/stillopen">still/open</a> workshop, directed me to a video recording of a lecture delivered by <a href="http://www.mdlaw.com.au/staffpages/shaunmiller.html">shaun miller</a> a senior lawyer from the firm <a href="http://www.mdlaw.com.au/">marshalls and dent</a> to first year media students. <p/><br/><div class="hVlog" style="text-align: left;"><br/>  <a class="hVlogTarget" href="http://networkedmedia.adc.rmit.edu.au/wp-content/video/copyright/copyright_miller.mov" type="video/quicktime"><br/><br/>      <img src="http://networkedmedia.adc.rmit.edu.au/wp-content/video/copyright/miller_poster.jpg"/></a><br/><br/><br/><br/>  <a href="http://networkedmedia.adc.rmit.edu.au/wp-content/video/copyright/copyright_miller.mov" type="video/quicktime"/></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-19T13:29:51Z</updated>
    <published>2007-10-02T08:42:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc lectures"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc general info"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="shaun miller"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159.post-7565688835603079242</id>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/2007/11/cc-planet-cc-people.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=3385820776751654159&amp;postID=7565688835603079242" rel="replies" type="text/html"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/7565688835603079242/comments/default" rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/7565688835603079242" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/3385820776751654159/posts/default/7565688835603079242" rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <title>cc planet + cc people</title>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">i was thinking the other day about how great it is that the <a href="http://creativecommons.org">cc international</a> homepage now feeds from the other <a href="http://creativecommons.org/international/">jurisdictions</a> webpages. i had long thought that would have been a great idea.<br/><br/>but when i tried to work out what the feed address was so i could subscribe to it in my <a href="http://www.utsire.com/shrook/">rss reader</a> i couldn't find it anywhere! i even spent some time searching the page code and came up with nothing.<br/><br/>i'm pretty slack, so i hadn't gotten around to now, cc international has conveniently created <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/">cc planet</a>, which does just that. you can either go to the website or subscribe to the feed to keep up with what all the cc jurisdictions are up to. <br/><br/>interestingly they've also decided to include the individual blogs of people who work for creative commons, both within the planet list and as a <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/people/">separate page</a> of just the cc people. well actually, cc planet incorporates three different pages: the <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/jurisdictions/">jurisdictions page</a>, <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/people/">cc people page</a> and the international site, jurisdictions and <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/people/">cc people</a> altogether in <a href="http://planet.creativecommons.org/">one feed</a>.<br/><br/>and they have included little old me (on this blog) ^_^<div class="blogger-post-footer">the text of creative commons through the looking glass is available for reuse under the terms of a creative commons attribution 2.5 australia license. for more information see 'legals + licence' at http://ccelliott.blogspot.com</div></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-19T08:43:14Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-19T08:06:00Z</published>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc international"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="creative commons"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="cc planet"/>
    <author>
      <name>plastikkpoet</name>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-3385820776751654159</id>
      <author>
        <name>plastikkpoet</name>
      </author>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25" rel="next" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <link href="http://ccelliott.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <title>cc through the looking glass</title>
      <updated>2007-12-20T06:17:48Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>

  <entry xml:lang="ja">
    <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1.4716</id>
    <link href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/12/three_years_with_icann.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title xml:lang="ja">Three years with ICANN</title>
    <summary xml:lang="ja">What used to think ICANN was like... Apologies for the delay in writing the post. I've been trying to think about what to say and have just decided that I better write it before my thoughts get old... I...</summary>
    <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joi/1807861462/" title="Photo Sharing"><img alt="Darth Vader, Stormtroopers come to ICANN meeting" height="336" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2337/1807861462_2d39fbeb55.jpg" width="500"/></a><br/>
What used to think ICANN was like...</p>

<p>Apologies for the delay in writing the post. I've been trying to think about what to say and have just decided that I better write it before my thoughts get old...</p>

<p>I joined the ICANN board during the December 2004 ICANN meeting in Cape Town. I served for a three year term and stepped down at this last meeting in Los Angeles and didn't run for another term. My apologies to all of the ICANN community and the people who helped me learn about and participate in the complex but important process that is ICANN.</p>

<p>Before joining ICANN, I thought that ICANN was the only part of the Internet that wasn't really working. I knew that there must be a better way to do what ICANN does, but I couldn't be bothered to figure it out. I'd agree with people who said things like, "it should just be distributed" or "it should just be first come first serve" or "we should just get rid of it." People from ICANN would say, "it's more complicated than that" or "at this point that would be impossible."</p>

<p>After being part of the process for three years, I find myself saying those same things and feeling a sense of exasperation at the people who take pot shots at ICANN from the peanut gallery without really trying to help or change things. I also have gained a huge respect for most of the people who participate in ICANN, many as volunteers, trying to improve the process and keep the Internet running.</p>

<p>With all of it's tumultuous history and bumps and warts, ICANN, in my opinion, is the best way that we can manage names and numbers on the Internet and any new thing to try to do what it does would be less fair and probably wouldn't work. </p>

<p>There are some technical architectures and ideas that might make ICANN less relevant, which would be a good thing. However, even relatively obvious things like IPv6, IDNs and DNSEC are having a hard time getting traction. I think that it would be nearly impossible to "redesign the DNS" and get people to use it. It would be like trying to redesign a flying airplane. On the other hand, their might be some evolutionary changes that make domain names less relevant.</p>

<p>The ICANN process as it is currently working involves a number of supporting organizations that feed into a consensus and policy development process. The board is 15 people, 8 who are "neutral" and nominated from the public through the nomcom process and 7 who are elected from the supporting organizations. It is geographically and otherwise fairly well distributed and balanced. It is nearly impossible to "capture" the process. If any stakeholder wants to participate, they just have to show up.</p>

<p>The problem that ICANN has is not one of being unfair, the problem that ICANN has is the difficulty and time required in trying to reach consensus on difficult issues. The other problem is that most of the people who are affected by the decisions, the average users, don't know or care about ICANN. Trying to figure out an better way to get their input has always been an issue, but is one that is not unique for ICANN. All of politics and collective action share the difficulty in getting the public to care about issues that affect them.</p>

<p>When I was urged by a number of people to join the board, I thought of my term on the board as a kind of "jury duty". I had been benefiting from the Internet running properly for the last decade, building businesses and my social network on the Internet. I felt that three years would be a kind of "community service" to give back some of what I had received. The board work included nearly monthly conference calls, probably several thousand pages of reading, two face-to-face board retreats and three meetings per year. The meetings are a week long. This adds up to nearly two months or more of work a year.</p>

<p>As the new chairman of Creative Commons and my portfolio of companies requiring more and more of my time, I just couldn't justify serving another term. I calculated that I spent more time reading about and discussion whether we should allow .xxx than I spent on any one portfolio company this year... and at the end of it, I voted in the minority and .xxx was shot down and I ended up as just a voting statistic.</p>

<p>Having said that, I have no regrets. I met amazing people, learned a lot about how the Internet works and have gained a great respect for the people and the organizations that make up and contribute to ICANN. Many thanks to the ICANN staff, board and various constituents who have made my term a fruitful and exciting one.</p>
		
		<a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/12/three_years_with_icann.html#comments" title="Comment">Comment</a> - <a href="http://joi.ito.com/archives/2007/11/12/three_years_with_icann.html#trackbacks" title="Trackback">TrackBack</a></div>
    </content>
    <updated>2007-11-13T09:01:54Z</updated>
    <published>2007-11-12T22:08:28Z</published>
    <category term="ICANN"/>
    <author>
      <name>Joi</name>
      <uri>http://joi.ito.com</uri>
    </author>
    <source>
      <id>tag:joi.ito.com,2007://1</id>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
      <link href="http://joi.ito.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
      <subtitle xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's conversation with the living web.</subtitle>
      <title xml:lang="ja">Joi Ito's Web</title>
      <updated>2007-12-14T09:05:41Z</updated>
    </source>
  </entry>
</feed>
